<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PotHix</title>
    <link>https://pothix.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pothix.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of Wolves of the Calla (The Dark Tower, #5)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower5/</guid>
      <description>Book: Wolves of the Calla (The Dark Tower, #5) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️
Estou lendo essa série em português, então os reviews também serão em português. Eu gostei mais desse livro do que do anterior porque ele moveu mais a história para a frente ao invés de dar mais contexto para as coisas. Conhecer uma nova cidade e os ocultismos que vem com ela foi bem interessante. Eu também curti saber mais sobre &amp;ldquo;Os outros mundos além desse&amp;rdquo; e como as coisas se conectam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Wizard and Glass (The Dark Tower, #4)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower4/</guid>
      <description>Book: Wizard and Glass (The Dark Tower, #4) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Outro livro que li em Português, então o review vai ser em Português também.
Eu gostei do livro no geral. Parece que a sensação de &amp;ldquo;nossa, que legal&amp;rdquo; e &amp;ldquo;mano, que bizarro&amp;rdquo; está se atenuando cada vez mais. Em alguns momentos eu fico bem interessado sobre como as histórias do mundo de Roland de Gilead (não consigo chamar de Roland Deschain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2021 Productivity Workflow</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/workflow2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/workflow2021/</guid>
      <description>This post is the updated version of the one I wrote in 2019. Instead of changing the previous one, I decided to create an updated version based on that.
From time to time, I receive questions about my productivity workflow and I think it will be useful to have it written down somewhere. This post will describe how I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with it in 2021.
Tool As you probably know, I work for Doist for some time now, and I&amp;rsquo;m a Todoist user since 2007, so the my tool of choice is quite obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Waste Lands (The Dark Tower, #3)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower3/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Waste Lands (The Dark Tower, #3) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Ouvi esse livro em Português (e provavelmente farei o mesmo para todos os próximos). Eu tenho todos os livros físicos mas preferi procurar um audiobook para facilitar a minha &amp;ldquo;leitura&amp;rdquo;.
Assim como o livro 2, esse me surpreendeu bastante (talvez porque eu gostei pouco do primeiro). Agora eu estou começando a me envolver com a história e ficar curioso com o mundo da Torre Negra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My knowledge base bootstrap</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/knowledgebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/knowledgebase/</guid>
      <description>Note-taking is my current obsession, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to talk about it here. 😃
How it started Last year I was talking to my friend Diego Eis about his note-taking workflow. I knew he was doing that for a long time but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the advantages of doing this. He described his workflow but I was still not convinced it would be useful for me at the time.
When January came, I saw a post by Caffo talking about Roam Research and how he was using it to build his blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Drawing of the Three (The Dark Tower, #2)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower2/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Drawing of the Three (The Dark Tower, #2) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
What a surprise! I enjoyed listening to this book. I have the whole series of books (printed version) here and decided to listen to the first one some years ago. I was not very impressed by it and decided to put the who series aside for some time. Last month I decided to give the second book a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Life‑Changing Magic of Tidying Up</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/magicoftidyingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/magicoftidyingup/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Life‑Changing Magic of Tidying Up by Marie Kondo. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I like the book and there are very few things I disagree with the author. I think it&amp;rsquo;s too much to talk to objects, but I understand where this is coming from. In my opinion, just holding the object is enough, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t talk to them.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to remove all objects from your bad/purse every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinião: Produtos e contratações globais</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/contratacaoglobal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/contratacaoglobal/</guid>
      <description>Tudo começou com uma discussão no grupo off-topic do Ruby Brasil. Alguém compartilhou a seguinte imagem:
Encontrei o post original no Linkedin
Esse post não é uma resposta direta ao Bruno Pereira, mas sim estendendo a discussão que começamos no grupo do Telegram.
Um dos argumentos usados lá é que as empresas precisam entender que esse é um mercado global e ligar com isso tentando fazer as coisas ficarem locais gera várias frustrações.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password managers</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/passwordmanagers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/passwordmanagers/</guid>
      <description>After many years using LastPass, I decided to make the switch to 1Password. I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe here why I did this and how was my process to choose.
LastPass I&amp;rsquo;m using LastPass for many years now. A lot of people say that LastPass is not a good password manager, it has bugs, it&amp;rsquo;s ugly, it has too many trackers, yada, yada, yada.
I was always the guy who said: &amp;ldquo;Yeah, it works for me&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/2020/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, like any other stats post, this one will be HUGE
If you&amp;rsquo;re following my blog, you know that I sometimes mentioned things were too hard and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sit down and write. Looking back now, I have a good laugh for my past self. ☺️
I can say for sure that 2020 was a complicated year and a lot of things change in my life. The biggest change is that I&amp;rsquo;m now a father of twins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falando sobre a pirataria</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pirataria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pirataria/</guid>
      <description>Há alguns dias atrás, um amigo meu compartilhou um texto sobre pirataria no twitter. O texto possui o tema &amp;ldquo;Precisamos falar sobre a pirataria&amp;rdquo; e pode ser visto aqui.
O texto é bem leve ao falar do assunto e mostra a visão da autora e sua própria experiência com a pirataria. Se eu fosse resumir o texto em uma frase (sim, é o meu entendimento sobre ele), seria:
 Todo mundo já usou pirataria de uma forma ou de outra quando não tinha dinheiro o suficiente para pagar por um determinado material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/books/</guid>
      <description>If you want to see all my reviews, not just the small list of recommended books (still WIP), I suggest you to check the books tag.
Here I describe the list of books I recommend to people. The recommendation also links to my review here, in case you want to have more information about it.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s start with my recommendations. 💪
Tolkien: A biography It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movies</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/movies/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wanted to write down the movies I recommend. There are so many great movies to recommend that I will never be able to reply from the top of my head.
This is a list of the movies that I really enjoy. Hopefully, they will be great for you as well.
The Lord of the Rings trilogy (200[4,5,6]) - Extended version It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on group chats</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/group-chats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/group-chats/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of group chats. The current app I use the most for group chats (and direct messages as well) is Telegram. I even created some group chats for topics I like (mechanical keyboards, note taking and productivity, Books and audiobooks, Money and investing, etc.).
I take group chats (and communities) more seriously than I should and I make sure chats are moderated and following their topic, otherwise, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense to have chats split by topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic The Gathering</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mtg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mtg/</guid>
      <description>Some context I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Magic The Gathering (or MTG) since the first time I played it in 2004. Even before 2004, I remember seeing some cards a friend had and being totally amazed, even without understanding how the game worked.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t play much when I was a kid because these cards were (and some still are) very expensive. In 2007 I found some people to play and I bought some new cards (cheap ones).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien&#39;s Ordinary Virtues book</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien’s Ordinary Virtues, by Mark Eddy Smith. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I’m a big fan of Tolkien (if you follow me or my blog, you probably already know that) and decided to give a chance to this one even knowing it was totally related to religion and it’s not my thing anymore.
The book is about Christian comparisons between The Lord of the Rings and some virtues shown in the Bible. I know talking took his Catholic religion very seriously and was even raised by a Priest after his mother passed away, so it would be nice to see the book again through these lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Um mês de um PJ para o exterior</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mespj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mespj/</guid>
      <description>Esse é o último post que eu tinha planejado para a série de PF &amp;amp; PJ. Não necessariamente será o último da série, mas toda essa série começou para eu poder fazer esse post. 😄
Eu gostaria de mostrar como é o ciclo de um mês trabalhando como PJ para o exterior, já que isso ainda é uma incognita para muita gente e várias vezes eu explico isso para amigos que pretendem entrar na mesma ideia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would it be necessary?</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/t/willitbenecessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:45:35 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/t/willitbenecessary/</guid>
      <description>I have no idea if I&amp;rsquo;m going to continue maintaining this section. I currently have my own private notes in Roam research and maybe I will publish some of them here. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it&amp;rsquo;s going to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome: Invalid HTTPS in development</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/thisisunsafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/thisisunsafe/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time I had to use HTTPS for local development and had to do the whole setup of self-signed certificates. It&amp;rsquo;s a painful process that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a good ROI for the developer.
One day, after being sick of doing this every time, I decided to do some research for an easy way to workaround this. That was when I found the thisisunsafe hack.
If you&amp;rsquo;re using Chrome (or chromium) you can type thisisunsafe when you access your development app complaining about HTTPS certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Daily Rituals: How Artists Work</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dailyrituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dailyrituals/</guid>
      <description>Book: Daily Rituals: How Artists Work. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I just read the book When and it mentioned this book. The idea was so interesting that I decided to give it a try.
What first caught my attention was the pattern of the peak, through, rebound everywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s not everywhere because we&amp;rsquo;re just mentioning artists here. I believe a similar pattern tends to emerge whenever people have control over their time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub CLI (a.k.a gh)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ghcli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ghcli/</guid>
      <description>The GitHub CLI is been a major time saver for me. I was skeptical about its usage in the beginning but it proved to be very useful.
Cloning When I want to download a new repository, instead of typing the whole URL or going to the browser to find the repository, I just type:
 gh repo clone name-of-the-repository  It works out of the box if the repo is mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust, LotR, and focus</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lotrfocus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lotrfocus/</guid>
      <description>💡 Quick thought post. A bigger tweet but on my own platform.
I&amp;rsquo;m co-authoring a book about Rust and was reviewing an example about enums. My plan was to use some sort of reference to J.R.R. Tolkien fantasy world (because I really like it). I was considering using something like this:
enum Race { Elf, Dwarf, Men, Hobbit, Ent } PS: I&amp;rsquo;m only considering the free-peoples of middle earth for this enum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a promicro</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dactyl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dactyl2/</guid>
      <description>A lot happened since my last post and all parts are already here! 😃
It was expected that I would not have that much time to work on the keyboard when all the parts arrive, this will be a long journey. The only thing that I wanted to do as soon as possible was to check if the products were in a good condition.
These are cheap parts coming from China in a month-long journey, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to check if they are working as expected while I still can open a dispute with the seller if something is wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PJ optante do Lucro Presumido</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pjpresumido/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pjpresumido/</guid>
      <description>Nesse quarto post da série de PF &amp;amp; PJ eu vou explicar o que eu sei sobre o Lucro Presumido para o nosso tipo de trabalho (desenvolvimento de software), como é o dia-a-dia de impostos e porque decidi migrar do Simples alguns anos atrás.
DISCLAIMER: Eu não sou contador, mas essas são as informações que eu levantei depois de toda a minha pesquisa, assim eu consegui conversar melhor com os contadores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PJ optante do Simples</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pjsimples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pjsimples/</guid>
      <description>Nesse terceiro post da série de PF &amp;amp; PJ eu vou explicar o que eu sei sobre o Simples Nacional atual e como era a minha vida quando minha empresa era optante.
Esses não são assuntos tão divertidos de se falar aqui no blog, mas são eternos motivos de conversas com amigos para enteder o que é mais viável para eles, portanto eu resolvi escrever sobre o meu caso e o que eu sei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/when/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/when/</guid>
      <description>Book: When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing, by Daniel Pink. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I read this book two times. The first time I had no context and was just looking for something to improve myself. The second time I read it to review everything I used and implemented so I could quote the book when writing an article about how to manage your energy to be more effective.
The book provides amazing insights if you like to base your decisions on scientific research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abertura de empresa</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aberturapj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aberturapj/</guid>
      <description>Esse é o segundo post da série de PF &amp;amp; PJ e vou contar sobre a minha epopéia de como foi abrir uma empresa em 2017 e o que escolhi.
A ideia principal desse post é mostrar para as pessoas como é abrir uma empresa de desenvolvimento de software, os custos envolvidos e qual a melhor forma (IMO) de estruturá-la.
DISCLAIMER: Eu não sou contador, mas essas são as informações que eu levantei depois de toda a minha pesquisa, assim eu consegui conversar melhor com os contadores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</guid>
      <description>Book: J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography, by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a secret to anyone that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R. Tolkien. I have 3 versions of this book. A translated version (pt-BR), the original version in English, and the audiobook. It&amp;rsquo;s no news that it would be a 5 star book to me.
I just listened to the Inklings book by Humphrey Carpenter, so it was the best time to also listen to this one (yes, I went for the Audiobook).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelancer PF para o exterior</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pf/</guid>
      <description>Esse é um texto que eu escrevi em 2017 quando eu comecei a abrir a minha empresa. Como o post ficou interminado e eu acho que ainda tem valor, eu resolvi terminar e publicar.
Vou escrever uma pequena série de posts sobre esse lance de formas de trabalho e a minha experiência fora de CLT.
DISCLAIMER: Eu não sou contador, mas essas são as informações que eu levantei depois de toda a minha pesquisa, assim eu consegui conversar melhor com os contadores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Inklings: C.S. Lewis, J.R.R. Tolkien, Charles Williams, and Their Friends</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/inklings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/inklings/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Inklings: C.S. Lewis, J.R.R. Tolkien, Charles Williams, and Their Friends by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;m giving it 5 stars because I enjoyed it a lot and it came at the right time for me. For most people, it will probably be a 4-stars book.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien and also the concept of the Inklings. I have my own spin-off of this group with some friends but instead of discussing literature, we just take some time to have some deep conversation about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dactyl keyboard - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dactyl1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dactyl1/</guid>
      <description>After build the Iris keyboard I decided to start a new quest to build a Dactyl-cc (as I mentioned at the end of the Iris post 😉)
Dactyl is the keyboad I wanted to build from the start but I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t have the skils to do it. I decided to first build a &amp;ldquo;portable kinesis&amp;rdquo;, so I could take it with me when I was traveling and Iris seemed like a great fit for this and not that hard for a first project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Programming Rust: Fast, Safe Systems Development</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/programmingrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/programmingrust/</guid>
      <description>Book: Programming Rust: Fast, Safe Systems Development. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a great book for sure. I started reading it in 2017 but never find the time to read it. Now, thanks to having two babies at home, I have enough time to read while waiting for them to sleep. :)
There are many things I like about this book. The first is the comparisons with C and C++ since both authors are/were C/C++ developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assembling an Iris Rev4</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/iris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 09:48:21 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/iris/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a keyboard that would be great to take with me when I&amp;rsquo;m not working from home for some days. I finally found the Iris keyboard that seems to be exactly what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for.
The need I currently have a Kinesis Advantage at home. The keyboard is great, probably the best keyboard I used so far, but it&amp;rsquo;s far from what we can call portable 😅.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Nonviolent Communication</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/nonviolentcommunication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/nonviolentcommunication/</guid>
      <description>Book: Nonviolent Communication by Marshall B. Rosenberg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book! It&amp;rsquo;s short and straight to the point.
In summary, we should emphasize more with other people and understand what they are really trying to say. Sometimes we don&amp;rsquo;t communicate well and it&amp;rsquo;s up to someone to find out what is the problem and raise the right questions.
This book feels even more important now that we have more people working remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Antidote: Happiness for People Who Can&#39;t Stand Positive Thinking</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/theantidote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/theantidote/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Antidote: Happiness for People Who Can&amp;rsquo;t Stand Positive Thinking by Oliver Burkeman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was a suggestion from a friend when I published the review of Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic: Taking Control of Anxiety Attacks, as he found the content to be complimentary.
I liked the book overall. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how the author shows some scientific facts of the &amp;ldquo;positive thinking&amp;rdquo; which contradicts the current collective thinking. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything against positive thinking, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure positive thinking alone will not do much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Don&#39;t Panic: Taking Control of Anxiety Attacks</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dontpanicbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dontpanicbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic: Taking Control of Anxiety Attacks by R. Reid Wilson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book and exactly what I needed, thanks for the recommendation, Rafael Rosa!
Some people said it seems like a Rust programming language book because of the word &amp;ldquo;panic&amp;rdquo; but it&amp;rsquo;s actually related to panic/anxiety attacks. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time I suffer from anxiety but it&amp;rsquo;s the first time I felt the panic attack symptoms, so I decided to read more about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Essentialism: The Disciplined Pursuit of Less</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/essentialismbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/essentialismbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Essentialism: The Disciplined Pursuit of Less by Greg McKeown. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nothing outstanding, but a good book overall.
I like listening to books like this one from time to time as it helps me to again think about what is essential. This topic is something we tend to forget and having a reminder is nice.
Sometimes we have so much noise around that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find what is really essential to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Courage to Be Disliked: How to Free Yourself, Change your Life and Achieve Real Happiness</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/couragetobedisliked/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/couragetobedisliked/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Courage to Be Disliked: How to Free Yourself, Change your Life and Achieve Real Happiness by Ichiro Kishimi. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I love these kinds of dialogues where both sides know how to win something. Currently, there are not many good dialogues on our society, especially with the advent of social media (🙄), but I would not go into detail here.
The whole idea of Adlerian psychology is very interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Year in Review (full of metrics!)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/2019/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, like any other stats post, this one will be HUGE
My year in review for 2018 was never posted because I could never finish it. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to let the same thing happen this year, so here I am.
The end of 2018 and the beginning of 2019 was quite hard for me and me just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to sit down in front of the computer during the weekends to write my monthly reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of On the Shortness of Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/shortenessoflife/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/shortenessoflife/</guid>
      <description>Book: On the Shortness of Life by Seneca. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A short and good book. After reading Letters from a Stoic, I got the recommendation of this book as well and it was worth listening to it. This book makes me think about the way I&amp;rsquo;m living my life and how I&amp;rsquo;m using my time (not focusing enough?).
If you want a quick and meaningful book, pick this one. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/digitalminimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/digitalminimalism/</guid>
      <description>Book: Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World by Cal Newport. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World book and this is another great book by Cal Newport. This one is not life-changing as Deep work was for me, but it brings great insights into technology in general.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of social networks in general, they are mostly a waste of time in my point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Peak Performance: Elevate Your Game, Avoid Burnout, and Thrive with the New Science of Success</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/peakperformance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/peakperformance/</guid>
      <description>Book: Peak Performance: Elevate Your Game, Avoid Burnout, and Thrive with the New Science of Success by Brad Stulberg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book. I felt like it&amp;rsquo;s a compilation of some good books I read in the past years. It was not a life-changing book for me but it was great to review the important info I collected in the past years. I would totally recommend this book as the first book for someone looking for performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Born Standing Up: A Comic&#39;s Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bornstandingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bornstandingup/</guid>
      <description>Book: Born Standing Up: A Comic&amp;rsquo;s Life by Steve Martin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I got a recommendation for this book on Quora. I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember what was the question about, but I usually mark some books to read when I get these &amp;ldquo;books you should read&amp;rdquo; questions.
I had low expectations about this one and it surprised me. :)
It was great to follow Steve&amp;rsquo;s career from a broke comedian to a famous one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Rust</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rust-contrib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rust-contrib/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m involved with the Rust community for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;m one of the main organizers of the Rust meetup in São Paulo and also the Rust conference in Latin America (Rust LATAM) for more than one year now, but did not contribute to Rust source code yet.
This post will show the step by step I did to submit my first pull request to the Rust compiler.
If you want to go straight to the step by step, without any introduction, jump to My step by step to the first contribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of How to Be Free: An Ancient Guide to the Stoic Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/howtobefree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/howtobefree/</guid>
      <description>Book: How to Be Free: An Ancient Guide to the Stoic Life by Epictetus. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book. It seems like a summary of the whole enchiridion. After reading Seneca, I decided to try Epictetus. These books are usually very dense and require some time to think about, so I decided to not go with the long form of the enchiridion. I do not regret it; it was a good reading/listening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Letters from a Stoic</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lettersfromastoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lettersfromastoic/</guid>
      <description>Book: Letters from a Stoic by Seneca. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was expecting a bit more about this book but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it is just a problem with my expectations. The book is a collection of letters from Seneca to Lucilius, and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you should expect from it. Seneca was a wise man and these letters contain great pieces of advice. Many of these advices are still valid today, but some makes much more sense when you consider the whole context in which Seneca was at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of So Good They Can&#39;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sogoodtheycantignoreyou/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sogoodtheycantignoreyou/</guid>
      <description>Book: So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love by Cal Newport. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is the kind of book you read and think: &amp;ldquo;I would love to have read this when I was starting my career&amp;rdquo;, as you have seen a lot of what he describes during the past 10 years.
I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I did most of what he mentions here, and I can say it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Utopia for Realists: How We Can Build the Ideal World</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/utopiaforrealists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/utopiaforrealists/</guid>
      <description>Book: Utopia for Realists: How We Can Build the Ideal World by Rutger Bregman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book that I will recommend to many people. I was between 4 and 5 stars for this one and decided to go with 4. If there was a 4.5, I would totally go for it.
I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with all the ideas presented here but I enjoyed thinking about them and seeing some different perspectives on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2019 Productivity Workflow</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/workflow2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/workflow2019/</guid>
      <description>From time to time, I receive questions about my productivity workflow, so I decided to write it down here. Keep in mind it&amp;rsquo;s a living thing and may change with time, but what I&amp;rsquo;m documenting here is what I&amp;rsquo;m using right now.
Tool As you probably know, I work for Doist for some time now, and I&amp;rsquo;m a Todoist user since 2007, so the my tool of choice is quite obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Moonwalking with Einstein: The Art and Science of Remembering Everything</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/moonwalkingwitheinstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/moonwalkingwitheinstein/</guid>
      <description>Book: Moonwalking with Einstein: The Art and Science of Remembering Everything by Joshua Foer. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I like this book. Learned many things and enjoyed listening to it as a story. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s life-changing for me, but it brought good insights and some curiosity about how I can improve my memory.
I saw some people mentioning that &amp;ldquo;this is not a book to teach you how to improve your memory&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Buraco Analista</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/buracoanalista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/buracoanalista/</guid>
      <description>Book: Buraco Analista by Aguinaldo Prandini Ricieri. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
É um livro interessante se você tiver interesse em conhecer a vida do professor Ricieri. Eu fui a uma de suas palestras alguns anos atrás e achei muito interessante a forma que ele apresenta a matemática. Ainda não participei de um de seus cursos, mas pretendo.
Esse livro conta a história dele querendo ser um cientista em Cornélio Procópio. Parece ser uma boa descrição do que é ser um cientista no Brasil no geral pelo que ouço falar de outros cientistas também.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/whywesleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/whywesleep/</guid>
      <description>Book: Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams by Matthew Walker. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Amazing book! It has the potential to be life-changing for me.
When I started reading it, my review was around 3 stars. This book is not easy to read and sometimes (especially in the beginning) it feels boring. It took me some time to engage in the topic. I think I felt the same when reading Deep Work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Make Time: How to Focus on What Matters Every Day</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/maketimebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/maketimebook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Make Time: How to Focus on What Matters Every Day by Jake Knapp. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.
They mostly talk about their personal experiences and how they helped them to get better. There are some interesting experiences, especially because they were working for Google in the past and the culture of meetings is really strong there.
I already knew many things exposed here, so it was not life-changing for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Norse Mythology</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/norsemythology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/norsemythology/</guid>
      <description>Book: Norse Mythology by Neil Gaiman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book was in my reading list for a while. After an exam that requires pupil dilatation, I decided to go for the audiobook as it would not require any notes. :)
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the influence of Norse Mythology in some things. I particularly noted that Ragnarok mentions the coldest winter, which is also mentioned in ASOIAF as something the is near to the end of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Powerful: Building a Culture of Freedom and Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerful/</guid>
      <description>Book: Powerful: Building a Culture of Freedom and Responsibility by Patty McCord. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book but I was expecting more from it. I think it happened because I had the chance to attend a workshop with Patty and it was very good. My feeling is that the book was not bringing that much news for me.
I part I like the most about this book is how Netflix &amp;ldquo;considers their employees as adults&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Remote: Office Not Required</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/remotebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/remotebook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Remote: Office Not Required by David Heinemeier Hansson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The interesting part of reading this book is that I&amp;rsquo;m currently living most part of it in the past 2 years. :)
The book itself is a little bit outdated as it was written in 2013 and we had a very different scenario then. They mention it in the first chapter, BTW.
I found it to be a little repetitive as well, they are not very pragmatic about the content and decided to mention things over and over again so you can open the book in any particular chapter and use it as a reference (at least that&amp;rsquo;s what I felt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Joy of Less, A Minimalist Living Guide: How to Declutter, Organize, and Simplify Your Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/joyofless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/joyofless/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Joy of Less, A Minimalist Living Guide: How to Declutter, Organize, and Simplify Your Life by Francine Jay. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a book I can see myself writing. I would say that around 80% of the things said here regarding a personal organization I already practice since I was a child. The ones about decluttering I learned many years ago when my home was robbed and I decided to get rid of [almost] everything that was left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Coming Storm</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/comingstorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/comingstorm/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Coming Storm by Michael Lewis. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A nice and informative book. It&amp;rsquo;s not outstanding but I found it to have great information about how data can change the way we live, especially in this case where human lives may be in danger. The whole thing about the way the U.S. government deal with their data department is weird, but at least they have one. 🤷‍♂️
Here are my notes for this small book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Homo Deus: A History of Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/homodeus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/homodeus/</guid>
      <description>Book: Homo Deus: A History of Tomorrow by Yuval Noah Harari. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a great book that made me pause many times think. This is the kind of book I love to read. I heard some criticism about Yuval&amp;rsquo;s books and they are mostly related to his way to connect things that he is not an expert about. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s the best part of the books because it also makes me consider the connections and think about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was Rust LATAM 2019</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rustlatam2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 14:02:54 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rustlatam2019/</guid>
      <description>For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, I&amp;rsquo;m a proud core organizer of the Rust LATAM conference. 🎉 The conference happened on March 29 and 30, and this post describes how it was to organize the whole thing.
Even with the small problems we had (as any other big conference), the feedback we received so far were very positive. We were able to bring amazing speakers to the conference, which brought high-level content even for beginners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:45:26 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/nyc/</guid>
      <description>I had to chance to go to travel to NYC more than once. The first time I came there alone and the second one I went with my wife and both trips were good.
Airport I always try to go to JFK because it&amp;rsquo;s the biggest and simplest airport to use. The airport is really big and they have a train called Airtrain, that can be used to go from one terminal to another and also connects to the Subway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Atomic Habits: An Easy &amp; Proven Way to Build Good Habits &amp; Break Bad Ones</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/atomichabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/atomichabits/</guid>
      <description>This is an amazing book! I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about productivity and habits for a while now and I think this book does a great work of gathering everything together and presenting it in a nice form.
I think I liked it even more because I already apply many of the tips written here and I can assure (at least to myself) that it actually works. I have to say that it was really great to hear confirmation of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of 21 Lessons for the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/21lessons21stcentury/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/21lessons21stcentury/</guid>
      <description>Book: 21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I just read Sapiens and I don&amp;rsquo;t think this book is so good as Sapiens is, that&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to go with 4 stars.
I like the way Yuval brings some topics to the discussion. This book made me think about many things I usually don&amp;rsquo;t think about. Religion is a topic I like to read/listen to from different angles, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Servant: A Simple Story about the True Essence of Leadership</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/theservant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/theservant/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Servant: A Simple Story about the True Essence of Leadership by James C. Hunter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book was a big hit in Brazil for a while and of course, I heard about it in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit skeptical about books that became a hit, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick this one. My sister asked me to buy this book for her as a gift and I decided to buy one for me too so we could discuss it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Radical Focus: Achieving Your Most Important Goals with Objectives and Key Results</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/radicalfocus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/radicalfocus/</guid>
      <description>Book: Radical Focus: Achieving Your Most Important Goals with Objectives and Key Results by Christina Wodtke. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This one is hard to rate. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I liked it or not, and it&amp;rsquo;s probably related to the structure of the book.
It starts as a non-fiction/business book, as I expected it to be, but out of nowhere, it became &amp;ldquo;a novel&amp;rdquo; (big quotes here). This &amp;ldquo;novel&amp;rdquo; part was not too bad, I liked it in the end, but it was totally unexpected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sapiens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sapiens/</guid>
      <description>Book: Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind by Yuval Noah Harari. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
One of the best books I ever read. The amount of information here is huge. There are many things I did not know about the history and some possible explanations about where we came to the current state.
I really like the way the author says &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t know this yet&amp;rdquo;. Sometimes, we just don&amp;rsquo;t have the answer but we have many proposed theories, so he talks about them and lets you reach your own conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The 21 Irrefutable Laws of Leadership: Follow Them and People Will Follow You</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/21lawsofleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/21lawsofleadership/</guid>
      <description>Book: The 21 Irrefutable Laws of Leadership: Follow Them and People Will Follow You by John C. Maxwell. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between 3 and 4 stars and decided to go with 3 for this one.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book, I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to complain about it. Some &amp;ldquo;laws&amp;rdquo; seem to be fillers to me, but many make total sense.
I would recommend it to someone, but reading a summary first would probably give you 80% of the value the book can bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Meet the Frugalwoods: Achieving Financial Independence Through Simple Living</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/meetthefrugalwoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/meetthefrugalwoods/</guid>
      <description>Book: Meet the Frugalwoods: Achieving Financial Independence Through Simple Living by Elizabeth Willard Thames. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I follow their blog for a while now and like it a lot, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the same feeling with the book.
It was interesting to read that they felt themselves to be privileged when comparing to the rest of the population. Financial independence is not for everyone but frugality can be and that&amp;rsquo;s what they tried to say, IMO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Power Of Less: The Fine Art of Limiting Yourself to the Essential</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerofless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerofless/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Power Of Less: The Fine Art of Limiting Yourself to the Essential by Leo Babauta. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. It&amp;rsquo;s repetitive and a bit outdated (I heard Google reader somewhere) but all the hints here are still valid.
To summarize: the focus is everything. Chose something you want to do and do it. Remove everything else that&amp;rsquo;s not moving you toward your priorities and do what you have to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashing a different firmware for the Atreus keyboard</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/atreus-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/atreus-firmware/</guid>
      <description>I just bought an Atreus keyboard and I&amp;rsquo;m now configuring my own firmware.
To do that, I&amp;rsquo;m using the qmk_firmware.
I&amp;rsquo;m adding a new file as a layout (link here) and I have to change tmk_core/common/avr/bootloader.c to be able to compile it:
-uint32_t reset_key __attribute__ ((section (&amp;quot;.noinit&amp;quot;))); +uint32_t reset_key __attribute__ ((section (&amp;quot;.noinit,\&amp;quot;aw\&amp;quot;,@nobits;&amp;quot;))); After that, I just had to get the keyboard to the reset mode via fn + ESC (to change the layout) and then pressed the RESET button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of It Doesn&#39;t Have to Be Crazy at Work</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/crazyatwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/crazyatwork/</guid>
      <description>Book: It Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Have to Be Crazy at Work by Jason Fried. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
What a great book! The best part of this book is that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing so out of this world there, they are just talking about what we should be doing.
Hey, it&amp;rsquo;s true, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be crazy at work. We can still do our best and deliver an amazing product without making ourselves miserable working like crazy to meet some made-up numbers used as &amp;ldquo;goals&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Principles</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/principlesbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/principlesbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Principles (Summary) by Ray Dalio. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between 4 and 5 stars for this one. I would say I would rate it with 4.5, but when I was editing my notes I realized the big number of notes I had and decided to go for 5 stars.
There are many good ideas in this book and many of the things I see here are logical. If you&amp;rsquo;re a logical person (instead of an emotional one) you will understand many of the strategies he describes in this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of 1984</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/1984/</guid>
      <description>Book: 1984 by George Orwell. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between a 4 and 5 stars for this book and decided to go with 4.
The ideas behind this book are amazing, especially when you read a little bit about Orwell and the political scenario of the time. It is a criticism of many things but it&amp;rsquo;s still an interesting construct of what may happen in a very extreme scenario.
The whole idea of creating a language to limit how people describe things and how they think is a really interesting concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Lay of Aotrou and Itroun</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aotrouanditroun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aotrouanditroun/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Lay of Aotrou and Itroun by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s an OK book if you&amp;rsquo;re a Tolkien fan.
For those who like Tolkien and everything he researched, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting book to read. I would not recommend this book to someone who&amp;rsquo;s not into Tolkien.
There are three poems in this book and it tries to tell a story about how Tolkien wrote the final poem. None of them are that great alone but together they show one particular part of Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s style of writing/researching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar) by Michael D.C. Drout. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book if you are a fan of J.R.R. Tolkien (like me).
I read 10+ J.R.R. Tolkien books already. I really like the descriptive way of writing and the whole fantasy world he created. I also read some other books that are not related to middle earth.
With that said, it was amazing to me to find so much that was not explicit in the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Brief History of Time</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/briefhistoryoftime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/briefhistoryoftime/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Brief History of Time by Stephen Hawking. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book but not that simple for those who are not engaged with physics. That&amp;rsquo;s not a problem with the book, IMO, physics is complicated.
The pacing of the book is really good. He starts with the basics of physics and how paper after paper it is changing. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how Stephen Hawking puts himself as part of that story, not the center of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Introvert&#39;s Edge: How the Quiet and Shy Can Outsell Anyone</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/introvertsedge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/introvertsedge/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Introvert&amp;rsquo;s Edge: How the Quiet and Shy Can Outsell Anyone by Matthew Owen Pollard. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I bought this book because I wanted to understand a little bit more about introverts, so I can improve myself and understand others better. In the end, this book is totally related to sales, and part of it was not so interesting to me.
I have to say that his method seems to be really good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jun, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jun2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jun2018/</guid>
      <description>Guess what!? Yes, metrics for June! 📊
Books I usually don&amp;rsquo;t count how many books I read, I just track and check at the end of the month. When I saw that I read five books read this month, my face was like 😱. All of them received a 4-star review, so the result is quite good.

 Managing Oneself: This is a great book. It&amp;rsquo;s not life-changing, but there are many great tips to improve your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Fast Focus: A Quick-Start Guide To Mastering Your Attention, Ignoring Distractions, And Getting More Done In Less Time!</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fastfocusbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fastfocusbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Fast Focus: A Quick-Start Guide To Mastering Your Attention, Ignoring Distractions, And Getting More Done In Less Time! by Damon Zahariades. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book overall. I was between 4 and 5 for this one. It shares some great insights with [b:When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|35412097|When The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|Daniel H. Pink|https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1502223427s/35412097.jpg|56779991][b:When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|35412097|When The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|Daniel H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Managing Oneself</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/managingoneself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/managingoneself/</guid>
      <description>Book: Managing Oneself by Peter F. Drucker. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book is not life-changing but it&amp;rsquo;s small, straight to the point, and has many terrific bits of advice for your career and life.
I would totally recommend you to read it since it&amp;rsquo;s not expensive and quick to read/listen to (around 1 hour on Audible).
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Feedback analysis: whenever you take a crucial decision or action take note of the results you&amp;rsquo;re expecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Filosofia Explica as Grandes Questões da Humanidade</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/filosofiaquestoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/filosofiaquestoes/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Filosofia Explica as Grandes Questões da Humanidade by Clóvis de Barros Filho. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro bem interessante para aqueles que querem pensar sobre algumas coisas mais &amp;ldquo;profundas&amp;rdquo; mas sem precisar adentar em um idioma mais complicado. Os autores comentam de forma simples sobre algumas questões interessantes (e as vezes complicadas) da filosofia. Se você já conhece muitas delas mais a fundo, provavelmente esse não seja um livro para você.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hardthingabouthardthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hardthingabouthardthings/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers by Ben Horowitz. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book overall, especially if you are (or want to be) a CEO. Some (many?) ideas are not aligned with the way I would manage my own company, but there are many useful insights into hairy situations one may be faced during his CEO time.
Sometimes the author contradicts himself, IMO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Blood, Sweat, and Pixels: The Triumphant, Turbulent Stories Behind How Video Games Are Made</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bloodsweatandpixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bloodsweatandpixels/</guid>
      <description>Book: Blood, Sweat, and Pixels: The Triumphant, Turbulent Stories Behind How Video Games Are Made by Jason Schreier. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Good book overall, I did not take notes because it seems like a fictional book. :P
If you like this book I would also recommend you to read Masters of Doom and some chapters of Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution where they tell some game companies stories.
I would also add Indie game: the movie (also available on Netflix) to the list of complimentary content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/zerotoone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/zerotoone/</guid>
      <description>Book: Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future by Peter Thiel. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. There are some good insights, some things that only work for a particular context, and some others that I disagree.
I have to highlight one item of my notes:
&amp;ldquo;Even working remotely should be avoided because misalignment can creep in whenever colleagues aren&amp;rsquo;t together full-time, in the same place, every day&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for May, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/may2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/may2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s May, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for metrics! 📊
Books Two books read this month, but both received a 3 stars review: 
 Wait, What?: And Life&amp;rsquo;s Other Essential Questions: Exactly what the author says in the beginning: It&amp;rsquo;s a lecture that became a book. Not bad, but OK-ish. Shop Class as Soulcraft: An Inquiry into the Value of Work: More political views than I was expecting and the pacing is not so good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Wait, What?: And Life&#39;s Other Essential Questions</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/waitwhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/waitwhat/</guid>
      <description>Book: Wait, What?: And Life&amp;rsquo;s Other Essential Questions by James E. Ryan. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I bought this book as an Audible daily deal. For the price and size of the book, it was ok.
The book is exactly what the author says in the beginning: It&amp;rsquo;s a lecture that became a book. It can be summarized in less than 10 lines. Please read the other reviews and you will know the whole book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Shop Class as Soulcraft: An Inquiry Into the Value of Work</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/shopclasssoulcraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/shopclasssoulcraft/</guid>
      <description>Book: Shop Class as Soulcraft: An Inquiry Into the Value of Work by Matthew B. Crawford. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between 3 and 4 stars for this review but decided to stick with 3. The book has some interesting insights and the whole motorcycle thing resonates a lot with me, but in general, I found myself bored by the pacing and abstraction.
Here are my raw notes about the book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Apr, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/apr2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/apr2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for April metrics! 📊
Books Note: I write a review for each book I read. You can find them on my Goodreads account.
Again, just one book this month, and again, a 5 stars one!

A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy. This book was on my reading list for many months now. After reading it, I realized I&amp;rsquo;m practicing a fraction of Stoicism for many years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/guidetogoodlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/guidetogoodlife/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy by William B. Irvine. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about stoicism and its practices. After reading this I found that I&amp;rsquo;m practicing many techniques of stoicism for many years without knowing it.
The book starts with the history of stoicism, the first stoics, and the context of their time. The beginning is not pragmatic as I was expecting but when I finished the book, I decided it was a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Mar, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mar2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mar2018/</guid>
      <description>March is gone, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for metrics! 📊
Books Note: I write a review for each book I read. You can find them on my Goodreads account.
Just one book this month, but a 5 stars one:

When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing. This book is about optimization based on time and energy. What is the best time to do some action based on statistics? I found it to be amazing and could confirm many of the assumptions with my data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Feb, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/feb2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/feb2018/</guid>
      <description>February time! Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can get from my metrics. 😀
Books Note: I write a review for each book I read. You can find them on my Goodreads account.
I&amp;rsquo;m quite satisfied with my reading list for this month:

Five books read in a month and a 4.6 average rating. That&amp;rsquo;s what I call a good reading month.
The Art of Learning: A Journey in the Pursuit of Excellence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of Learning: A Journey in the Pursuit of Excellence</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artoflearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artoflearning/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of Learning: A Journey in the Pursuit of Excellence by Josh Waitzkin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book. I first heard of Josh when listening to Tim Ferriss show and then I got a recommendation (tks, Amir!).
The author is the guy from &amp;ldquo;Searching for Bobby Fischer&amp;rdquo; movie (http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108065/). He was a chess prodigy as a kid and a Tai Chi Chuan champion as an adult. The links between the learning of martial arts and chess are really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Richest Man in Babylon</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/richestmaninbabylon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/richestmaninbabylon/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I just read &amp;ldquo;rich dad poor dad&amp;rdquo; before reading this one and I think it ruined my experience. After reading that book first, this one looks like a puzzle you already know the answer.
This book is a series of parables of the &amp;ldquo;richest man in Babylon&amp;rdquo; (as you expect) and you need to read the parables understand the context and translate it to your life if you want to get something useful from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Rich Dad, Poor Dad</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/richdadpoordad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/richdadpoordad/</guid>
      <description>Book: Rich Dad, Poor Dad by Robert T. Kiyosaki. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The first part of this book was truly amazing. I really enjoyed the way he was showing the difference that both dads tell him how to live life and invest in his future. It was really great to take children for that because some things just don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for a child and are really easy to explain to the reader without having to rely on his current knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jan, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jan2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jan2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to write this post about my performance for the first month of the year. I think I will have some great news at the end of this post, related to my expenses.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started! 😀
Books I decided to listen to my podcasts this month, so I did not hear that many audiobooks. The only book I read this month was a physical book:

Hiding in unnatural happiness is a book I received from a monk in York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Anything You Want</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/anythingyouwant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/anythingyouwant/</guid>
      <description>Book: Anything You Want by Derek Sivers. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Amazing book! It&amp;rsquo;s worth 5 stars.
I listened to it on Audible, and it&amp;rsquo;s around 1h30 of audio, straight to the point. He is not theorizing about what should be right or what you should do to be successful. Instead, he is talking about his experience and what he thinks were the goods and bad choices he made.
This book was concise enough and with tons of valuable information to earn this 5 stars review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of Invisibility: The World&#39;s Most Famous Hacker Teaches You How to Be Safe in the Age of Big Brother and Big Data</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artofinvisibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artofinvisibility/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of Invisibility: The World&amp;rsquo;s Most Famous Hacker Teaches You How to Be Safe in the Age of Big Brother and Big Data by Kevin D. Mitnick. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is not new to me that we have a lot of security flaws everywhere. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s scary, but that&amp;rsquo;s what you sign for when you decide to use the internet.
He shows some things you can do to be anonymous but it&amp;rsquo;s tough and you usually don&amp;rsquo;t need it to live a normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Hiding in Unnatural Happiness</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/unnaturalhappiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/unnaturalhappiness/</guid>
      <description>Book: Hiding in Unnatural Happiness by Devamrita Swami. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I received this book from a monk while walking on the streets of York (UK) last year. I gave a small donation, and he told me to keep the book, so I decided to read it. He said it was about meditation, but it&amp;rsquo;s about yoga in general (not the physical practice).
I was not aware of anything related to Bhagavad Gita, Krishna, or anything like that, so it was an enjoyable reading for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Year in Review (with metrics!)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/2017/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, this post will be HUGE
TL;DR: It was a great year and I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to see the metrics and notice everything I accomplished.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I posted my yearly review publicly but as I&amp;rsquo;m doing monthly posts of my stats, it makes sense to do an annual review as well.
I do yearly reviews since around 2005 but I never post them publicly. I also write down my goals for the next year, so I can review them in the last week of the year (like I did some weeks ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Dec, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dec2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dec2017/</guid>
      <description>Came back from a travel last month and just packed my stuff to travel again this month. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it affected my performance.
Books I was traveling this month, so as usual, I&amp;rsquo;m not reading/listening to audiobooks because I prefer to focus on the place I&amp;rsquo;m visiting. For this reason, I did not finish any book this month.
With that said, it is the first time I have 4 books on my reading list at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Quantum ctrl-q</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/firefox-ctrlq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/firefox-ctrlq/</guid>
      <description>This will be a quick post to help people that are doing the same search as I was doing some minutes ago: &amp;ldquo;firefox disable ctrl+q&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;m using Firefox Quantum for some weeks now (will probably post about it in the future) and the ctrl+q &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; really annoys me.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time that I hit ctrl+q by accident just to see the entire browser and tabs being closed without warning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Nov, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/nov2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/nov2017/</guid>
      <description>Came back from a travel last month and just packed my stuff to travel again this month. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it affected my performance.
Books 
Read three books this month. My first book of H.P. Lovecraft, called At the mountains of madness was one of them. It was an interesting experience to read it. I also read about minimalism just to realize that I&amp;rsquo;m a minimalism since forever. If you like minimalism I also recommend to listen to their podcast and read their website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of At the Mountains of Madness</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mountainsofmadness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mountainsofmadness/</guid>
      <description>Book: At the Mountains of Madness by H.P. Lovecraft. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The first H.P. Lovecraft book I read/listen and now I understand what people say from his descriptions.
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how he keeps the suspense until the last 5% of the book. The bad part is that it becomes boring sometimes. You want to understand was is there and why he doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about it but he keeps describing icy mountains and large rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Minimalism: Live a Meaningful Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/minimalismbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/minimalismbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Minimalism: Live a Meaningful Life by Joshua Fields Millburn. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was expecting more from this book.
I listen to their Podcast and read some articles on their website. This book looks like a list of pointers to their website. I would just recommend it in case you want something to start your journey in minimalism thinking, so you can buy the audiobook and listen to it in your spare time before diving deep into their articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Oct, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/oct2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/oct2017/</guid>
      <description>This month was very unusual because I was traveling through Portugal and Spain for work and tourism, so it will probably affect my stats a lot. With that said, let&amp;rsquo;s see how it is. 😄
Books I read some pages from Elixir in Action, but unfortunately did not finish any book this month. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t read that much when traveling, so it&amp;rsquo;s sad but expected. 😞
Articles As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m using that same export file from Pocket and the same script to calculate the amount of articles I read:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of On Power</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/onpowerbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/onpowerbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: On Power by Robert A. Caro. Rating: ⭐️⭐️.
Not that much to learn from this &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s really small (almost two hours of audio) and looks like an abridged version of a collection of other books. I&amp;rsquo;m not American, so I&amp;rsquo;m not part of the context or his target audience and maybe it also plays some role here.
The whole thing about the electricity was a reality for my mom (and for me when I visited my grandparents as a child) in Brazil, it may be shocking to people living in New York nowadays but I already knew all of that in my own context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for sep, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sep2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sep2017/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s already the end of October and I could not manage to post my stats from September but I have a good reason for that (which you will read about in the next month 😉).
Books 
What Doesn’t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength is a book that describes what the human body can do if trained for it. The writing process is not so good for my taste, sometimes it looks like a memoir, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s non-fiction&amp;hellip; but the message it passes is really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PotHix ❤ Doist</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/doist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/doist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: I&amp;rsquo;m working on something I really believe is good at Doist and I feel great.
As I mentioned on this post (in pt-BR) I left the company I was working for the last year to join a new company. The new company is Doist and I&amp;rsquo;m working for them since July.
Some time ago a friend asked me why I joined Doist and I realized it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a love story so I decided to write the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of What Doesn&#39;t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude, and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/wimhoffbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/wimhoffbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: What Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude, and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength by Scott Carney. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was 3 stars most part of the book but I actually learned some stuff and added some pointers for further research, so it deserves a 4.
The good part of this book is to convince you, or at least inspire you to research a little bit on the topic, that we can be more than what we are now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Aug, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aug2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aug2017/</guid>
      <description>September is here, time to review my stats for August, 2017.
Books 
This is my personal record of books read in one single month. 7 freaking books. 😱
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with two small books I read. Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Audiobooks for Dogs and Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog. These two books were free on Audible for Dogs, so I decided to give them a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Rendezvous with Rama (Rama, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rendezvouswithrama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rendezvouswithrama/</guid>
      <description>Book: Rendezvous with Rama (Rama, #1) by Arthur C. Clarke. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I tend to not read much science fiction but this is a great book.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R. Tolkien because I love the way he used to build his world. I found Rama an amazing place where things work in a different way but following most of the same laws we have.
Arthur C. Clarke writes in a nice way, adding the exact number of details you need to feel immersed in the story without adding too much information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of My Favorite Universe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/myfavoriteuniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/myfavoriteuniverse/</guid>
      <description>Book: My Favorite Universe by Neil deGrasse Tyson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book to introduce physics to common people.
Neil deGrasse Tyson is great at explaining complicated topics in a simple way. The explanation of dense objects using hot chocolate and cream was really nice for me (no spoilers, read it! :D).
Did you watch Cosmos? Do you like to (or at least used to) follow Discovery Channel space documentaries? In case your answer is yes to any of these questions, you probably already know most part of this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Cesar Millan&#39;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bringinghomeashelterdog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bringinghomeashelterdog/</guid>
      <description>Book: Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog by Cesar Millan. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book for those thinking about adopting a shelter dog and did not research it yet.
I adopted my dog from a local shelter, he was abandoned at the shelter door with his brothers as a puppy. He was 2 months old when we adopted him. I had to do some research in different sources and buy some e-&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Radical Candor: Be a Kickass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/radicalcandorbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/radicalcandorbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Radical Candor: Be a Kickass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity by Kim Malone Scott. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A book every boss should read. It helps to create a culture of giving and receiving honest feedback and create great teams. It has many truths, you will notice many of them if you&amp;rsquo;re working for a big company. You may not agree with some parts of it depending on how you see work and people but if you really care about people careers and the performance of your team it makes a lot of sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jul, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jul2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jul2017/</guid>
      <description>Okay, here we go for the first full month working in my new job. :)
Books 
This month I read Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman, which was recommended by the other Doisters. It&amp;rsquo;s a great book by the guy who built the company Patagonia, a bootstrapped company, from scratch. Their way of thinking looks a lot like the way we think at Doist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Archlinux setup</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/archlinux/</guid>
      <description>I was playing with Archlinux in the last 3 or 4 years and last year I decided to reboot my configuration files and start using Xfce.
Talking to Fabio Akita about my Archlinux tunning, I heard that I should be posting about that. That&amp;rsquo;s true, so I decided to start writing it. I wrote in March and it was in draft form since then, so it&amp;rsquo;s time to release it. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/leadershipselfdeception/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/leadershipselfdeception/</guid>
      <description>Book: Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box by The Arbinger Institute. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. Good information in a good narrative form.
This is a short book with an easy to follow narrative about leadership. There are not so many notes about this one, but here they are:
 See People as people, not objects Self-betrayal is an act in contrary of what I feel I should do for another person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Game of Thrones (A Song of Ice and Fire, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gameofthrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gameofthrones/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Game of Thrones (A Song of Ice and Fire, #1) by George R.R. Martin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great book.
I know ASOIAF from the TV show &amp;ldquo;Game of Thrones&amp;rdquo;. This book was the first one I bought at Audible but decided to not start with it (33hs of content). As the 7th season of the TV show started, I decided to gather more information about the whole plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Practice Perfect: 42 Rules for Getting Better at Getting Better</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/practiceperfectbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/practiceperfectbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Practice Perfect: 42 Rules for Getting Better at Getting Better by Doug Lemov. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book with lots of advice. The structure is not so good, but it&amp;rsquo;s OK.
As the title says, it shows 42 rules to improve yourself and practice in the right way. It an introduction, 42 tips on how to get better at getting better, a conclusion, and the appendices. The structure looks like a to-do list of &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo;, so it&amp;rsquo;s not so comfortable to read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jun, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jun2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jun2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m ready to review my stats for June and share them with you! Are you? Hope so! :D
Books 
Last month I read Deep Work again because I was preparing to work for a new company. The new company is Doist, but this is a topic for a another post. It proved to be a great asset, as they also recommend reading it. From their reading list I also took The score takes care of itself and Start with Why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/letmypeoplegosurfing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/letmypeoplegosurfing/</guid>
      <description>Book: Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman by Yvon Chouinard. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was 3 stars until 70% of the book but the ending deserves 4.
This book is the story of Patagonia and how its founders deal with business, people, and the environment.
Their way of life resonates a lot with what I think is a good way to live. Maintain a sustainable business, hire people you trust and give them enough freedom to live a good life while giving their best to make the company grow, thinking about the environment, grow only when you have to grow (to supply your demand), live a minimalistic life, and so many other stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Score Takes Care of Itself: My Philosophy of Leadership</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/scoretakescareofitself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/scoretakescareofitself/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Score Takes Care of Itself: My Philosophy of Leadership by Bill Walsh. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great book on leadership. I confess that I was really bored in the first 15% of the book. The beginning is boring for those who don&amp;rsquo;t give a f*ck about football but keep reading, it worth the journey. Bill Walsh took the San Francisco 49ers from a really bad performance (2 wins/14 losses) to an amazing one (13 win/3 losses) 2 years later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/startwithwhy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/startwithwhy/</guid>
      <description>Book: Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action by Simon Sinek. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I always thought we must first have a reason to create something and this book shows some companies that are famous for doing that and how they did it.
Here are some notes about it:
 Most of what we have now is marketing by manipulation Fear is the most powerful manipulation of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 anos de Locaweb e a saida</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/locaweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 11:26:10 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/locaweb/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Esse mês eu completaria 7 anos trabalhando para a Locaweb, mas decidi sair no dia 2 de junho. Nada demais, só procurando coisas diferentes
Eu entrei na Locaweb em Junho de 2010. Na época o Fabio Kung entrou em contato comigo perguntando se eu queria me juntar a equipe de Cloud Computing.
A equipe de Cloud Depois de uma conversa com ele e com outro gestor, eu descobri que era exatamente o que eu queria fazer, trabalhar com Ruby e infraestrutura, duas coisas que eu gostava muito.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Secrets of Story: Innovative Tools for Perfecting Your Fiction and Captivating Readers</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/secretsofstory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/secretsofstory/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Secrets of Story: Innovative Tools for Perfecting Your Fiction and Captivating Readers by Matt Bird. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book on how to write books. 4.5 stars.
The book goes through many problems and misconceptions behind writing a fiction book. In the book blog, you can find a big checklist with many questions your book has to answer: http://www.secretsofstory.com/2014/09/the-ultimate-story-checklist-raising.html
There are many examples around each of these topics throughout the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress to Middleman, to Hugo using github-pages and HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hugo-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 13:54:49 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hugo-https/</guid>
      <description>Yes, it was a journey. I decided to chance my blog engine again.
But this time I decided to post about the whole transition, since I started my blog, back in 2008.
I needed a blog at the time but could not spend time creating something, I just wanted to &amp;ldquo;buy a blog&amp;rdquo; and write. Dreamhost was an awesome service for that. In one hour I bought a domain, installed a Wordpress via one click install and set up my own email via Google apps (at the time it was free).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for May, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/may2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/may2017/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again for my stats for the last month. :)
Books 
I will start a in a new company this month, so I decided to re-read Deep Work (I really recommend this one). This book is just great for everyone who wants to focus and do the hard work. It has everything to do with my new work schedule. The book about Elon Musk was a good reading as well, this guy has some great ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Louder Than Words: The New Science of How the Mind Makes Meaning</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/louderthanwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/louderthanwords/</guid>
      <description>Book: Louder Than Words: The New Science of How the Mind Makes Meaning by Benjamin K. Bergen. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book, but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.
I really like books that have a lot of research behind it, this is one of them. For almost every assumption made, the author reveals research done to support his point.
This book made me realize that our words do not give meaning to something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/deepworkbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/deepworkbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World by Cal Newport. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
re-reading 2017
I will work on a new project and this book will be a perfect fit for the new work environment, so I decided to revisit it.
I wrote my book (Desconstruindo a Web: As tecnologias por trás de uma requisição using Deep work and it was an amazing experience.
Embrace boredom is the most difficult practice from this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/elonmuskbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/elonmuskbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future by Ashlee Vance. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a life-changing book but it&amp;rsquo;s cool to understand Elon Musk path.
Here are some few sentences I like and some comments on them:
 The best minds of our time are working to make users click on ads
 That&amp;rsquo;s really sad. Elon has a great vision of the future and you can feel like him when reading the book (at least I can).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for April, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/apr2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/apr2017/</guid>
      <description>This was not a good month. I spent most of the time sick, recovering from what may be a Labyrinthitis. I still have to confirm that, but I&amp;rsquo;m in slow motion for a while.
But anyways, let&amp;rsquo;s go to the collected data.
Books Books for this month:

&amp;ldquo;Einstein no Brasil&amp;rdquo; (Einstein in Brazil) is a physical book I borrowed from a friend and The Art of The Lord of the Rings I have in my shelf (as a good LotR fan).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Power of Broke: How Empty Pockets, a Tight Budget, and a Hunger for Success Can Become Your Greatest Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerofbroke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerofbroke/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Power of Broke: How Empty Pockets, a Tight Budget, and a Hunger for Success Can Become Your Greatest Competitive Advantage by Daymond John. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
An ordinary book. 3 stars are good enough.
The whole book discusses how to do business when you have no money. Daymond is the man behind Fubu and a TV show called Shark Tank. His story is really interesting to follow because he raised his entire business out of nothing, following the power of broke principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Einstein no Brasil</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/einsteinnobrasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/einsteinnobrasil/</guid>
      <description>Book: Einstein no Brasil by Aguinaldo Prandini Ricieri. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro comum, com apenas um quote que valeu muito a pena. No geral consegui extrair algumas poucas boas informações sobre o Einstein daqui.
Muita coisa do que tem nesse livro é parte do contexto do Brasil em 1925. Apesar da visita do Einstein ter sido noticiada em vários jornais e ele ter recebido homenagens de vários grupos, não teve nada muito revelador.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Spaceman: An Astronaut&#39;s Unlikely Journey to Unlock the Secrets of the Universe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/spacemanbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/spacemanbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Spaceman: An Astronaut&amp;rsquo;s Unlikely Journey to Unlock the Secrets of the Universe by Mike Massimino. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book, 4.5 stars.
Mike does a great job describing how is the life of an astronaut. Listen (yes, I used an Audible audiobook) to his story was like living it with him. I could feel how was to be waiting for the NASA phone call after so many years trying to be an astronaut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Smarter Faster Better: The Secrets of Being Productive in Life and Business</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/smarterfasterbetter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/smarterfasterbetter/</guid>
      <description>Book: Smarter Faster Better: The Secrets of Being Productive in Life and Business by Charles Duhigg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is a good book. I almost gave 3 stars, but it is still a Mastery effect. It deserves four.
Each chapter in the book is devoted to a specific area: Motivation, Teams, Focus, Goal setting, Managing others, Decision making, Innovation, and Absorbing data.
My notes on each topic:
Motivation  Motivation is feeling in control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artoflotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artoflotr/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien by Wayne G. Hammond. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is one of those books for Tolkien fans. I do not recommend it if you did not read other books by Tolkien.
It is nice to read if you already read The Hobbit and The Lord of the Rings. This book shows a lot of details that Tolkien used as a guideline to write the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for March, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mar2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mar2017/</guid>
      <description>Back to work this month. :)
After one month vacation, I got back to my routine and got some good results this month.
Books Added three more books to the list:

I have to note here that Mastery is one of the best books I ever read. Both Mindfulness in plain English and The Urban Monk are about meditation and how to live a minimalist life.
Articles I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to find a way to track the articles I read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for February, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/feb2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/feb2017/</guid>
      <description>February was an atypical month because I was on vacation. :)
Much of my stats will reflect my travel around Europe. But no coding was done during this trip.
Books Continuing my goal to read 30 books this year, I read two books this month:

I had plans to visit Amsterdam and Oxford during my travel. Because of that I decided to read the story of Kullervo, which mention a lot about J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for January, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jan2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jan2017/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of a series that will show all the data I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting during the month. One of my goals this year is to track everything possible. These posts will help me to analyze all the data and may extract something for me.
This is not a new idea, I&amp;rsquo;m inspired by posts like this from Matthew of truevalhalla.com.
Books My goal is to read 30 books this year, so I must have an average of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Mindfulness in Plain English</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mindfulnessplainenglish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mindfulnessplainenglish/</guid>
      <description>Book: Mindfulness in Plain English by Henepola Gunaratana. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was expecting some more but after reading the description again it seems to deliver exactly what it says.
The whole book is about meditation and I would say 50% of it is about focusing on your breathe.
The chapter about loving kindness is also interesting. There are some quotes of Buddha that are really great.
Here are my raw notes about the book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Urban Monk: Eastern Wisdom and Modern Hacks to Stop Time and Find Success, Happiness, and Peace</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/urbanmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/urbanmonk/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Urban Monk: Eastern Wisdom and Modern Hacks to Stop Time and Find Success, Happiness, and Peace by Pedram Shojai. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The author was a Monk for 4 years, is a Doctor of Oriental Medicine and studied Kung Fu and Tai Chi for decades, this is what you will get from the book.
There are some chapters with a lot of meditation techniques and some tips about sustainability. The idea is to help you to live like a monk in the urban landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Mastery</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/masterybook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/masterybook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Mastery by Robert Greene. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
One of the best books I ever read.
This book goes through the life of various masters of our history. Some of them I did not know and decided to look after their life, which was a great experience as well.
If you want to be a master of something, be prepared to use a huge amount of time dealing with it and practicing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford for Tolkien fans</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/oxford-tolkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/oxford-tolkien/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: When traveling to Europe, I decided to take 2 or 3 days to visit Oxford. I will describe how was the experience of a J.R.R. Tolkien fan there.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien. Have read most of his books, the ones released when he was still alive and other edited by Christopher Tolkien.
After attending FOSDEM I decided to travel around some countries in Europe and UK. The most expensive part, the airplane tickets (Brazil -&amp;gt; Europe), were already paid, so&amp;hellip; why not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSDEM survival guide</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fosdem-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fosdem-guide/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: It was my first time at FOSDEM and it took some time to feel comfortable, this post may help newcomers.
As I mentioned in my previous post, I spoke at FOSDEM this year. It was my first time there (in the whole Europe, btw!) and it took some time to get used to the way the event goes. This post will show some tips that may help FOSDEM newcomers and maybe some veterans as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My presentation at FOSDEM 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fosdem2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fosdem2017/</guid>
      <description>This year my proposal to speak at FOSDEM was accepted and I spoke at the Desktop devroom! :)
It was my first talk in English, so I decided to do as many rehearsals as I could. I was 8 in total, but as expected, it was still a little bit faster than expected. :P
I had 30 minutes to present and I did it in 26. I usually speak fast and this presentation was made to be fast because I had a lot of content to show in 30 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de A história de Kullervo</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/kullervo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/kullervo/</guid>
      <description>Book: A história de Kullervo by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro para quem é fã de Tolkien.
Esse é um livro relativamente pequeno, com uma história de cerca de 50 páginas e muitas referências para um dos primeiros trabalhos do Tolkien. Eu só recomendaria esse livro para quem já leu outras obras do Tolkien como Silmarilion ou Os Filhos de Húrin.
A história de Kullervo inspirou muito do que aconteceu na história de Turin Turambar, além de outras coisas que são contadas no Silmarilion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Diary of a Young Girl</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/annefrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/annefrank/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Diary of a Young Girl by Anne Frank. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I decided to read this book one month before visiting the Anne Frank Museum in Amsterdam. My plan is to use the whole context of the book to have the full experience when visiting the museum.
The book is OK. Most part of it is just what you expect from a diary of a 14 years old girl, even with the whole context implied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Outliers: The Story of Success</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/outliersbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/outliersbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Outliers: The Story of Success by Malcolm Gladwell. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was a good reading. I would review this book as 3 stars but at the end, I was convinced that it made me think about many interesting things on successful people in general.
The key point of this book is: what makes successful people is a match of many factors. Some of those factors were not clear to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Memory Illusion: Remembering, Forgetting, and the Science of False Memory</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/memoryillusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/memoryillusion/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Memory Illusion: Remembering, Forgetting, and the Science of False Memory by Julia Shaw. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The whole point of this book is to show that our memories are not reliable. We can&amp;rsquo;t be sure that something happened because a lot of things may influence our past memories.
The good argument in favor of this book is its references. There are many references for academic studies. The bad part is that it is not so comfortable to read, the language is not that good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Algorithms to Live By: The Computer Science of Human Decisions</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/algorithmstoliveby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/algorithmstoliveby/</guid>
      <description>Book: Algorithms to Live By: The Computer Science of Human Decisions by Brian Christian. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is that kind of book that does not answer questions, it just creates a lot more. :)
I tend to not implement algorithms just for the sake of learning a new one and this is not a good thing. When you read these kinds of books you understand why it&amp;rsquo;s so important to know which kinds of algorithms already exists and which problems they solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Introdução à Web Semântica: A inteligência da informação</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/websemantica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/websemantica/</guid>
      <description>Book: Introdução à Web Semântica: A inteligência da informação by Diego Eis. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Tive o prazer de ajudar no processo de revisão desse livro. O assunto sempre me chamou a atenção mas nunca parei para estudar e entender as necessidades.
Esse livro vai desde o começo da internet, mostrando as outras tentativas de implementação e como chegamos na forma de mostrar dados que temos hoje. Essa forma possui alguns problemas para dar contexto para as coisas e fazer os links entre os conteúdos, e é aí que entra a web semantica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Programming Elixir: Functional |&gt; Concurrent |&gt; Pragmatic |&gt; Fun</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/programmingelixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/programmingelixir/</guid>
      <description>Book: Programming Elixir: Functional |&amp;gt; Concurrent |&amp;gt; Pragmatic |&amp;gt; Fun by Dave Thomas. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the best Elixir book I read but it&amp;rsquo;s a good book.
I started with Programming Phoenix for a more practical learning. This book feels like the other &amp;ldquo;Programming language book&amp;rdquo;. You will find how to split a string, or how you can deal with regex. In case you&amp;rsquo;re looking for the methods for many types, it will be for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck: A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artofnotgivingafuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artofnotgivingafuck/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck: A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life by Mark Manson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was good at the beginning but the end was too self-help for me.
I learned good things in this book and that&amp;rsquo;s what matters for me.
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Give a fuck about things you already have, not only what you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of TED Talks: The Official TED Guide to Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tedtalksbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tedtalksbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: TED Talks: The Official TED Guide to Public Speaking by Chris J. Anderson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
There are some cool tips in this book but it&amp;rsquo;s not so straight to the point if you&amp;rsquo;re just looking for speaking tips. If you like to speak at IT events (like I do) I really recommend http://speaking.io.
This book shows the way to deliver a presentation that earns a standing ovation at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Will It Fly?: How to Test Your Next Business Idea So You Don&#39;t Waste Your Time and Money</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/willitfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/willitfly/</guid>
      <description>Book: Will It Fly?: How to Test Your Next Business Idea So You Don&amp;rsquo;t Waste Your Time and Money . Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I like this book and have a bunch of notes to share.
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Grab a piece of paper and divide it into four sections. Then, identify the four most important parts of your life. Your categories might be, for example, Family, Career, Well-being and Money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The 10x Rule: The Only Difference Between Success and Failure</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/10xrule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/10xrule/</guid>
      <description>Book: The 10x Rule: The Only Difference Between Success and Failure by Grant Cardone. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I really like this book. I would recommend it if you are the kind of person that wants to make a difference in the world and want to be remembered in the future generations. The book will not give you that but if you follow a methodology like it recommends you will get closer to your big goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Guia Front-End: O caminho das pedras para ser um dev Front-End</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/guiafrontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/guiafrontend/</guid>
      <description>Book: Guia Front-End: O caminho das pedras para ser um dev Front-End by Diego Eis. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
O Diego Eis está aí desde a época que usávamos tabelas para construir sites, é sempre interessante absorver conteúdo de pessoas com tanto histórico.
O livro não foi escrito para o meu perfil, mas mesmo assim me fez pensar em umas coisas interessantes. Ele me fez realizar o mundo sem CSS para criação de páginas, onde você precisava colocar o estilo em todas as tags, sendo que as tags que estão dentro dela não herdariam o estilo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Einstein: His Life and Universe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/einsteinbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/einsteinbio/</guid>
      <description>Book: Einstein: His Life and Universe by Walter Isaacson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is the first biography that I read and I found it amazing.
I knew that Albert Einstein was a genius but it was not just that. He was extremely devoted to what he did. I had many quotes from this book and one of them shows what I just said:
&amp;ldquo;As long as I am able to work, I must not and will not complain, because work is the only thing that gives substance to life&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Programming Phoenix: Productive |&gt; Reliable |&gt; Fast</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/programmingphoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/programmingphoenix/</guid>
      <description>Book: Programming Phoenix: Productive |&amp;gt; Reliable |&amp;gt; Fast by Chris McCord. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is a great book for web developers learning Elixir (yeah, not just Phoenix).
I&amp;rsquo;m on the path of playing with Elixir and was looking for a book to amplify my knowledge. I first started with Programming Elixir, from Dave Thomas but I was looking for something more practical.
I decided to try Programming Phoenix and found that it shows everything I need to know about Elixir to build a web application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/phoenixproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/phoenixproject/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win by Gene Kim. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a great book for IT folks.
In case you worked (or still work) in a big company with lots of ITIL things that holds the development, this book will be like home for you.
It is a typical hero&amp;rsquo;s journey and the characters are not so well developed (IMO) but the story is still good to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Level Up Your Life: How to Unlock Adventure and Happiness by Becoming the Hero of Your Own Story</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/levelupyourlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/levelupyourlife/</guid>
      <description>Book: Level Up Your Life: How to Unlock Adventure and Happiness by Becoming the Hero of Your Own Story by Steve Kamb. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a good book but it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.
I already use many of the tips mentioned in this book and they really work. It makes a good pair with habitica.com, in case you like to play these kinds of games in real life.
There are many great references for the nerds out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escrevendo o Desconstruindo a web</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/desconstruindoaweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/desconstruindoaweb/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Escrevi um livro em 315 horas, geralmente aos fins de semana durante 2 ou 3 horas consecutivas. O processo completo durou 8 meses e foi lançado oficialmente na Rubyconfbr2016.
Como muitos já sabem, eu lancei um livro chamado Desconstruindo a web pela Casa do Código.
Eu sou meio maluco (retardado, segundo o George Guimarães) por produtividade e organização pessoal e resolvi escrever sobre como foi o processo e mostrar todas as métricas que eu coletei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rubyconf 2016</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rubyconf2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rubyconf2016/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: A melhor Rubyconf que eu participei
Nos dias 24 e 25 de Setembro de 2016 aconteceu a Rubyconf Brasil. Assim como eu fiz um post sobre o primeiro Rails Summit que o Akita participou da organização, resolvi também fazer um post sobre a última rubyconf que ele resolveu organizar.
Essa Rubyconf teve vários pontos especialmente importantes para mim. O primeiro deles foi logo no início quando o Gilberto Mautner, que é um dos fundadores da Locaweb, mencionou os números do projeto que eu estou trabalhando por lá.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/coachinghabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/coachinghabits/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp;amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Read this book in 2016 but never published any review until now (2021, even if the post date is the day I finished the book). I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say now, but at least I can publish my notes from 2016.
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Kickstart, AWE (and what else), and Focus - Are the guides for a coach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of How to Spot a Liar with People Don&#39;t Tell the Truth</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/howtospotaliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/howtospotaliar/</guid>
      <description>Book: How to Spot a Liar with People Don&amp;rsquo;t Tell the Truth by Gregory Hartley. Rating: ⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used the Audible Abridged version for this one. The narration is not good as the other audiobooks I&amp;rsquo;m used to listen.
The book content is not good to follow as well. It is focused on interrogation and this is not my goal for reading it.
But it is not all that bad. I got some interesting tips on body language and these kind of stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Thinking, Fast and Slow</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/thinkingfastslow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/thinkingfastslow/</guid>
      <description>Book: Thinking, Fast and Slow by Daniel Kahneman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The concept of system 1 (fast) and system 2 (slow) is really great.
For tech folks, the system 1 looks like a cache inside your head. It is the best way to explain it for tech related people, in my opinion.
There are dozens of serious research done to make this book happen. They were not made exclusively for the book, but it is really nice to read a book that has strong foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Armadilhas da Mente</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/armadilhasdamente/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/armadilhasdamente/</guid>
      <description>Book: Armadilhas da Mente by Augusto Cury. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Eu já tinha lido o &amp;ldquo;Ansiedade - Como Enfrentar o Mal do Século&amp;rdquo;, portanto esse livro não adicionou tanto para mim.
Esse livro mostra todos os conceitos gatilhos, janelas, autofluxo e etc. dentro de um romance. A história é ok e chega a ser interessante até perto do final. Na minha visão ficou nítido que a história não é o centro do livro e sim os conceitos que estão envolvidos com ela.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerofhabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerofhabit/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business by Charles Duhigg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Read this book for the first time in 2016 and re-read it now (2019). The first time I read it, I did not take notes, so I decided to &amp;ldquo;properly read/listen&amp;rdquo; now.
I like the number of studies this book shows and how much we understand about our habits by looking at its results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Life, the Universe and Everything (Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy, #3)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker3/</guid>
      <description>Book: Life, the Universe and Everything (Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, #3) by Douglas Adams. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nothing special about this one&amp;hellip; The first one is brilliant, the second one is great, the third is just OK.
This book made me think about reading the fourth and fifth and I think I will stop here. All that moments that make you think about &amp;ldquo;Life, Universe and Everything&amp;rdquo; are not present here like was in the first books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ouvir livros (audiobooks), o futuro da leitura</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/audiobooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/audiobooks/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Ouvir livros é o futuro.
Atualização de 18/06/2016: Adicionando o audiobooks.com.
Quem me conhece sabe que há muito tempo eu ouço podcasts sempre que eu posso, principalmente no caminho entre a minha casa e o trabalho. No fim do ano de 2015 eu vi a quantidade de livros que o Rafael Rosa leu e fiquei abismado. Ele leu mais de 90 livros em um ano! Tudo bem que ele estava em um período sabático, mas mesmo assim ainda é uma quantidade bem absurda de livros para se ler em um ano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Restaurant at the End of the Universe (Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy, #2)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker2/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Restaurant at the End of the Universe (Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, #2) by Douglas Adams. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Another great book from Douglas Adams. The idea behind the restaurant is really really interenting and the author does a great job to insert funny concepts behind the whole event.
There are some nice gotchas that make you laugh while reading, I really recommend it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy (Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker1/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy (Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, #1) by Douglas Adams. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book is amazing! There are some non-sense parts but in general, it makes you think about &amp;ldquo;life, universe, and everything&amp;rdquo;.
There are some ideas that look so absurd in real life but make sense in the book context. If you&amp;rsquo;re that kind of geek/nerd that likes physics (you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert, just an enthusiast) this book will be great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Future of the Professions: How Technology Will Transform the Work of Human Experts</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/futureofprofessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/futureofprofessions/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Future of the Professions: How Technology Will Transform the Work of Human Experts by Richard Susskind. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is a nice idea and the arguments looks valid and make you think about the future. The book is not easy to follow through and I the first 5 chapters are not so interesting. Most part of the book is an introduction to the main subject that is presented on the last chapters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Docker Security: Using Containers Safely in Production</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dockersecuritybook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dockersecuritybook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Docker Security: Using Containers Safely in Production by Adrian Mouat. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book for who is using or planning to use Docker in production. There are some very good tips that are not so obvious about Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Caixa de Ferramentas DevOps: Um guia para construção, administração e arquitetura de sistemas modernos</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/caixaferramentasdevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/caixaferramentasdevops/</guid>
      <description>Book: Caixa de Ferramentas DevOps: Um guia para construção, administração e arquitetura de sistemas modernos by Gleicon Moraes. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um bom livro para quem não conhece as ferramentas de devops do momento e está procurando alguma coisa que seja bem mão na massa. O autor mostra como usar Ansible, Docker, Vagrant e como fazer deploy usando Digital Ocean e AWS de uma forma automatizada e que pode ser aplicada a multiplas linguagens e/ou ambientes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Wolf of Wall Street (The Wolf of Wall Street, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/wolfofwallstreet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/wolfofwallstreet/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Wolf of Wall Street (The Wolf of Wall Street, #1) by Jordan Belfort. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Did you watch the movie?
Yes: you&amp;rsquo;re done. The book does not add anything relevant IMO.
No: Watch the movie.
In case you prefer books than movies, you may try this one. It is not a bad book and you will see how a smart guy can be a perfect asshole.
The only thing that I absorved from this book is: This kind of life is not for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People: Powerful Lessons in Personal Change</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/7habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/7habits/</guid>
      <description>Book: The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People: Powerful Lessons in Personal Change by Stephen R. Covey. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a good book. There are some good examples there and it is worth reading, but if you want to understand the habits in a quick and easy manner just read on the author&amp;rsquo;s website.
There are some great insights, at least for me, in this book. The author says that the world works on the &amp;ldquo;outside-in&amp;rdquo; but we need to work on the &amp;ldquo;inside out&amp;rdquo;, taking care of ourselves and doing the best to make things better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Ferreiro de Bosque Grande</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ferreirobosquegrande/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ferreirobosquegrande/</guid>
      <description>Book: Ferreiro de Bosque Grande by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
É um livro muito legal para quem é fã de Tolkien. A história é bem pequena, menos da metade de livro. O restante do livro é um pouco de contexto sobre a história e porque ela foi escrita, juntamente com algumas ligações sobre a vida do Tolkien na época.
Esse foi o último livro escrito pelo Tolkien antes de sua morte e diz muito sobre o seus pensamentos sobre escrita, sobre o mundo das &amp;ldquo;fadas&amp;rdquo; (que não tem nada a ver com o que pensamos dele atualmente) e sobre a vida no geral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Getting Real: The Smarter, Faster, Easier Way to Build a Web Application</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gettingrealbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gettingrealbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Getting Real: The Smarter, Faster, Easier Way to Build a Web Application by 37 Signals. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
There are almost 10 years from this book release and the ideas are still valid for the software development industry that we have now.
Some of them can&amp;rsquo;t be applied to big and established companies, but it shows why small companies can beat them if they know how to organize. &amp;ldquo;Divide and conquer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Do only what is needed&amp;rdquo; are the core of this book IMO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hackerscomputerrevolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hackerscomputerrevolution/</guid>
      <description>Book: Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution by Steven Levy. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book. John Carmack said it was the most inspiring book for him and I can understand why.
The word Hackers is not the same these days, but the Hacker Ethics still lives in some of the programmers out there. Those guys that keep hacking (and/or programming) for hours and hours just for the joy of create and modify things still exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of MONEY Master the Game: 7 Simple Steps to Financial Freedom</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/moneymasterthegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/moneymasterthegame/</guid>
      <description>Book: MONEY Master the Game: 7 Simple Steps to Financial Freedom by Anthony Robbins. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I have mixed feelings about this one. I got some cool insights about financing and how I can improve my plant of financial freedom, but the book was repetitive most of the time.
When I started this book my feeling was: &amp;ldquo;Man, this may be one of the best books I read&amp;rdquo;. Some time ago I was reading a lot of &amp;ldquo;soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see&amp;rdquo; or even repeating what was said before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de O Pistoleiro (A Torre Negra, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower1/</guid>
      <description>Book: O Pistoleiro (A Torre Negra, #1) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nunca tinha lido Stephen King, esse foi meu primeiro livro dele.
O começo do livro é bem confuso e muitas vezes eu tinha que reler para entender em qual contexto as coisas estavam acontecendo. Gostei do clima de suspense que o autor coloca em várias partes e das partes bizarras que foram descritas bem o suficiente para me deixar imerso e pensando.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de O Cavaleiro dos Sete Reinos (The Tales of Dunk and Egg)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dunkandegg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dunkandegg/</guid>
      <description>Book: O Cavaleiro dos Sete Reinos (The Tales of Dunk and Egg #1-3) by George R.R. Martin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good story for those who follow the whole series of &amp;ldquo;A song of ice and fire&amp;rdquo; as it occurs around 100 years before the first book.
The only part that is a bit annoying is that the story feels unfinished for me in the end, but the whole experience is good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de A Jornada do Escritor: Estrutura mítica para escritores</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jornadaescritor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jornadaescritor/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Jornada do Escritor: Estrutura mítica para escritores by Christopher Vogler. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Essential reading for those who wants to write a book. I really like the way that Christopher explores movies like Titanic, Pulp Fiction, and The Lion King. The examples of the Hero&amp;rsquo;s journey based on this movie really helped me to understand the various archetypes and how they interact in each stage of the journey.
Just read it for the first time but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that I&amp;rsquo;ll read it again soon and keep it on my desk for reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Study in Scarlet (Sherlock Holmes, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sherlockholmes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sherlockholmes1/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Study in Scarlet (Sherlock Holmes, #1) by Arthur Conan Doyle. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book! I always wanted to read Sherlock Holmes books but never tried it. Thanks to BBC&amp;rsquo;s Sherlock Series I decided to give it a try. The good part is that I could understand a lot of jokes that the TV show made and the differences from the 189x to 201x. :)
I really recommend you to read it if you like stories on investigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Masters of Doom: How Two Guys Created an Empire and Transformed Pop Culture</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mastersofdoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mastersofdoom/</guid>
      <description>Book: Masters of Doom: How Two Guys Created an Empire and Transformed Pop Culture by David Kushner. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I love this book. The two Johns created an empire by using the engineering capabilities of Carmack with the enthusiasm and ideas of Romero.
There are some other thoughts to put in this book. The two Johns are doing great and creating amazing games following the startup way of life, relying on junk food and diet coke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Cartas do Papai Noel por J.R.R Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/cartaspapainoel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/cartaspapainoel/</guid>
      <description>Book: Cartas do Papai Noel by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Eu realmente admiro o J.R.R Tolkien. Esse tipo de livro mostra como ele usava toda a sua imaginação e suas habilidades para fazer coisas para os filhos dele.
Para quem é fã das obras do Tolkien vai curtir bastante esse livro. Se você é pai (não é o meu caso) talvez veja uma forma legal de lidar com o seu filho pequeno e fazer brincadeiras durante os anos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Big Drop: How To Grow Your Wealth During the Coming Collapse</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bigdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bigdrop/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Big Drop: How To Grow Your Wealth During the Coming Collapse by James Rickards. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
TL; DR - A lot of theories about the next economic crash, if you want to know some connections between gold, dollar and other different investments to protect you in case it happens, it may be a good book for you.
I&amp;rsquo;m Brazilian and some part of the economic context is not the same here, but there are some parts make totally sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/freakonomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/freakonomics/</guid>
      <description>Book: Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything by Steven D. Levitt. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book with really interesting statistics done in some sets of data. It remembers me about the whole &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; trend that we have today.
In some parts it looks like the comparison of the global warming and the number of pirates (as my &amp;ldquo;Statistics One&amp;rdquo; professor and the book author used to say: &amp;ldquo;correlation does not imply causation&amp;rdquo;), but the whole idea behind the studies are really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Management 3.0: Leading Agile Developers, Developing Agile Leaders</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/management30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/management30/</guid>
      <description>Book: Management 3.0: Leading Agile Developers, Developing Agile Leaders by Jurgen Appelo. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I read this book in 2015 when the product director of the company I worked for suggested to buy a bunch of copies and do a book club on that book. The director (and many of us, leaders) liked the ideas here, but there were not not attractive to the rest of the directors. Needless to say that reading this didn&amp;rsquo;t change anything in how the company does things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiences of almost two years using Colemak</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/colemak-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/colemak-experience/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: I like Colemak, and it is a very good layout. I found some equivalent pros and cons, so I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it to anyone without a little bit of philosophy. :)
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know Colemak, it is a keyboard layout created to make the most used keys stay in the home row as well as make you swipe between your right and left hand.
There is a keyboard layouts heatmap for you to understand the benefits of using a keyboard layout that was designed to help you to be comfortable and fast when typing instead of one that helping the operator to not jam the typewriter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As escolhas do desenvolvedor</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/escolhasdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/escolhasdev/</guid>
      <description>Esse ano fui chamado para palestrar em todas as edições do Encontro Locaweb que acontecem por várias cidades do Brasil! Palestrei em 6 cidades de estados diferentes, e aconteceram na seguinte ordem:
 Belo Horizonte Curitiba Recife Porto Alegre Rio de Janeiro São Paulo  Adicionei os links para as fotos dos eventos na listagem acima. :)
Minha palestra se chama &amp;ldquo;As escolhas do desenvolvedor&amp;rdquo; e fala sobre as escolhas que fazemos durante nossa carreira de desenvolvedor, escolhas com linguagens, configurações de servidores, deploy, equipe, testes e etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSCON 2015</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/oscon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/oscon/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR I&amp;rsquo;ve been at OSCON this year (thanks to Locaweb) and this post will summarize my impressions about the conference. I spoke at Locaweb Tech-Talks about it and you can find my slides here (in portuguese).
OSCON (Open Source Conference) is one of the most important open source conferences of our time and happened in Portland this year as usual. Portland is a great city, the one I liked the most until now, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have high car traffic, MAX (the train) took us for most of the places we wanted to know, nice people all over the place, great convention center and a lot of other benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New layout of PotHix blog</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/layout2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/layout2015/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new blog layout of PotHix.com! :)
I decided that the time has came to change not just the layout but the blog engine as well. I&amp;rsquo;m now using middleman instead of wordpress. Just to be clear, I don&amp;rsquo;t think wordpress is not good at all, but I want to publish static files instead of keeping the wordpress &amp;ldquo;infrastructure&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve divided into 3 feeds:
 Only english posts: http://feeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby, Python e native threads</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/threads-rubypython/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/threads-rubypython/</guid>
      <description>Pode ser que eu seja meio burro (heheh) mas eu ainda achava que o Ruby e o Python usavam Green Threads, mas depois de conversar com uma galera me disseram que eram threads nativas. Pesquisando na internet eu vi que eram mesmo, mas decidi rodar um strace para ver elas rolando e postar sobre isso.
Fiz dois scripts simples:
Python
import threading import time for i in range(5): t = threading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang and 1.2 version performance improvement</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/golang12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/golang12/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Go last month and I really liked to work with the language.
The project I&amp;rsquo;m working on is dead simple and just retrieves metrics and save on a redis server (the data will be analyzed by a different project that I&amp;rsquo;m working on). So I have 15 goroutines retrieving data constantly and I&amp;rsquo;m using just two native threads.
I did some CPU profiling on the code using my current machine for Golang 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O Guru-SP e seus 5 anos de vida</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gurusp5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gurusp5/</guid>
      <description>Há pouco tempo aconteceu o encontro numero 31 do Guru-SP, e como sempre saímos (dessa vez estavamos @vinibaggio, @agaelebe, @nuxlli e @anderson_leite) para aquele velho momento de bate papo pós evento. Durante a conversa o @nuxlli perguntou sobre como o Guru-SP começou e nesse momento eu comecei a relembrar daquela velha tarde em 2008.
Mas peraí&amp;hellip; 2008!! O Guru-SP está próximo de fazer 5 anos de vida! :)
Em pensar que tudo começou após um post do @agaelebe na Rails-br falando sobre criar grupos locais para conversar mais sobre Ruby e fazer encontros com mais frequência, o que gerou interesse de várias pessoas de São Paulo, que decidiram levar esse &amp;ldquo;projeto&amp;rdquo; pra frente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendendo minhas coisas</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/venda2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/venda2013/</guid>
      <description>Esse ano aconteceram algumas coisas zuadas para mim e resolvi capitalizar o dinheiro das coisas que eu tenho e começar denovo no ano que vem.
Procurei preços justos para tudo que estou vendendo (os links das minhas pesquisas estão nas descrições dos produtos), mas caso alguém ache que alguma das coisas está com um preço não-justo e estiver interessado é só entrar em contato que negociamos.
Estou aproveitando para testar a plataforma do loja integrada, mas os pagamentos eu prefiro que sejam por depósito mesmo, e se possível marcamos a entrega pessoalmente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendo Dragstar 2008</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dragstar2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dragstar2008/</guid>
      <description>Chegou a hora de pendurar o colete por um tempo, obviamente estarei de volta num futuro não tão distante, mas pelo menos por enquanto vou ficar um tempo sem motos. Por esse motivo estou vendendo minha Dragstar 2008.
Informações sobre ela:
 Segundo dono Licenciada 2013 31000 km de boas estradas! Pneu dianteiro e traseiro trocados há menos de 1000km (duraram mais ou menos 29k)  Acessórios que vão com ela (além de todas as peças originais):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendo intruder 125 customizada e com guidão seca suvaco</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/intruder125/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/intruder125/</guid>
      <description>Depois de brincar de customização de motos por um tempo chegou a hora de vender minha intrudinha. Estou com ela desde 2008 e só me deu alegrias.
Algumas informações sobre ela:
 Único dono Toda a parafernalha que veio com ela quando eu comprei eu ainda tenho IPVA pago Pneu traseiro praticamente novo, não rodou nem 100km Bateria nova, 1 mês de uso Motor, protetor de corrente e paralamas frontal são preto fosco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Network Programming</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/game-netprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/game-netprog/</guid>
      <description>English Abstract: This post was about my presentation with Diego Souza (vulgo Marciano) about Game network programming. I was studying and reading Quake source just for fun and decided to learn more about game networking in general, so I decided to prepare this presentation to show other people what I’ve learned. You can see the full video (portuguese only, sorry) and the slides below.
Portuguese: Eu e o Diego Souza (vulgo Marciano) fizemos uma palestra sobre Game network programming tanto na Locaweb como no Guru-SP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plaev, HTML5 e Skeleton-jigsaw</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/skeleton-jigsaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/skeleton-jigsaw/</guid>
      <description>Depois de muito tempo desenvolvendo finalmente terminamos o Skeleton-Jigsaw em outubro! Demorei para postar sobre isso aqui no blog por falta de tempo, mas aqui está!
Eu e o Rafael Masoni trabalhamos nesse jogo durante quase 1 ano (começamos a falar dele no comecinho de janeiro) investindo nosso tempo livre para fazer todas as partes do jogo (audio, programação, arte, game design, level design e etc).
Vou descrever um pouco do que fizemos e como organizamos, mas vai ser apenas um resumo do que falamos na nossa palestra no Guru-SP:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saudades do Poker</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/poker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/poker/</guid>
      <description>Apesar de eu não ser bom o suficiente eu curto bastante jogar poker, mas as poucas vezes que me juntei com os amigos pessoalmente para jogar foi na época da faculdade, que marcavamos as &amp;ldquo;poker nights&amp;rdquo; e jogavamos apostando pequenas quantias.
Depois de sair da faculdade eu sempre penso em tentar juntar aquele pessoal novamente, ou até mesmo juntar outras pessoas para poder jogar, mas eu acho difícil conseguir contato com o aquele pessoal novamente e a galera que eu tenho contato hoje geralmente não sabem jogar e tampouco se importam em aprender, ainda mais quando sabem que o jogo só tem graça quando está valendo dinheiro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lifestyle</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>Just a transcript from here, but it reflects my way of life at this stage of my life:
We believe in going our own way,no matter which way the rest of the world is going. We believe in bucking the system that’s built to smash individuals as bugs on a windshield. Some of us believe in the man upstairs.All of us believe in sticking in to the man down here. We believe in the sky and we don’t believe in the sunroof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript and Gamedev discussion</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jsgamedev-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jsgamedev-discussion/</guid>
      <description>I read the blog post from Impact engine creator Dominic where he shows an email he sent to John Carmack about his opinions on Javascript expressed on his keynote.
Dominic is trying to show that Javascript is not a good language to develop the next AAA game but it is awesome to make simple games and have it easily available to the world.
We have a lot of negative comments on the post (I really don&amp;rsquo;t know why) but some good ones too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Ruby on Rails: coloque sua aplicação web nos trilhos</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/railsvinibaggio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/railsvinibaggio/</guid>
      <description>Book: Ruby on Rails: coloque sua aplicação web nos trilhos by Vinícius Baggio Fuentes. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Esse livro é muito legal para quem não conhece Rails e quer colocar a mão na massa criando uma aplicação do zero. Com ele você consegue explorar uma boa parte do que é necessário para criar uma aplicação comum usando o framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel compiling</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/kernel-compiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/kernel-compiling/</guid>
      <description>Since I bought an Acer notebook to use Linux again (I sold my mac, I have a post about it but in portuguese) I started to compile my own kernel.
The reasons for the decision:
I have a hardware that works better with the newer kernels. I really want to understand the linux kernel better. As Judas Priest sings on Painkiller song: “I’m living on the eeeeeedge”. LOL
How to proceed There are some steps to follow when compiling a new kernel for your Linux box:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menos mac e mais Linux</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mac-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mac-linux/</guid>
      <description>TL; DR Usei mac por mais de 6 meses e decidi voltar ao Linux. Na minha opinião mac não é ruim, mas Linux é melhor.
A idéia desse post não é fazer um flame war, muito menos justificar porque eu voltei para o Linux (afinal, eu não devo nada pra ninguém), e sim falar um pouco do que eu vi de vantagens e desvantagens no Mac e porque eu resolvi voltar a usar Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aprendendo com o código do Quake</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/quakecode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/quakecode/</guid>
      <description>Desde que eu terminei a faculdade eu venho lendo bastante coisa útil (foi muita coisa inútil durante 4 anos&amp;hellip;) e aprendendo bastante coisa. Nos ultimos meses eu li vários code reviews dos códigos do Quake e do Doom.
Os review foram feitos por Fabien Anglard e estão todos disponíveis no site dele http://fabiensanglard.net.
O primeiro artigo que eu li foi sobre o code review do código do Quake 2 de 1997.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simlinks for ruby on Debian Squeeze</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ruby-debian-squeeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ruby-debian-squeeze/</guid>
      <description>Every time we need to deploy a new Ruby application on top of Debian Squeeze we need to fix some Ruby depedencies to make the application work as it should.
It happens because we&amp;rsquo;re building using rvm instead of the packaged version of ruby, but it needed to be that way in order to use our old build server.
I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it documented here:
ln -s /usr/lib/libruby-1.9.1.so.1.9.1 /usr/lib/libruby.so.1.9 ln -s /usr/bin/rake1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palestra sobre implementacoes paralelas</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/implementacoes-paralelas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/implementacoes-paralelas/</guid>
      <description>Esse post ficou como draft desde que eu palestrei sobre implementações paralelas, e agora que eu lembrei dele decidi publicar! :)
Bem, como eu disse, eu paletrei sobre implementacoes paralelas tanto na Locaweb como no Guru-SP. A idea da palestra vem de um post do John Carmack sobre implementações paralelas, e nesse post ele comenta sobre todos os tipos de implementação paralela que ele já utilizou e as que mais funcionaram para cada tipo de caso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMPP e Ruby</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rubyxmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rubyxmpp/</guid>
      <description>Alguns (vários…) meses atrás eu fiz uma palestra pequena no Guru-SP(São Paulo Ruby Users Group) sobre Ruby e XMPP, os vídeos e slides estão disponíveis:
Nessa talk eu mostrei como criar dois bots simples e como subir eles na sua conta do Gmail. A Gem blather tem uma DSL bem legal para trabalhar com XMPP em Ruby, mas nos meus testes funcionou muito melhor com ruby 1.9.3 do que com 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viagem de moto para Eldorado na Argentina</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/moto-argentina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/moto-argentina/</guid>
      <description>TL; DR Fiz uma viagem de moto saindo de São Paulo e indo para Eldorado (Argentina) , durou uma semana no total e rodei mais de 3000km, esse é o relato da viagem.
Quem quiser ver todas as fotos que eu tirei durante a viagem, estão no Picasa
Bem, vamos ao relato:
Essa foi minha primeira viagem para fora do Brasil e também a minha primeira viagem grande de moto (tinha feito uma de 700km no total 350 contínuo), e é claro que com essas condições eu tava meio perdido para organizar as coisas, preocupado com a moto e etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palestra sobre Gamedev, Javascript e HTML5</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gamedev-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gamedev-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Esse fim de semana eu palestrei no FLISOL de São José dos Campos sobre desenvolvimento de jogos, Javascript e HTML5. Foi uma palestra simples e rápida, durou pouco mais de meia hora (preciso aprender a falar um pouco mais devagar :P) mas foi divertido.
A grande maioria das pessoas que estavam assistindo a palestra não eram desenvolvedores, e estavam começando a estudar agora, e acho que por isso não surgiram muitas perguntas sobre o assunto, mesmo eu evitando colocar código.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sempre aprender coisas diferentes</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aprender/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aprender/</guid>
      <description>Estou começando a fazer meu TCC agora e resolvi brincar um pouco com LaTeX. Ja faz um bom tempo que eu queria brincar um pouco com ele, entender melhor como funciona e por que tanta gente usa ele e acha legal.
Eu tive um pouco de experiência com LaTeX quando estava ajudando a escrever o vimbook, mas não tive contato o suficiente por que entrei no meio do projeto e já estava tudo pronto, foi só seguir a estrutura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalando o Full Throttle no Motorola Milestone</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fullthrottle-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fullthrottle-android/</guid>
      <description>Logo depois que eu comprei a minha Dragstar 650, me deu uma grande vontade de voltar a jogar full throttle (por que será, né?), e eu comecei a procurar uma forma de fazer isso.
Eu tenho o jogo (o CD-ROM mesmo) ripado no meu computador, e agora só faltava emular ele.
Procurando na internet eu achei o scummvm que emula os games da LucasArts em várias plataformas! Baixei o .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PotHix e as motos</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pothix-motos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pothix-motos/</guid>
      <description>Bem, para introduzir um assunto sobre os meus Hobbies aqui no blog eu vou falar um pouco da minha história com motos. Eu nunca gostei da idéia de ter um veículo, mas na época que eu comecei a trabalhar mais longe e fazer faculdade eu estava gastando 4 horas diárias dentro de onibus, e isso estava me incomodando bastante, mesmo eu ouvindo podcasts todos os dias eu ainda considerava isso como tempo perdido.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viajar de moto com um grupo de motociclistas</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/motogrupo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/motogrupo/</guid>
      <description>Pois é! Essa era uma das coisas que eu tinha vontade de fazer há muito tempo, mas não queria ir de Intruder 125, e agora o momento chegou. :)
Depois que comprei o monstro (apelido da minha Dragstar 650), a vontade de viajar de moto aumentou muito, afinal, montar sobre 650cc com 40HP para andar por bairro é zuado! :P
Aproveitei o natal e fui com uns amigos para Itanhaém, eu sozinho na moto e eles de carro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizando os Feeds do Blog</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/feeds2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/feeds2011/</guid>
      <description>Como muitos sabem, eu sou meio doido por organização (heheh) e eu mesmo não gosto de ficar lendo coisas que não me interessam de outros blogs, ou seja, no blog de alguém que gosta bastante de Vim eu ter que ficar lendo sobre paraquedismo :P
Agora eu gostaria de além de escrever sobre coisas técnicas, escrever também sobre os meus outros hobbies, como Motos, Shows e etc. Alguns deles eu até já escrevia um pouco antes, mas nem tanto, e isso já me incomodava um pouco, por que eu sei bem que várias pessoas que seguem o feed não gostam das mesmas coisas que eu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meu ambiente de desenvolvimento</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ambiente-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ambiente-dev/</guid>
      <description>Fui convidado pelo @jtadeulopes e pelo @qmx para participar do meme sobre ambientes de desenvolvimento, então estou fazendo esse post para falar um pouco mais sobre o meu.
Sistema Operacional Já usei Windows um bom tempo atrás, e agora tenho um pós-conceito para usar (preconceito é só quando vc não conhece), não vejo nenhuma vantagem para utilizar ele e acho que não vale o preço (tenho um Vista e um Win7 originais que ganhei na compra do notebook e na CampusParty e nem uso).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semana de eventos (#rubyconfbr, #adl e #gddbr)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rubyconfbr-adl-gddbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rubyconfbr-adl-gddbr/</guid>
      <description>Na semana passada (semana do dia 24 ao dia 30 de outubro) foi uma semana de grandes eventos, que eu tive o prazer de participar de todos! :)
Rubyconf Brasil A Rubyconf Brasil é o Antigo Rails Summit Latin America, que acontecia no centro de convenções do Anhembi, e agora mudou sua localização para o centro de convenções Frei Caneca, para diminuir os custos e prover um local mais acessível para os participantes (próximo ao metrô e a avenida paulista).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conto da migração para Rails 3</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/migracao-rails3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/migracao-rails3/</guid>
      <description>Nesse post eu vou falar um pouco de como foi atualizar a aplicação que eu trabalho atualmente para Rails3.
Em uma segunda feira eu tive a brilhante ideia de aproveitar que as tasks que eu estava fazendo estavam dependentes de algumas coisas que ainda não estavam feitas, e resolvi começar a atualizar a aplicação para Rails3 só para saber o trabalho que ia dar, e no final do dia eu já tinha feito todas as alterações necessárias para o boot da aplicação e para rodar a suite de testes (não fazer os testes passar, apenas rodar!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluxo de leitura e o Android</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/leitura-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/leitura-android/</guid>
      <description>Quem me conhece sabe como eu sou meio doido quanto a ler coisas aleatórias (Google reader e artigos interessantes que eu acho perdidos por aí), e como eu tenho um tempo um pouco limitado, devido ao trabalho e a faculdade eu sempre tenho alguns esquemas diferentes para ler. :P
Fluxo de leitura Depois que eu comprei um Android o meu fluxo de leitura se modificou um pouco. E está da seguinte maneira:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorola Milestone e Android</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/motorola-milestone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/motorola-milestone/</guid>
      <description>Muita gente tem me perguntado sobre o meu Android atual, um motorola Milestone, e resolvi postar algumas informações e opiniões sobre o aparelho e sobre o Android em si.
Primeiramente, gostaria de dizer que o Android é um sistema muito bom, e estou bastante satisfeito com as features, apps, SDK e etc.
Milestone É um aparelho bem legal e na minha opinião é o Android mais &amp;ldquo;custo X benefício&amp;rdquo; do Brasil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rework/</guid>
      <description>Hoje terminei de ler o livro da 37signals chamado Rework! E vou falar um pouco sobre a idéia dele aqui.
Atualmente eu fiz uma compra na Amazon em conjunto com uns amigos (@vinibaggio, @hugobarauna, @cantoniodasilva), e cogitei a compra do Rework, mas depois de uma pergunta no Twitter e algumas respostas sobre a idéia do livro eu resolvi não comprar, pois parecia muito gerencial, e acabei optando por outros (Design Patterns In Ruby, Ruby Programming Language, The Pragmatic Programmer), que falarei em outros posts :P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FISL11</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fisl11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fisl11/</guid>
      <description>Finalmente depois de 4 anos planejando eu consegui ir para o FISL! :)
Para quem ainda não sabe, eu estou trabalhando na Locaweb desde o começo deste mês e consegui ir com a equipe deles para o FISL.
Esperava um conteúdo técnico melhor no FISL, e algumas palestras (ou a falta de boas palestras) me decepcionou um pouco, mas pelo que eu fiquei sabendo foi decisão do público os temas, então ficou meio incontrolável.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silmarilion</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/silmarilion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/silmarilion/</guid>
      <description>Book: Silmarilion by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is J.R.R. Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s life work. The other known books a product of this. He was not able to finish this masterpiece, but Christopher Tolkien finished his father&amp;rsquo;s work in a great way.
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie, the Silmarilion is not an easy to read book. I would not recommend it to anyone who was not totally aware of the other books and still looking for more middle earth content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de Março</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-mar2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-mar2010/</guid>
      <description>Como vocês puderam perceber (ou não) eu não postei sobre os serviços legais de fevereiro e tenho um bom motivo para isso: Não achei nenhum serviço que valia a pena ser mencionado e não queria fazer um post enchendo linguiça! :P
O meu ultimo post foi sobre o Yahoo Open Hack 2009, e lá eu pude conhecer muita coisa legal, e ver outras nascendo de projetos lá mesmo! Por isso tenho informações legais para essa série novamente!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux, Vim, Screen e Pair programming!</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/linux-pairprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/linux-pairprog/</guid>
      <description>Aqui estou eu mais uma vez para falar mais uma das maluquices que eu fiz um bom tempo atrás mas não tive tempo de postar.
Primeiramente eu vou falar o que muita gente já falou muito bem, que é sobre screen e pair programming. Mas vou dizer como funcionou para mim. Alguns posts que eu li antes e depois de começar a brincar com screen e pair programming, e que eu gostei:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palestra sobre Vim</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/palestra-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/palestra-vim/</guid>
      <description>Esse vai ser um post curto, apenas para deixar registrado algumas informações sobre a palestra de Vim que teve no sétimo encontro do Guru-sp (sim, eu fui o palestrante :D).
Primeiramente, já começo com uma desculpa, por que já faz mais de 2 semanas que palestrei e só agora estou fazendo esse post. :(
Foi bem legal palestrar para uma galera que já conhecia ao menos um pouco do editor. Quando eu estava planejando o que eu ia falar eu fiquei com uma grande dúvida de qual seria a minha linha de apresentação, por que eu não sabia quantos já conheciam o editor, portanto eu poderia chegar falando de coisas avançadas e ninguem entenderia nada, ou pelo contrário, se muitos conhecessem e eu chegasse falando de coisas básicas demais a palestra seria um saco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo Open Hack 2010</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hack2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hack2010/</guid>
      <description>Para quem ainda não soube, no final de semana passado rolou o Yahoo Open Hack Day 2010! O intuito do evento é juntar uma grande quantidade de Hackers para criar serviços úteis utilizando informações públicas e de preferência utilizar as API&amp;rsquo;s do Yahoo (havia premios para alguns hacks com elas).
Uma das coisas legais do evento é que nada é proibido com relação aos Hacks, ou seja, você pode fazer um Hack com as ferramentas do Google (não vai concorrer aos premios, mas poderá apresentar lá e tudo mais), todas as linguagens de programação estão permitidas, não somente hacks web eram permitidos, o que deixou a criatividade ir longe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Party 2010</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/campusparty2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/campusparty2010/</guid>
      <description>Esse começo de ano eu estou aproveitando para participar de alguns eventos, e a Campus Party é um dos principais deles. Assim que eu entrei na empresa que eu estou trabalhando atualmente eu já informei que em janeiro tinha um evento que eu gostaria muito de participar (entrei na empresa em abril :P) e deixei combinado que eu estaria liberado para o tal, portanto agora consegui uma semana de férias para aproveitar a campus party!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show do Metallica</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/metallica2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/metallica2010/</guid>
      <description>E vou para um assunto meio OFF no meu blog (ou não), que é falar de shows que vou, nesse caso o do Metallica!
Há muito tempo queria que o Metallica viesse para o Brasil, e no ano passado que tiveram vários shows bons (ACDC, Motorhead, Megadeth, Iron Maiden e etc) fiquei sabendo que eles viriam ao Brasil e já antecipei a compra do ingresso com a ajuda do meu amigo Bruno Assis que é cliente do CityBank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de Janeiro</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-jan2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-jan2010/</guid>
      <description>E ae galera! Vamos para mais um post sobre os serviços legais do mes.
OpenDNS Estranho eu falar de OpenDNS não? Já existe faz tanto tempo e muita gente já conhece/usa. O que me fez colocar ele na lista de serviços legais foi justamente as opções que você tem na web do OpenDNS!
Se você se cadastrar no OpenDNS você pode configurar muitas coisas legais, como por exemplo a página de endereço não encontrado, ou a página de tentativa de fishing, entre outras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cabeça de Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/stevejobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/stevejobs/</guid>
      <description>Aqui estou eu novamente para falar de um livro que eu li nas férias! Dessa vez vou comentar sobre: &amp;ldquo;A cabeça de Steve Jobs&amp;rdquo;
Sobre o livro O livro é bem interessante e conta como Steve Jobs fez para ter o sucesso que tem atualmente, contando não somente os acertos, mas também os erros de Steve com o mercado, o que faz com que você caia na real que ele (assim como você) é apenas uma pessoa comum e que as vezes suas decisões fantásticas levavam a uma má situação.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anjos e Demônios</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/anjosedemonios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/anjosedemonios/</guid>
      <description>Felizmente eu estou de férias da faculdade novamente, e isso me dá um tempo livre para ler alguns livros, portanto resolvi começar com “Anjos e Demônios“, que é um livro que eu estou postergando a leitura faz mais de 2 anos (desde que li o código da vinci).
Eu particularmente gosto dos livros do Dan Brown, pois em sua grande maioria são histórias “polemicas” por misturar alguns fatos reais (que ninguem consegue provar a favor nem contra) com outros que são pura ficção.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crontab dentro da sua aplicação rails com whenever</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/crontab-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/crontab-rails/</guid>
      <description>Hoje estou aqui para falar de uma coisa que quando vi pela primeira vez ignorei por parecer uma coisa boba, mas olhando melhor eu percebi que é uma idéia bem interessante. O que a gem whenever faz é manter o seu crontab de uma forma mais Ruby, e melhor, dentro da sua aplicação!
A principio parece estranho tentar manter o crontab dentro da sua aplicação, mas ganhamos muitas vantagens com isso:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev In Sampa</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/devinsampa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/devinsampa/</guid>
      <description>Nesse sábado, dia 28/11/2009 aconteceu aqui em São Paulo (obviamente! :P ) o Dev In Sampa! Um evento para desenvolvedores em geral, sem foco em uma determinada linguagem de programação, ou seja, um evento bem legal e pragmatico! :D
Perdi um pouco a hora, portanto não assisti o começo da palestra do José Valim, que por sinal é um assunto que muito me interessa, portanto recorri aos vídeos do @agaelebe para assistir o comecinho.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de dezembro</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-dec2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-dec2010/</guid>
      <description>Infelizmente não consegui postar sobre os serviços legais do mes de novembro por que eu estava cheio de coisas para fazer ( devido as provas de fim de ano, e meu curso é anual ), portanto não consegui agregar nada para novembro, e muito menos tempo para postar. Mas agora estou eu aqui denovo para postar sobre o que eu achei de legal na internet nesse meio tempo! E lá vamos nós:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show do ACDC</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/acdc2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/acdc2009/</guid>
      <description>Como muitos sabem eu tive o prazer de estar no show do ACDC aqui no Brasil, que aconteceu no dia 27 de novembro de 2009.
Eu não queria perder esse show por nada, por vários motivos, sendo 2 deles:
 Eu curto pra caramba ACDC Os caras já estão bem velhinhos! Assim como o Ozzy que eu fui e já pensava que podia ser a ultima vez :P  O show foi no estádio do Morumbi:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Summit 2009</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/railssummit2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/railssummit2009/</guid>
      <description>Esse é um post para relatar como foi o Rails Summit Latin America desse ano! 😀 Já começo o post com um grande #win para a organização do #railssummit, por que eles tem tomadas para todos e wi-fi liberado para todos os participantes, o que ajuda para que pessoas como eu possam ficar postando no blog durante o evento, :) Vamos ao evento!
Rails Insurgency – Chad Fowler A palestra foi muito interessante e o Chad Fowler falou sobre como é a dificuldade de implantar uma aplicação Rails em uma grande empresa quando você tem grandes gerentes que te enchem de perguntas do tipo: “Rails faz X?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de outubro</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-oct-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-oct-2009/</guid>
      <description>Já estava me esquecendo de postar sobre os serviçoes legais desse mes! :P
Estava com poucos quando lembrei, mas não demorou muito para que eu lembrasse de alguns muito bons. Vamos lá!
yUML&amp;lt; O yUML é um serviço para se criar UML facilmente utilizando apenas uma URL com determinadas marcações. O caike que me mostrou no ultimo post quando eu tinha mencionado sobre criação deUML. Valeu Caike!
Gliffy Continuando em diagramas e UML temos o Gliffy que também faz uma grande quantidade de diagramas diferentes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalando e configurando o monit</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/monit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/monit/</guid>
      <description>Esses dias eu peguei para instalar o monit no servidor da empresa que eu trabalho e sofri um pouquinho com algumas coisas básicas, portanto decidi postar aqui para que seja útil para quem quer começar a utilizar o monit.
Se você usa Ubuntu, você pode fazer download do Monit por apt-get:
sudo apt-get install monit  Se você não usa Ubuntu ou quer a ultima versão do Monit, então faça download do tar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de setembro</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-sep-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-sep-2009/</guid>
      <description>E lá vamos nós novamente para mais um post sobre os serviços legais que eu encontrei esse mes.
Creately O Creately é um site para se fazer diagramas! Eu estava procurando por isso faz bastante tempo e nunca tinha achado um satisfatório, mas esse parece ser muito bom!
Com ele é possível fazer uma grande quantidade coisas, como diagramas de classe, fluxograma, esqueletos de layout e mais um monte de coisas legais e depois exportar para alguns formatos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meme: Game design ao Extremo</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/meme-gamedesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/meme-gamedesign/</guid>
      <description>Estou escrevendo esse post por que fui convocado para esse meme pelo Bruno Croci, que foi meu parceiro no desenvolvimento de um dos games vencedores do GameJam do itaú cultural, o Robotz Warehouse.
A idéia do post é mostrar alguns games interessantes e falar a sua opinião sobre eles. As regras são:
 Liste quantos jogos em Flash quiser. Preferencialmente aqueles que, por algum motivo de design chamaram sua atenção. Diga o que desses jogos te chamou a atenção, seja em quantas linhas quiser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saldo final das férias de julho</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ferias-julho2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ferias-julho2009/</guid>
      <description>Eu sempre digo que a faculdade me atrasa bastante, por que eu não consigo estudar/fazer um monte de coisas que eu tenho vontade para me dedicar as coisas que a faculdade me obriga a fazer. Se a faculdade é bom ou ruim não é discussão para esse post, mas resolvi postar a quantidade de coisas que eu consegui fazer nessas férias aproveitando que eu não precisava me preocupar com a faculdade, assim deixando o tempo da noite e a cabeça menos preocupada:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Um pouco sobre o Vim</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/vim/</guid>
      <description>Aqui começa uma série de artigos sobre por que eu gosto de usar o VIM para programar.
Uma das primeiras coisas que eu gostaria de comentar é sobre a quebra de paradigma que você deve ter quando começa a usar um editor como o vim que tem vários modos de operação, ou seja, não é mais apenas digitar, pois cada modo de operação tem o seu modo de agir. Os modos de operação são os seguintes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameJam</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gamejam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gamejam/</guid>
      <description>Como alguns sabem no final de semana passado ( dias 7, 8 e 9 ) eu participei do GameJam do Itaú cultural.
Nesse evento os participantes tinham que formar equipes de até 4 pessoas e fazer um jogo em 48 horas, sendo que o tema ao qual o jogo devia responder só seria passado na sexta feira as 19, e teríamos até as 19 horas do domingo para entregar o jogo pronto utilizando qualquer plataforma para desenvolvimento.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalando o Allegro 4.2.2 no Linux x86</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/allegro422/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/allegro422/</guid>
      <description>Como mencionei no meu ultimo post eu parcicipei do GameJam do Itaú cultural e desenvolvi um jogo com Allegro. Agora com o jogo pronto estou criando arquivos executáveis para divulgar e tinha me esquecido da diferença de arquitetura no Linux, assim compilei apenas para meu Linux x64.
Quando me dei conta que não funcionou no computador do trabalho por que eu tinha um binário x64, eu tive que instalar o Allegro no computador de lá para poder fazer funcionar também em Linux x86.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de Agosto</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-aug2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-aug2009/</guid>
      <description>E lá vamos nós com mais um post (que felizmente estou conseguindo manter mensal) sobre os serviços legais que eu vi no mês passado e estou usando esse mês.
TypingWeb O TypingWeb é um serviço web que possui vários tutoriais para aprender a digitar corretamente. Eu estou treinando digitação já faz um tempo utilizando o TypeRacing e um programinha para Linux chamado gtypist que tambem é bem legal para treinar. Achei esse site fantástico, e o mais legal de tudo é que tem uma versão em português, então eu posso passar para outras pessoas (como a minha mãe por exemplo) que tambem querem aprender a digitar melhor mas não se dão bem com o inglês.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance Websites</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/highperfwebsites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/highperfwebsites/</guid>
      <description>Mais um dos livros que eu consegui terminar de ler nas férias! O livro fala sobre performance de front end, como fazer as suas páginas carregarem mais rapidamente e fornecer uma melhor experiência para o usuário.
O livro começa explicando um pouco sobre o HTTP, seus métodos e utilizações, e depois inicia as sobre as 14 regras para ter um website mais performático. Eu vou tentar mostrar um pouco de cada uma das regras que o livro aborda, mas é claro que sem os grandes detalhes, comparações e exemplos que o livro dá, que são muito amplos e interessantes para se entender, mas vou dar uma visão geral de qual é o conteúdo da regra, para te chamar para comprar o livro e ler (ou não&amp;hellip;hehhe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalando gems do GitHub manualmente</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gems-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gems-github/</guid>
      <description>Esse vai ser um post rápido para relatar um problema que eu tive ( e ainda estou tendo ) para instalar gems do GitHub.
Por algum motivo bizarro (nem tanto assim, parece ser dns, mas já tentei opendns e nada) a página http://gems.github.com não abre de maneira nenhuma, enquanto a navegação continua normal sem nenhum problema&amp;hellip; A consequência disso é que eu não consigo colocar o source do github nas minhas configurações do Rubygems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lotr/</guid>
      <description>Chegou o momento que eu estava esperando há vários meses&amp;hellip;. Após terminar de ler, vou escrever sobre O Senhor dos Anéis! :D
Todos que me conhecem sabem como eu sou apaixonado pelo mundo de O senhor dos anéis na verdade sobre histórias medievais e o Senhor dos anéis é foda), e eu só tinha assistido o filme (mais de 10 vezes o primeiro, e milhões de vezes os outros 2) e não tinha lido o livro ainda, o que me deixava inquieto, pois eu sabia muito bem que o nível de riquezas e detalhes do livro ia muito alem do que eu podia imaginar, sem contar que muita coisa foi cortada no filme (obviamente) para que se fosse feita uma boa adaptação.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameReview: SpiderMan - Friend or Foe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/spiderman-friendorfoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/spiderman-friendorfoe/</guid>
      <description>Aqui estou eu com mais um GameReview de um jogo que eu tenho jogado ultimamente no PSP e finalmente no sábado as 02:15 eu consegui terminar, o Spiderman - Friend or foe!
Como quem já me conhece sabe, eu sou um fã de homem aranha! Não aquele fã que tem todos os quadrinhos ou que fica comprando um monte de coisas, mas eu sempre gostei das histórias do aranha e sempre que possível comprava ou pegava emprestado algumas séries de quadrinhos para ler, ou jogos para jogar, ou desenhos/filmes para assistir, enfim&amp;hellip; Homem Aranha FTW!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encontro de numero 5 do Guru-sp</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gurusp-meetup5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gurusp-meetup5/</guid>
      <description>Nesse sábado aconteceu o quinto encontro do Guru-sp! :)
O encontro estava marcado para as 10 da manhã com uma seção para iniciantes e começou as 10:30 ( sempre atrasa um pouquinho né? hehe ), já com um bate papo legal coordenado pelo @rafaelrosafu após uma breve apresentação de todos os participantes.
Rails para iniciantes Nessa primeira seção tiveram muitas conversas interessantes sobre algumas filosofias Rails, como:
 DRY REST TDD Test all the Fucking Time Skynny Controllers and Fat Models  e mais algumas outras coisas bem interessantes que fomentaram uma ótima discussão sobre quais os melhores padrões para se seguir quando se constrói uma aplicação Rails (sim, falamos tomando como base uma aplicação Rails), como utilizar plugins como o ResourceController (que tem seus prós e contras), manter seus scripts num lugar diferente da pasta scripts, que é a pasta padrão para scripts &amp;ldquo;internos&amp;rdquo; do Rails e tentar centralizar em uma pasta dentro de lib, além de usar Rake sempre que possível para essas tarefas ficarem organizadas e de fácil acesso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameReview: Diablo</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/diablo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/diablo/</guid>
      <description>Pois é&amp;hellip; Sei que muitos de vocês devem estar pensando se esse era um review de algum demo do Diablo III que sabe se lá como eu teria conseguido por que ainda nem lançou, mas não, esse é um review do Diablo I! Estranho como um jogo lançado a tantos anos atrás tenha ganhado um review meu agora, não? :P
Quando o Diablo I foi lançado eu mal sabia o que era ter um computador, e a única coisa que eu podia fazer era ver um colega meu com o jogo original jogando enquanto eu ficava babando&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic version control using Git</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pragmaticgit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pragmaticgit/</guid>
      <description>Há tempos que eu estava querendo conhecer um pouco mais do Git e nos últimos dias estava procurando um livro legal, quando me deparei com esse livro. Fiz algumas perguntas para um pessoal no Twitter como pessoalmente sobre esse livro, alguns me recomendavam, outros me passavam outros também interessantes, e estava em dúvida entre comprar ou não, até que consegui emprestado e li em 3 dias.
O livro é bem interessante, aborda desde o mais básico até o nível intermediário, não abordando conteúdos tão avançados.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Como desabilitar o beep no Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ubuntu-beep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ubuntu-beep/</guid>
      <description>Resolvi postar sobre isso por que é uma coisa tão simples mas irrita muito quando você não sabe como desabilitar, e sempre que eu procurava eu caia em fóruns com vários comandos bizarros e colocar algo referente ao com no blacklist e não sei o que mais lá que era chato de se fazer, quando é tão fácil.
O que sempre acontecia é que eu estava aqui ouvindo boa musica (e alta, por sinal) e programando, o que me levava ao terminal em vários momentos, e quando eu menos espero aquele meu backspace adicional gera um beep monstruoso que dá um grande susto, e isso me irritava profundamente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços legais de Julho</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-jul2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-jul2009/</guid>
      <description>Esse mês eu estou conseguindo novamente fazer um post sobre os serviços legais que eu encontrei esse mês ( e alguns que eu já uso faz tempo )
Wakoopa O Wakoopa é um software que você instala em seu computador e ele lhe dá estatísticas do que você mais usa, entre aplicações desktop e webapps! Mas isso não é o melhor disso tudo! O melhor é que ele se integra com uma conta que você tem no site do Wakoopa e se torna uma rede social onde você pode ver o que seus amigos estão usando, fazer reviews de softwares que você gosta, encontrar softwares novos e outras coisas bem legais!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opera Unite</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/opera-unite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/opera-unite/</guid>
      <description>Hoje é o dia em que o pessoal da Opera falou que iria reinventar a web, e o que eles fizeram foi lancar o Opera Unite!
A idéia do Opera Unite é tornar a internet mais interligada, fazendo com que você consiga compartilhar arquivos, conversar com amigos e outras coisas apenas usando o browser.
Eu nunca utilizei Opera ( não por que eu sou contra, e sim por que eu nunca precisei e sempre estive confortável com o Firefox, principalmente para desenvolver ), mas achei interessante a campanha de marketing e a idéia deles com esse novo produto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalando modem 3G Claro USB E226 no Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/modemclaro-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/modemclaro-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Após receber um modem Claro da empresa que eu trabalho atualmente eu fui fazer o processo de instalação no Ubuntu. Já tinha recebido a informação de um colega de trabalho de como fazer, e obviamente não foi nada difícil (o que que é difícil no Ubuntu? :)).
Vou descrever aqui o processo:
 Inserir o modem na entrada USB Vai aparecer um assistente de configuração simples ( Next Next Finish ), para você seguir e instalar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serviços interessantes</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/servicos-jul2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/servicos-jul2019/</guid>
      <description>Depois de conhecer alguns serviços legais na internet resolvi postar sobre eles aqui. Gostaria de fazer um post desse tipo mensalmente ( assim como o Ronaldo Ferraz faz no seu blog sobre o balanço cultural, que eu acho bem legal ), mas pelo menos dessa vez quero postar algumas coisas legais, e se possível eu posto periódicamente o que eu tenho feito / encontrado de divertido. ;)
Dropbox Já começando com o DropBox, que é uma aplicação para sincronização de arquivos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizando seu Gmail para manter Inbox zero</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gmail-inboxzero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gmail-inboxzero/</guid>
      <description>Agora chegando em tempo de provas e grande acumulo de atividades no trabalho eu fico começando a procurar as brechas de tempo que eu gasto &amp;ldquo;inútilmente&amp;rdquo; para ver se eu consigo aplicar em alguma coisa que possa me ajudar a cumprir todas as tarefas. Fiz uma pequena análise do tempo que eu perdia em determinados lugares, e vi que tanto e-mail como Twitter me consumiam uma grande quantidade de tempo ( com o Twitter é fácil, só desativar temporariamente e seguir menos gente ), portanto decidi fazer um refactoring!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usando Git em projetos do Google Code</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/git-googlecode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/git-googlecode/</guid>
      <description>Resolvi escrever esse post depois de começar a contribuir para o projeto do vimbook, que está no Google Code.
Como o Google Code só usa Subversion (infelizmente) e eu sou do mundo Git, resolvi usar a ferramenta Git para lidar com SVN, o git-svn! Com ele você pode clonar um repositório SVN e utilizar como Git, e na hora de &amp;ldquo;commitar&amp;rdquo; ele retransforma em SVN.
Já havia tentado usar Git-svn no meu projeto de plugin para wordpress, mas nesse caso eu já tinha um repositório Git e fui tentar mandar para um repositório SVN vazio, o que só me deu dor de cabeça, e no fim das contas acabei jogando para um repositório SVN qualquer só para mandar para o Wordpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configurando seu Gtalk do Google Apps no Pidgin</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gtalk-pidgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gtalk-pidgin/</guid>
      <description>Resolvi postar sobre isso depois de passar por 3 empresas que usam o Google Apps for your Domain e eu sempre esbarrar com o maldito probleminha ao se configurar o Pidgin.
Pensei que isso era burrice minha de não ver a configuração correta, mas depois percebi que não era só eu que não via essas configurações para poder fazer o negócio funcionar! Como eu nunca anotava o processo, sempre tinha que ficar pesquisando para ver se achava algo relacionado a isso, e nunca funcionava.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 9.04</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ubuntu904/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ubuntu904/</guid>
      <description>Hoje estou aqui para falar um pouco sobre o Ubuntu 9.04! :)
Alguns dias atrás eu postei no twitter que não estava satisfeito com o Ubuntu 9.04, e abaixo descrevo alguns dos motivos.
Primeiramente comecei tentando instalar ele pelo cd (para não ter que deixar o computador ligado mil horas baixando, e tambem por que tenho mais de 1 Ubuntu em casa, portanto mais de mil horas x 2) e não consegui&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encontro de Design e Tecnologia Digital</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/encontro-designtec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/encontro-designtec/</guid>
      <description>Participei nesse sábado do EDTED (Encontro de Design e Tecnologia Digital), e vou postar as minhas impressões sobre o evento, focando as palestras que assisti:
CMS’s livres: não reinventado a roda no desenvolvimento web A palestra foi conduzida por Paulino Michelazzo da Fábrica Livre, e foi uma palestra interessante!
O palestrante soube levar bem a palestra, com momentos engraçados ( várias brincadeiras com Java e Windows, que obviamente não devem ser levadas a sério ), e apresentando como é fácil criar uma loja virtual utilizando o Joomla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Começando a falar de Ruby</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ruby-inicio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ruby-inicio/</guid>
      <description>Se você já conhece Ruby, ignore esse post! A idéia do post é mostrar um pouco da linguagem Ruby para pessoas que não conhecem nada sobre ela.
Eu, claro, acho muito interessante que muita gente por aí ainda não conhece Ruby, mesmo com a grande popularização do Rails, e eu chego a ouvir coisas assim:
 &amp;ldquo;Não é você que programa naquela linguagem esquisita?&amp;rdquo;
 Cheguei a ouvir do meu &amp;ldquo;professor de algoritmo&amp;rdquo; (perdeu meu respeito):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin para WordPress: Anti IE6 Army</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/antiie6army/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/antiie6army/</guid>
      <description>Estou postando para anunciar que foi lançada a versão 1.0 do meu plugin para Wordpress chamado anti-IE6-army! :D
A idéia do plugin é juntar um exército de campanhas contra o Internet Explorer 6 que estão perdidas pela internet em um único plugin, para que todos que possuem blogs com Wordpress possam usar facilmente, sem precisal alterar HTML, ou abrir qualquer arquivo de código!
Aqui no blog tem uma página só para falar do Plugin, e lá você pode obter mais informações.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translated Rubylearning presentation</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rubylearning-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rubylearning-presentation/</guid>
      <description>As I promised, here goes my presentation! :)
Finally i finished to translate all the presentation! Watched the video a lot of times, pausing and playing to write all I said translating to english. :)
Fortunately I had a big help from my friend Victor Goff, that corrected all my grammar errors and typos.
I&amp;rsquo;m posting below all i have about the presentation, slides from Slideshare and a translation pasted here, but you can find the translation at Google Docs too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails X Django</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rails-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rails-django/</guid>
      <description>Como todos sabem eu sou do mundo Ruby/Rails (Não sou xiita mas é o que mais gosto) e de vez em quando começo a brincar com coisas diferentes para poder formar a minha própria opinião sobre o assunto. No mes de fevereiro me surgiu um projeto bem interessante para trabalhar, pessoas legais, oportunidade legal, bem interessante! O projeto seria feito em Python/Django, e achei bem interessante a idéia de poder comparar várias coisas do Rails com o Django.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby e Rails no mundo real</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rrails-mundoreal-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rrails-mundoreal-overview/</guid>
      <description>Como muitos leitores do Blog sabem, eu palestrei no Evento &amp;ldquo;Ruby e Rails no mundo real&amp;rdquo;, e vou fazer um pequeno overview desse evento que eu havia divulgado aqui no blog:
O evento foi bem interessante, bem alem do que nós havíamos planejado nas primeiras conversas do primeiro encontro do GURU-SP, e atendeu bastante as nossas expectativas por ser o primeiro. Obviamente cometemos alguns erros que vamos melhorar no próximo, como garantir que tenha Wi-Fi por exemplo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projeto de fevereiro</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/feb2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/feb2010/</guid>
      <description>No mês de fevereiro eu estive envolvido com um projeto bem interessante na empresa que estou trabalhando (ainda vamos trabalhar mais em nosso site 😛), que foi feito em Python / Django e deveria gerar páginas estáticas ( exigência do projeto ).
Tivemos um prazo muito curto para tudo que deveria ser feito, o que gerou uma grande quantidade de trabalho fora do horário e dos dias comuns. Entre o começo e o fim do projeto, tínhamos o carnaval, portanto tivemos que deixar nossos espíritos carnavalescos guardados e partir para o trabalho árduo no feriado até horas indeterminadas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Inside Brasil</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rubyinsidebr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rubyinsidebr/</guid>
      <description>Há um tempo já que eu deveria ter postado sobre o Ruby Inside Brasil, mas estou esvaziando aos poucos o meu Todo List e estou aproveitando a promoção que eles fizeram para liberar esse post tambem. :)
O Ruby Inside Brasil é a edição autorizada do Ruby Inside mantido pelo Peter Cooper. Uma ótima iniciativa para postar bom conteúdo em português.
A idéia inicial do projeto foi do Carlos Brando, que junto com vários outros colaboradores está contruindo o nome do Ruby Inside Brasil, e tem como idéia não apenas postar traduções dos conteúdos do Ruby Inside em inglês, mas tambem postar conteúdo próprio escritos por desenvolvedores brasileiros, cobrindo tudo que acontece relacionado a Rails e Ruby aqui Brasil!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colocando sua aplicação Rails na Dreamhost</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rails-dreamhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rails-dreamhost/</guid>
      <description>Estou fazendo um pequeno site em Rails e como tinha que mostrar o andamento para um colega, aproveitei para testar como seria o Deploy desse projeto na DreamHost ( mesmo sabendo que o provedor final não será lá ), e achei muito fácil de se fazer, portanto resolvi escrever um pouco sobre o processo. :D
Primeiramente, você precisa ter acesso SSH na sua conta. Se você ainda não tiver esse acesso apenas faça o seguinte procedimento:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Show do Iron Maiden</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ironmaiden2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ironmaiden2009/</guid>
      <description>Fui ao show do Iron maiden nesse domingo dia 15/03 e resolvi postar as minhas considerações.
O show do Iron Maiden em si foi muito legal! Tocaram muitos clássicos como:
 Fear of the dark ( der&amp;hellip; ) Wasted Years Aces High The rime of ancient mariner Phanton of the Opera Hallowed be the name 666 the number of the beast The trooper  entre outras!
A abertura com o discurso de Winston Churchill e já entrando com Aces High foi muito legal!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curso de verão da USP</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/usp-verao/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/usp-verao/</guid>
      <description>Com o fim do curso de verão de 2009 da USP, resolvi postar minhas impressões sobre o mesmo!
O curso realmente foi muito bom e me ensinou muita coisa! Eu já tinha feito o curso no ano retrasado, mas não cheguei a terminar, por que o professor da época era muito foda e assumia que todos os alunos já sabiam do que ele estava falando, e para mim não significava tanto assim, portanto chegou um momento que eu simplesmente já não estava entendendo mais nada, e o professor já estava jogando matéria loucamente, portanto abandonei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DC&#43;&#43; no Linux</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dcpp-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dcpp-linux/</guid>
      <description>Hoje finalmente estou conseguindo escrever um post sobre o DC++! Desde a Campus Party eu quero escrever esse post mas nunca consigo tempo!
Para quem não conhece, o DC++ é um software para compartilhamento de arquivos, muito interessante, onde você pode facilmente compartilhar arquivos pela rede local, e por isso mesmo que foi muito utilizado na Campus Party, onde os campuseiros compartilharam terabytes e mais terabytes de arquivos!
Atualmente estou utilizando Ubuntu no meu notebook (não tenho mais PC nem em casa e nem no trampo, portanto o meu Slackware se foi&amp;hellip;:() e vou mostrar aqui como instalar o seu DC++ nele!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dia difícil</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dia-dificil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dia-dificil/</guid>
      <description>Hoje o dia foi $#&amp;amp;&amp;amp;!

Atualmente moro em Diadema (que não é uma cidade ruim como muitos ouvem falar), e tenho o azer de morar próximo a um córrego, que a prefeitura promete canalizar há mais de 10 anos, e agora parece que finalmente o projeto começou a andar, mas enquanto o projeto não é concluído de vez a coisa ficou pior que o normal&amp;hellip;
No momento ruim eu tirei algumas fotos (o que sempre faço nesses casos) para mostrar a situação da coisa&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby e Rails no mundo real</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rrails-mundoreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rrails-mundoreal/</guid>
      <description>Pessoal, hoje o meu post é para comentar sobre o evento do Guru-sp (Grupo de usuário Ruby de São Paulo), cujo fui um dos fundadores e participo até hoje (quem vê pensa que faz bastante tempo&amp;hellip; Apenas uns 4 meses haha).
O evento já tem site oficial e está com as inscrições abertas!
Pelo que estamos fazendo o evento tende a ser grande, com auditório para cerca de 200 pessoas, com direito a crachá, apostila, Coffee break e etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIVO online agora funciona no Firefox / Safari</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/vivo-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/vivo-firefox/</guid>
      <description>Boas novas!
Eu tinha feito um post sobre os usuários dos serviços da VIVO que tiveram que desenvolver uma extensão para conseguir acessar os serviços do Vivo on line, e agora a vivo anunciou oficialmente em seu blog que o Vivo on line funcionará bem em outros navegadores diferentes de Internet Explorer! :)
Tudo bem que isso é um direito nosso e já deveria funcionar em todos desde o começo do serviço, pois prejudicava os usuários de outros sistemas operacionais diferentes do Windows, mas temos que parabenizar a VIVO por trabalhar em cima do problema que tinham e resolver assim como prometeram em novembro do ano passado!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campus Party 2009</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/campusparty2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/campusparty2009/</guid>
      <description>Como sabem eu estive na Campus Party nessa ultima semana, e consegui aproveitar bastante do evento, apesar do monte de coisas que estão acontecendo na minha vida e a correria toda de trabalho, curso e outras coisas.
Segue um pequeno resumo do que pude ver por lá:
Segunda-feira dia 19/01/2009 Cheguei no evento mais ou menos as 15:00 e consegui entrar rapidinho&amp;hellip; Já armei a minha barraca (vide fotos) e deixei algumas coisas por lá para não ficar carregando, e fui conectar na internet que ainda estava bem precária que só funcionava em algumas mesas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usuários resolvem os problemas da VIVO</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/problemas-vivo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/problemas-vivo/</guid>
      <description>Primeiramente quero parabenizar o Diogo Santos pelo seu add-on para Firefox, que faz com que o botão &amp;ldquo;entrar&amp;rdquo; do site da Vivo funcione sem que você tenha que usar javascript para manipular pela barra de endereços. Parabéns Diogo, é uma ótima contribuição para a comunidade.
Agora vem a hora da crítica&amp;hellip; Como que os usuários tem que ficar desenvolvendo formas alternativas para acessar os serviços que deveriam funcionar para eles, mas por descaso e serviço mal feito não lhe são concedidos?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fora IE6</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/foraie6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/foraie6/</guid>
      <description>Já está mais do que na hora de eu fazer um post sobre isso, e acho que não há momento mais propício do que esse afinal, até o Google já está dando alertassobre isso no Gmail. Sabemos que o Gmail é não é o serviço mais acessado do Google, mas isso já é uma grande ajuda para alertar os desavisados que esse navegador já passou da hora de deixar de existir, e quem sabe num futuro talvez distante ( espero que não tão distante assim ) o google resolva fazer algo parecido com o Orkut!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a simple Merb application on Locaweb</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/merb-locaweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/merb-locaweb/</guid>
      <description>I writing this post to help my friends of Rubylearning with a little Merb application deployment on Locaweb. I&amp;rsquo;m just translating some informations that you can find here in portuguese.
Lets get started! :D
First open the
Domain Manager (gerenciador de domínios) on Locaweb Panel (painel da Locaweb) and configure the pointer of your main site to other directory on public_html of your account (this directory don&amp;rsquo;t need to exist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year is coming</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/newyear2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/newyear2008/</guid>
      <description>Estou apenas postando para dizer que nesse novo ano eu pretendo postar mais sobre programação! Essa é a primeira virada de ano desse blog, então resolvi postar meus &amp;ldquo;planos&amp;rdquo; para o próximo ano.
Como o blog é novo eu comecei a escrever faz pouco tempo e estou pegando experiência aos poucos, e talvez agora nesse novo ano a qualidade dos posts aumente! (ou não&amp;hellip;heheh).
Não sei bem qual rumo minha vida vai seguir nesse novo ano, o que eu vou ter que aprender e estudar, talvez eu tenha que aprender coisas que eu não tinha planejado e isso pode tomar uma boa parte do meu tempo, mas eu pretendo postar todos os meus estudos aqui, portanto terei algum material interessante aqui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurso Quarto mais Nerd</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/quarto-nerd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/quarto-nerd/</guid>
      <description>Bem&amp;hellip;Estava eu aproveitando as férias (tanto da faculdade como as férias coletivas do trabalho) para colocar as coisas em ordem, começando pelo meu quarto que é o lugar da casa que eu passo mais tempo e eu gosto de manter bem organizado, portanto já tratei de aproveitar meu tempo livre para deixar ele do jeito que eu queria.
Comprei uma pequena estante para colocar mais livros e outras coisas legais, encaixotei várias coisas que eu quase nunca vou usar, e joguei 2 sacolas de papéis e outras coisas inúteis fora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configurando seu git para começar a usar</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/git-configurado/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/git-configurado/</guid>
      <description>Meu ultimo post foi sobre como subir um projeto para o GitHub, mas me veio agora uma vontade repentina de falar como deixar seu git legalzinho para começar a criar repositórios e contribuir com códigos! Serão apenas configurações básicas, mas que são bem úteis quando você estiver usando o Git ativamente!
Antes de mais nada precisamos instalar o Git, portanto é só baixar ele no repositório oficial e fazer a instalação referente ao seu sistema operacional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iniciando seu primeiro projeto no GitHub</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/primeiro-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/primeiro-github/</guid>
      <description>Hoje estou aqui para postar um pouco sobre o GitHub! =)
Minha idéia hoje é apenas mostrar como você inicia um projeto por lá, ou seja, enviar um pequeno repositório git e deixar no GitHub, e conforme os meus progressos eu postarei mais coisas por aqui! ; )
Antes de começar tudo isso você precisar ter cadastro no GitHub (obviamente) e já ter uma public-key cadastrada.
Para cadastrar uma public-key é só logar no GitHub, clicar em account (no canto superior direito) e clicar em &amp;ldquo;add public key&amp;rdquo; que vão aparecer os campos para inserir a mesma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post in English here</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hi international friends! :)
I&amp;rsquo;m just posting to inform that I want to post some content in English too! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make a RSS Feed only for my English posts, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to view my portuguese posts on your feed reader. :)
As everyone knows, my English is not so good, but I think you can understand me well! Any English errors (I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will have a lot of them) please tell me and I&amp;rsquo;ll correct it asap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GameReview: Need For Speed - Most Wanted</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/nfs-mostwanted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/nfs-mostwanted/</guid>
      <description>Como eu disse no ultimo post agora eu vou fazer uns pomsts sobre uns jogos que eu estou voltando a jogar no PSP, dizendo o que eu achei, como foi jogar ele, defeitos, qualidades, gosto pessoal e tudo mais!
Primeiramente vou falar sobre o gosto pessoal. Eu nunca fui muito fã de jogos de corrida, foram poucos que realmente me fizeram jogar até o final, e esse realmente foi um deles!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voltando a ser um gamer</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gamer/</guid>
      <description>Esse aqui vai ser um post um pouco fora do escopo &amp;ldquo;programação&amp;rdquo;, mas ainda no escopo &amp;ldquo;nerd&amp;rdquo;! :)
Com esse post eu pretendo introduzir uma nova série (não achei palavra melhor) posts sobre os games que eu estou jogando atualmente, postanto umas opiniões e tudo mais, e quem sabe até alguns jogos que eu pretendo instalar no Linux.
Vou contar um pouco do título &amp;ldquo;Voltando a ser um gamer&amp;rdquo;.
Eu sempre gostei de jogar vídeo games desde pequeno, a ponto da minha mãe dizer que eu só podia jogar 3 horas por dia&amp;hellip; hahaha&amp;hellip; Tive poucos vídeo games pois meus pais não tinham tanto dinheiro assim para ficar comprando novos, portanto se eu quisesse algo novo eu tinha que me virar e comprar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ir além do básico tambem é gratis</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/basico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/basico/</guid>
      <description>Faz um tempinho que eu estou querendo fazer um post seguindo os moldes da campanha do Marco Gomes, que também gerou o post do Diego Eis, e finalmente consegui um tempinho para expressar também a minha opinião nesse assunto! :)
Conheço muitas pessoas que fazem faculdade relacionada a programação, mas não aplicam o que estão vendo por lá, acham que já estão fazendo demais em ir para a faculdade e ficar lá no tempo em que o professor está falando&amp;hellip;Ou seja, essas pessoas não estão indo a faculdade para aprender algo para colocar em prática, eles estão lá simplesmente para &amp;ldquo;passar de ano&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A facilidade do Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Deixa eu explicar aqui para quem estou destinando esse post. Esse post é destinado a algumas pessoas que costumam me perguntar se o Linux é difícil, se ele vai conseguir mexer nele se instalar, se Linux é melhor que Windows e outras perguntas derivadas disso, portanto se você já tem conhecimentos em Linux e já usa Linux esse post só vai servir para você passar para seus amigos que não usam, pois é bem básico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Como são os primeiros passos de um Linuxer</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/inicio-linuxer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/inicio-linuxer/</guid>
      <description>Nesse post eu vou contar um pouco de como são os primeiros passos de alguem que quer mesmo brincar com Linux. No caso vou falar como eu comecei com o Linux! Vamos lá! :)
Eu sempre ouvia falar de Linux quando eu lia Livros sobre segurança e tudo mais, portanto sempre tinha vontade de utilizar&amp;hellip; Meu primeiro contato direto com Linux foi em 2004, mas nessa época eu ainda era bem fanático por jogos de computador, o que me fez continuar no Windows por um tempo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montando imagens do Nero (nrg) no Linux</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/nero-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/nero-linux/</guid>
      <description>Vou comentar agora sobre como montar aquela imagem chata do Nero (.nrg ) que seu amigo que gosta de janelas lhe enviou com aqueles vários arquivos que você tinha pedido&amp;hellip; É um hack bem fácil!
Instalações Primeiro instale o nrg2iso
No Ubuntu # apt-get install nrg2iso  No Slackware Baixando o pacote no Linux Packages e instalando normalmente com:
# installpkg nrg2iso-versao.tgz  Utilização Agora já podemos utilizar o nrg3iso para converter nossa imagem:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizando o sshfs</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sshfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sshfs/</guid>
      <description>Estou utilizando bastante o sshfs para transferir alguns arquivos para o servidor, ao invés de utilizar o bom e velho scp, por questão de ficar mais prático e facil a cópia de vários arquivos para diretórios distintos.
O que facilita bastante é utilizar a sua chave privada ( explicado por mim nesse tópico) para montar os seus diretórios sshfs, assim você terá o diretório do servidor montado facilmente em seu computador e poderá enviar arquivos para esse diretório e seus sub-diretórios como se estivesse copiando arquivos para outro diretório qualquer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deixando seu ssh mais facil de trabalhar</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ssh-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ssh-easy/</guid>
      <description>Se você usa bastante SSH vou mostrar um método para facilitar um pouco a sua vida. Sei que existem métodos melhores para trabalhar com vários SSH ao mesmo tempo, geralmente a galera que administra vários servidores costuma usar screen para se manter conectado, mas eu como conecto de vez em quando para ver algo em algum dos servidores prefiro configurar desse modo.
A primeira coisa a se fazer é configurar o seu .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ativando numlock na Inicialização do Fluxbox no Slackware</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fluxbox-slackware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fluxbox-slackware/</guid>
      <description>Estava eu pesquisando na internet como conseguir fazer o meu numlock já iniciar ativado quando meu fluxbox inicia e encontrei várias dicas, sendo umas para XFCE e outros sistemas não sendo Slackware, portanto decidi escrever como fiz no Slackware.
Primeiramente precisamos do numlockx que é o programinha vai ativar o num facilmente.
Podemos instalar ele via SlackBuilds que eu uso muito!
Após baixar o numlockx.tar.gz e o numlockx-.version.tar.gz` vamos seguir os procedimentos do SlackBuilds:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ouvindo suas musicas no Amarok</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/amarok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/amarok/</guid>
      <description>Como sabem, instalei o Ubuntu no meu notebook Toshiba U405-S2854, e estou brincando um pouco com programas bunitinhos e mais pesados do que os que eu costumava usar no Slackware.
Resolvi começar o Amarok para tocar os meus mp3, e ele lembra bastante o Itunes (ta certo que usei pouco o Itunes, mas conheço algumas funções dele).
Tive um pequeno probleminha para configurar minhas teclas multimedia para funcionar no amarok, já que elas vem configuradas para chamar o player padrão do Ubuntu&amp;hellip; Mas nada muito problemático tambem&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitando a instalação de pacotes no Slackware</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/slackware-pacotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/slackware-pacotes/</guid>
      <description>Estava escrevendo outro post e chegando em um ponto onde eu instalaria um pequeno Software utilizando o SlackBuilds me fez escrever esse post sobre algumas facilitações de instalação para Slackware.
Nesse post eu vou referenciar 4 facilitadores para instalação de pacotes no Slackware: SlackBuilds, LinuxPackages, Slackpkg, Slapt-get e Checkinstall.
SlackBuilds Primeiramente vou comentar sobre um dos que eu mais uso e que mudou a minha vida ( heheh ), que é o SlackBuilds!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aprenda Ruby no Rubylearning</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rubylearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rubylearning/</guid>
      <description>Como muitos sabem, eu sou um dos professores assistentes do Rubylearning.org que oferece gratuitamente cursos de ruby!
O Satish Talim anunciou que estão abertas as inscrições para o FORPC101-9C ( Free Online Ruby Programming Course 101 - Batch 9 Core) que é a série de cursos gratuitos sobre Ruby Core.
Aconselho todos que querem aprender Ruby a participarem! Não se preocupe muito com seu inglês, ele não precisa estar extremamente afiado para você participar, basta que você consiga entender bem para que você participe, e caso não consiga escrever bem o pessoal pode ajudar você a se expressar para conseguir ajuda nos Foruns!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Summit Latin America (Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/railssummit-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/railssummit-day2/</guid>
      <description>Para quem não viu o meu post sobre o primeiro dia da Rails Summit, veja aqui! ;) E agora vamos ao segundo post sobre a Rails Summit! :)
Começamos o segundo dia de Rails Summit as 8:00, e logo no começo do dia tivemos alguns probleminhas técnicos com energia elétrica que logo foi contornado com um gerador ( esse evento escala! ). Tivemos a abertura do dia com o Fabio akita comentando sobre as palestras e dando recados gerais.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Summit Latin America</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/railssummit-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/railssummit-day1/</guid>
      <description>Como muitos sabem eu participei da Rails Summit Latin America e vou agora fazer uns comentários sobre o evento.
Vou dividir em 2 posts, um para cada dia, por que o assunto ficou bem extenso.
Minha intenção com a Rails Summit, alem de ver as ótimas palestras era de fazer um social network com a galera que eu só conhecia por nickname, e isso realmente foi difícil de fazer justamente por isso, reconhecer as pessoas pessoalmente sendo que só as conheço por nickname e avatar não é nada fácil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mais de uma distro no Notebook!</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mais-distros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mais-distros/</guid>
      <description>Pouco tempo atrás comprei um notebook Toshiba U405-S2854 e instalei o Slackware 12.0 (não tinha baixado o 12.1 ainda) com fluxbox nele e aproveitei para brincar de compilar o Kernel e conhecer outras coisas&amp;hellip;
Percebi que meus conhecimentos não estavam bons o suficiente para eu fazer tudo o que eu queria com meu Slack em um curto espaço de tempo, infelizmente, e portanto resolvi instalar outro linux mais facil para eu usar enquanto meu slackware não fica do jeito que eu quero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primeiro post por aqui!</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/primeiro-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/primeiro-post/</guid>
      <description>Bem, como primeiro post vou me apresentar e dizer qual o meu intuito com esse blog.
Lembro muito bem da época que associava blog com os &amp;ldquo;flogão&amp;rdquo; da vida e prometia para mim mesmo que eu nunca criaria um blog para mim. Com a mudança de rumo dos blogs a minha vontade de criar um para divulgar informação útil foi crescendo, mas eu me mantinha preso aquela velha promessa, até que mês passado eu consegui me livrar disso e decidi finalmente ingressar no ramo de blog, pois eu pesquiso e leio tanta coisa que provavelmente algum dos conhecimentos que tenho ou coisas que fiz serão úteis para mais alguem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Willian Molinari, also known as PotHix. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with software development since 2006, using many languages professionally throughout the years.
It would be hard to add all the topics I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about in the top menu, so I decided to keep a list here:
 Write: I&amp;rsquo;m a published author and writing is something I love. Tech: I love technology and I&amp;rsquo;m usually speaking about programming in Brazil and around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/code/</guid>
      <description>This is my page of all things code-related.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing code professioally since 2007 and have some things to show. Some of them were done on my spare time and others were part of my paid job.
Paid work These are projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked full-time while being employed by a company or working as a freelancer. They are projects I deeply cared about, in one way or another.
Locaweb: Cloud PRO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desconstruindo a web</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/articles/</guid>
      <description>Articles published outside of this blog I as invited to write articles for other blogs which I respect and/or have a good reach. I will list here some of them.
The game loop: Gamedev tuts+ 
An article that explains how the Game loop works in game development. It was written for gamedev.tutsplus.com in Nov 2012.
Client side prediction: Gamedev tuts+ 
Article that explains how client side pretiction works in game development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desconstruindo a web</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/book/</guid>
      <description>I wrote desconstruindo a web in 2016 and my goal was to help web developers to understand the whole cycle of their application, from the initial keystroke to the loaded page.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to understand all the pieces involved in a web request so we can better debug problems happening in this process. The internet is a complex system and many parts can fail, knowing the purpose of each is quite useful when something goes wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/media/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re here looking for videos of my talks, I recommend you to check my list of talks page.
I love podcasts! It&amp;rsquo;s the media I consume the most nowadays (along with audiobooks!), so I do my best to contribute to it. Most of them (maybe all) are in pt-BR, but I&amp;rsquo;m adding the language in the table so you can find the ones you can understand, if any.
   Date Lang Episode title     2021-04-30 pt-BR Todoist e trabalho remoto   2019-10-01 pt-BR Cultura de aprendizado   2019-09-24 pt-BR Comunidades de software   2019-08-10 pt-BR Papo sobre Docker   2019-05-04 pt-BR Como ler um livro rendeu uma vaga na Red Hat   2018-12-21 pt-BR DNE 186 - Fim de Ano   2018-12-04 pt-BR Mais produtividade   2018-11-06 pt-BR Desvendando os segredos do Todoist   2018-09-04 pt-BR Trabalho Remoto: Um programador no Todoist   2018-08-28 pt-BR Trabalho remoto   2018-08-15 pt-BR Trabalhar HOME OFFICE   2017-11-20 pt-BR A Doist e o trabalho remoto   2017-11-09 pt-BR Organização pessoal e produtividade   2017-07-24 pt-BR Willian Molinari - Desconstruindo a Web   2016-10-26 pt-BR DNE 77 - PotHix    I was also mentioned in some other podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/podcasts/</guid>
      <description>I listen to podcasts since 2007 when I had to download them and transfer to my AAA-battery powered MP3 player every day (👴). A lot changed since then, but I still listen to podcast now and then.
I also used Podcasts to help with my listening to learn new languages, so you will see different languages being listed here. I will write everything in English here and rely on Google Translate for the proper translation of everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/politics/</guid>
      <description>I usually don&amp;rsquo;t talk much about politics, mostly because it usually do not worth my time discussing it or because I want to keep all my public profiles tech related (I don&amp;rsquo;t care much if you think politics is everywhere BTW).
I wanted a page I can link to when someone asks about my perspective on politics, so I decided to write this.
I currently live in Brazil and I think I current president is an idiot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/talks/</guid>
      <description>No. Date Presentation Event     70 2021-04-24 Mesa redonda: Trabalho remoto para empresas de fora Guru-SP   69 2020-11-18 Exploring a Core Library for Multiple Languages using Rust Doist talks   68 2020-10-06 Trabalho remoto e assincrono Future of Work   67 2019-11-29 Mongo, Rails 3 -&amp;gt; Postgres, Rails 5 Rubyconf BR   66 2019-06-21 Mongo, Rails 3 -&amp;gt; Postgres, Rails 5 Guru-SP   65 2018-10-27 10 anos de Guru-SP Guru-SP   64 2018-09-21 Writing a simple game in Rust THE CONF   63 2018-09-15 Como foi participar da Rustconf 2018 Rust-SP   62 2018-07-21 Escrevendo um jogo simples em Rust Rust - TDC   61 2018-07-21 Introdução a Rust (ft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is happening now</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/now/</guid>
      <description>This is my now page, inspired by Derek Sievers.
I&amp;rsquo;m living in São Paulo, Brazil and working for Doist remotely and asynchronously full-time.
Intervac when there time to spare.
Here is a list of my current priorities:
 Improving Todoist and Twist APIs and integrations platform at Doist. Mostly working with Python, Golang, and a bit of Typescript. Improving my Rust skills and trying to contribute to the compiler (not much time for it nowadays, unfortunately) Co-authoring a book abour Rust in pt-BR 🦀 Taking care of my twin babies at home with all its ups and downs (more downs than ups in the beggining, but there are some magic moments sometimes).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
