<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tolkien on PotHix</title>
    <link>https://pothix.com/tags/tolkien/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tolkien on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pothix.com/tags/tolkien/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to read Tolkien, in my experience</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/readtolkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/readtolkien/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of J.R.R. Tolkien, and It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time friends ask me about how to read Tolkien books. I even discussed this on Twitter because of some misconceptions people have about some of his book. To make things clear, I decided to write this with my opinion on the topic.
Do not pick a book at random Tolkien has a long list of published books, some of them he published in life, but most of them were published postmortem, edited by his son Christopher Tolkien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien&#39;s Ordinary Virtues book</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien’s Ordinary Virtues, by Mark Eddy Smith. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I’m a big fan of Tolkien (if you follow me or my blog, you probably already know that) and decided to give a chance to this one even knowing it was totally related to religion and it’s not my thing anymore.
The book is about Christian comparisons between The Lord of the Rings and some virtues shown in the Bible. I know talking took his Catholic religion very seriously and was even raised by a Priest after his mother passed away, so it would be nice to see the book again through these lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust, LotR, and focus</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lotrfocus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lotrfocus/</guid>
      <description>💡 Quick thought post. A bigger tweet but on my own platform.
I&amp;rsquo;m co-authoring a book about Rust and was reviewing an example about enums. My plan was to use some sort of reference to J.R.R. Tolkien fantasy world (because I really like it). I was considering using something like this:
enum Race { Elf, Dwarf, Men, Hobbit, Ent } PS: I&amp;rsquo;m only considering the free-peoples of middle earth for this enum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</guid>
      <description>Book: J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography, by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a secret to anyone that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R. Tolkien. I have 3 versions of this book. A translated version (pt-BR), the original version in English, and the audiobook. It&amp;rsquo;s no news that it would be a 5 star book to me.
I just listened to the Inklings book by Humphrey Carpenter, so it was the best time to also listen to this one (yes, I went for the Audiobook).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Inklings: C.S. Lewis, J.R.R. Tolkien, Charles Williams, and Their Friends</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/inklings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/inklings/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Inklings: C.S. Lewis, J.R.R. Tolkien, Charles Williams, and Their Friends by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;m giving it 5 stars because I enjoyed it a lot and it came at the right time for me. For most people, it will probably be a 4-stars book.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien and also the concept of the Inklings. I have my own spin-off of this group with some friends but instead of discussing literature, we just take some time to have some deep conversation about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Lay of Aotrou and Itroun</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aotrouanditroun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aotrouanditroun/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Lay of Aotrou and Itroun by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s an OK book if you&amp;rsquo;re a Tolkien fan.
For those who like Tolkien and everything he researched, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting book to read. I would not recommend this book to someone who&amp;rsquo;s not into Tolkien.
There are three poems in this book and it tries to tell a story about how Tolkien wrote the final poem. None of them are that great alone but together they show one particular part of Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s style of writing/researching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar) by Michael D.C. Drout. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book if you are a fan of J.R.R. Tolkien (like me).
I read 10+ J.R.R. Tolkien books already. I really like the descriptive way of writing and the whole fantasy world he created. I also read some other books that are not related to middle earth.
With that said, it was amazing to me to find so much that was not explicit in the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artoflotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artoflotr/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien by Wayne G. Hammond. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is one of those books for Tolkien fans. I do not recommend it if you did not read other books by Tolkien.
It is nice to read if you already read The Hobbit and The Lord of the Rings. This book shows a lot of details that Tolkien used as a guideline to write the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford for Tolkien fans</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/oxford-tolkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/oxford-tolkien/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: When traveling to Europe, I decided to take 2 or 3 days to visit Oxford. I will describe how was the experience of a J.R.R. Tolkien fan there.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien. Have read most of his books, the ones released when he was still alive and other edited by Christopher Tolkien.
After attending FOSDEM I decided to travel around some countries in Europe and UK. The most expensive part, the airplane tickets (Brazil -&amp;gt; Europe), were already paid, so&amp;hellip; why not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de A história de Kullervo</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/kullervo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/kullervo/</guid>
      <description>Book: A história de Kullervo by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro para quem é fã de Tolkien.
Esse é um livro relativamente pequeno, com uma história de cerca de 50 páginas e muitas referências para um dos primeiros trabalhos do Tolkien. Eu só recomendaria esse livro para quem já leu outras obras do Tolkien como Silmarilion ou Os Filhos de Húrin.
A história de Kullervo inspirou muito do que aconteceu na história de Turin Turambar, além de outras coisas que são contadas no Silmarilion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Ferreiro de Bosque Grande</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ferreirobosquegrande/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ferreirobosquegrande/</guid>
      <description>Book: Ferreiro de Bosque Grande by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
É um livro muito legal para quem é fã de Tolkien. A história é bem pequena, menos da metade de livro. O restante do livro é um pouco de contexto sobre a história e porque ela foi escrita, juntamente com algumas ligações sobre a vida do Tolkien na época.
Esse foi o último livro escrito pelo Tolkien antes de sua morte e diz muito sobre o seus pensamentos sobre escrita, sobre o mundo das &amp;ldquo;fadas&amp;rdquo; (que não tem nada a ver com o que pensamos dele atualmente) e sobre a vida no geral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Cartas do Papai Noel por J.R.R Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/cartaspapainoel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/cartaspapainoel/</guid>
      <description>Book: Cartas do Papai Noel by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Eu realmente admiro o J.R.R Tolkien. Esse tipo de livro mostra como ele usava toda a sua imaginação e suas habilidades para fazer coisas para os filhos dele.
Para quem é fã das obras do Tolkien vai curtir bastante esse livro. Se você é pai (não é o meu caso) talvez veja uma forma legal de lidar com o seu filho pequeno e fazer brincadeiras durante os anos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Silmarillion</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/silmarillion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/silmarillion/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Silmarilion by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is J.R.R. Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s life work. The other known books a product of this. He was not able to finish this masterpiece, but Christopher Tolkien finished his father&amp;rsquo;s work in a great way.
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie, the Silmarilion is not an easy to read book. I would not recommend it to anyone who was not totally aware of the other books and still looking for more middle earth content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lotr/</guid>
      <description>Chegou o momento que eu estava esperando há vários meses&amp;hellip;. Após terminar de ler, vou escrever sobre O Senhor dos Anéis! :D
Todos que me conhecem sabem como eu sou apaixonado pelo mundo de O senhor dos anéis na verdade sobre histórias medievais e o Senhor dos anéis é foda), e eu só tinha assistido o filme (mais de 10 vezes o primeiro, e milhões de vezes os outros 2) e não tinha lido o livro ainda, o que me deixava inquieto, pois eu sabia muito bem que o nível de riquezas e detalhes do livro ia muito alem do que eu podia imaginar, sem contar que muita coisa foi cortada no filme (obviamente) para que se fosse feita uma boa adaptação.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
