<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tolkien on PotHix</title>
    <link>https://pothix.com/tags/tolkien/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tolkien on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pothix.com/tags/tolkien/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to read Tolkien, in my experience</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/readtolkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/readtolkien/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of J.R.R. Tolkien, and It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time friends ask me about how to read Tolkien books. I even discussed this on Twitter because of some misconceptions people have about some of his book. To make things clear, I decided to write this with my opinion on the topic.
Do not pick a book at random Tolkien has a long list of published books, some of them he published in life, but most of them were published postmortem, edited by his son Christopher Tolkien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien&#39;s Ordinary Virtues book</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien’s Ordinary Virtues, by Mark Eddy Smith. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I’m a big fan of Tolkien (if you follow me or my blog, you probably already know that) and decided to give a chance to this one even knowing it was totally related to religion and it’s not my thing anymore.
The book is about Christian comparisons between The Lord of the Rings and some virtues shown in the Bible. I know talking took his Catholic religion very seriously and was even raised by a Priest after his mother passed away, so it would be nice to see the book again through these lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</guid>
      <description>Book: J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography, by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a secret to anyone that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R. Tolkien. I have 3 versions of this book. A translated version (pt-BR), the original version in English, and the audiobook. It&amp;rsquo;s no news that it would be a 5 star book to me.
I just listened to the Inklings book by Humphrey Carpenter, so it was the best time to also listen to this one (yes, I went for the Audiobook).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar) by Michael D.C. Drout. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book if you are a fan of J.R.R. Tolkien (like me).
I read 10+ J.R.R. Tolkien books already. I really like the descriptive way of writing and the whole fantasy world he created. I also read some other books that are not related to middle earth.
With that said, it was amazing to me to find so much that was not explicit in the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford for Tolkien fans</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/oxford-tolkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/oxford-tolkien/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: When traveling to Europe, I decided to take 2 or 3 days to visit Oxford. I will describe how was the experience of a J.R.R. Tolkien fan there.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien. Have read most of his books, the ones released when he was still alive and other edited by Christopher Tolkien.
After attending FOSDEM I decided to travel around some countries in Europe and UK. The most expensive part, the airplane tickets (Brazil -&amp;gt; Europe), were already paid, so&amp;hellip; why not?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
