<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Places on PotHix</title>
    <link>https://pothix.com/places/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Places on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pothix.com/places/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paris</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/paris/</guid>
      <description>In January 2023, my team at Doist had a meeting in Paris, so I scheduled one week before the meeting to be a tourist in Paris. What I&amp;rsquo;m writing below is a combination of the time I had as a tourist with my wife and the places we visited before/after work.
Stay In the first week I stayed with my wife on Hotel Louvre Richelieu. It&amp;rsquo;s a 3 star hotel close to the louvre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diadema</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/diadema/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/diadema/</guid>
      <description>Morei em Diadema por quase 30 anos. Desde os 7 anos de idade até os 34.
Por muito tempo morei no suburbio, próximo a divisa com São Bernardo do Campo e São Paulo. Nessa época eu não tinha muito a recomendar sobre a cidade, era basicamente sobreviver e crescer.
Quando casei, me mudei para o centro de Diadema, próximo ao Shopping Praça da Moça. Nessa época eu comecei a conhecer melhor a cidade e aproveitar algumas coisas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indaiatuba</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/indaiatuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/indaiatuba/</guid>
      <description>Indaiatuba é a minha cidade de escolha para morar a partir de 2022.
Por muitos anos eu queria me mudar para o interior de São Paulo, mas nunca foi uma realidade. Agora com filhos e precisando de um lugar melhor, decidi por Indaiatuba e espero morar muitos anos aqui.
Moradia O mais próximo do parque ecológico possível. É uma área muito boa. Tem desde casas, condomínios e prédios por ali. Entretenimento Magic the Gathering: X1 Arena cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel (without kids)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/travelwithoutkids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/travelwithoutkids/</guid>
      <description>I have a long list of places I visited and if you look at the descriptions you will notice a pattern on how I usually travel. I decided to write this one, so I can refer to it most of the time. Here I&amp;rsquo;m going to describe how I like to travel when I&amp;rsquo;m alone or with my wife.
I currently have 2 kids and travelling with kids is a totally different kind of trip that I will describe in a different post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rome</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/rome/</guid>
      <description>In July 2022 I spent 3 days in Rome and quite enjoyed it. The only problem was the extreme heat and crowded city, but other than that, things went great.
Stay I stayed on a BnB called CityLife Rome. I booked it on booking as I was traveling with my wife and sister and was looking for a place for 3 that was affortable and had a great location.
This place is quite close to the Roma Termini, giving you access to the lines A and B and a lot of flexibility to use the Metro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Florence</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/florence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/florence/</guid>
      <description>As part of a 1-week trip through Italy 🇮🇹 in 2022, I had the chance to spend 2 days in Florence with my wife and sister.
Stay After staying on a Penzione in Venice, we decided to get a Hotel for Firenze. We got a 3-star hotel with an amazing location, right in front of the main basilica. The hotel is called Hotel Bigallo.
The place is good enough for what we wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venice</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/venice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/venice/</guid>
      <description>As part of a 1-week trip through Italy 🇮🇹 in 2022, I had the chance to spend 2 days in Venice with my wife and sister. It was right after the Doist retreat, and I was feeling quite tired in the first day of the trip, but the mood changed quite fast after the first day. 😀
Stay We decided to get a Penzione with a room for 3. The name of the place is Penzione Guerrato, and it is near the Rialto bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertisau</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/pertisau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/pertisau/</guid>
      <description>The Doist retreat 2022 happened in Pertisau, so I had the chance to visit Austria for the first time 🇦🇹!
I really enjoyed the city. We got there in summer, and I heard it&amp;rsquo;s a totally different town in the winter. It&amp;rsquo;s quite cool to see how they adapt sports for the season. As an example of things I saw: they have Ski on winter, lake swimming and paragliding on summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/munich/</guid>
      <description>In June 2021 I had the chance to spend 3 days in Munich while preparing for the Doist retreat. Unfortunately, I was not feeling well in the second day of the trip, so it was mostly 2 working days, but I enjoyed it.
It was interesting to see how Germans are totally fine on doing topless or changing in public places. Not in the street, but close to the river, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porto</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/opo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/opo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Porto for the first time in 2017 when I first joined Doist, but also had the chance to visit the city in 2019 in the company retreat.
I really like the city. Unlike Lisbon, it feels like a city that is not so big but is also not so small. To me, it feels right in the middle of a big and small city, with historical places and nice views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azores</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/azores/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/azores/</guid>
      <description>I went to Azores (actually, Açores in Portuguese) in the Doist company retreat of 2019. It was a hell of a ride to get there because there was a lot of complication to leave Uruguay (I was organizing Rust LATAM) and get there. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a story for a different context.
Anana We visited a place where they cultivate a specific local Anana. It looks like a pineapple, but it has its own category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/places/nyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:45:26 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/places/nyc/</guid>
      <description>I had to chance to go to travel to NYC more than once. The first time I came there alone and the second one I went with my wife and both trips were good.
Airport I always try to go to JFK because it&amp;rsquo;s the biggest and simplest airport to use. The airport is really big and they have a train called Airtrain, that can be used to go from one terminal to another and also connects to the Subway.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
