<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on PotHix</title>
    <link>https://pothix.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pothix.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Little Sisters of Eluria (The Dark Tower, #0.5)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower0/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Little Sisters of Eluria (The Dark Tower, #0.5) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story for those who are into the Dark Tower series. It&amp;rsquo;s a short story actually, and brings a bit more about Roland&amp;rsquo;s early adventures, happening a bit before &amp;ldquo;The Gunslinger&amp;rdquo;.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t add much to the whole story other than just showing a bit more of a random place in the Mid-World, but it&amp;rsquo;s still an enjoyable story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Wind Through the Keyhole</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower8/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Wind Through the Keyhole by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I wish I have read this book in chronological order. The book is not bad, but reading it right after finishing the series just because it was released afterwards was not a good call. On the other hand, I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if I would have enough motivation to continue reading the series if I read this book right after book 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Dark Tower (The Dark Tower, #7)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower7/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Dark Tower (The Dark Tower, #7) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Último livro da série, também lido (ouvido!) em Português, então vamos ao review em pt-BR.
Eu estava bem curioso com o fim da história e como as coisas se resolveriam com a torre, o ka-tet, Mordred, o Rei Rubro, etc. Também estava preparado para muita coisa, dado que é um livro do Stephen King.
A forma que o King construiu os personagens foi fantástica e me deixou bem apegado a eles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Lottery</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/thelottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/thelottery/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Lottery by Shirley Jackson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I decided to read The Lottery after reading The Waste Lands (The Dark Tower, #3. They mention the book because of a situation happening in Lud, and they call it &amp;ldquo;Shirley&amp;rsquo;s nightmare&amp;rdquo;. I took some notes about it and added this short story to my reading list.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny how random the situation is in Lud when the plot is revealed, but their case was much more complicated 😅.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Masque of the Red Death</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/reddeath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/reddeath/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Masque of the Red Death by Edgar Allan Poe. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I decided to read this book after reading Song of Susannah (The Dark Tower, #6). This book was mentioned because the &amp;ldquo;Red Death&amp;rdquo; was described there too, so I was curious to read the original story.
It&amp;rsquo;s all about a prince defying the disease by locking his people inside their castle walls with enough supplies and goodies. They do &amp;ldquo;masked parties inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Song of Susannah (The Dark Tower, #6)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower6/</guid>
      <description>Book: Song of Susannah (The Dark Tower, #6) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Livro lido (ouvido? 🙂) em Português, portanto review em Português também.
Gostei bastante do livro, foi curto e direto ao ponto. Parece que o Stephen King escreveu os 3 últimos livros de uma vez, um próximo do outro para terminar a história e eles encaixaram de uma vez muita coisa que estava faltando.
Nesse livro aconteceu algo que eu não vi em nenhum outro livro que eu li até hoje.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Wolves of the Calla (The Dark Tower, #5)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower5/</guid>
      <description>Book: Wolves of the Calla (The Dark Tower, #5) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️
Estou lendo essa série em português, então os reviews também serão em português. Eu gostei mais desse livro do que do anterior porque ele moveu mais a história para a frente ao invés de dar mais contexto para as coisas. Conhecer uma nova cidade e os ocultismos que vem com ela foi bem interessante. Eu também curti saber mais sobre &amp;ldquo;Os outros mundos além desse&amp;rdquo; e como as coisas se conectam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Wizard and Glass (The Dark Tower, #4)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower4/</guid>
      <description>Book: Wizard and Glass (The Dark Tower, #4) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Outro livro que li em Português, então o review vai ser em Português também.
Eu gostei do livro no geral. Parece que a sensação de &amp;ldquo;nossa, que legal&amp;rdquo; e &amp;ldquo;mano, que bizarro&amp;rdquo; está se atenuando cada vez mais. Em alguns momentos eu fico bem interessado sobre como as histórias do mundo de Roland de Gilead (não consigo chamar de Roland Deschain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Waste Lands (The Dark Tower, #3)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower3/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Waste Lands (The Dark Tower, #3) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Ouvi esse livro em Português (e provavelmente farei o mesmo para todos os próximos). Eu tenho todos os livros físicos mas preferi procurar um audiobook para facilitar a minha &amp;ldquo;leitura&amp;rdquo;.
Assim como o livro 2, esse me surpreendeu bastante (talvez porque eu gostei pouco do primeiro). Agora eu estou começando a me envolver com a história e ficar curioso com o mundo da Torre Negra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Drawing of the Three (The Dark Tower, #2)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower2/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Drawing of the Three (The Dark Tower, #2) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
What a surprise! I enjoyed listening to this book. I have the whole series of books (printed version) here and decided to listen to the first one some years ago. I was not very impressed by it and decided to put the who series aside for some time. Last month I decided to give the second book a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Life‑Changing Magic of Tidying Up</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/magicoftidyingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/magicoftidyingup/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Life‑Changing Magic of Tidying Up by Marie Kondo. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I like the book and there are very few things I disagree with the author. I think it&amp;rsquo;s too much to talk to objects, but I understand where this is coming from. In my opinion, just holding the object is enough, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t talk to them.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to remove all objects from your bad/purse every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien&#39;s Ordinary Virtues book</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienordinaryvirtues/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien’s Ordinary Virtues, by Mark Eddy Smith. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I’m a big fan of Tolkien (if you follow me or my blog, you probably already know that) and decided to give a chance to this one even knowing it was totally related to religion and it’s not my thing anymore.
The book is about Christian comparisons between The Lord of the Rings and some virtues shown in the Bible. I know talking took his Catholic religion very seriously and was even raised by a Priest after his mother passed away, so it would be nice to see the book again through these lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Daily Rituals: How Artists Work</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dailyrituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dailyrituals/</guid>
      <description>Book: Daily Rituals: How Artists Work. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I just read the book When and it mentioned this book. The idea was so interesting that I decided to give it a try.
What first caught my attention was the pattern of the peak, through, rebound everywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s not everywhere because we&amp;rsquo;re just mentioning artists here. I believe a similar pattern tends to emerge whenever people have control over their time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/when/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/when/</guid>
      <description>Book: When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing, by Daniel Pink. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I read this book two times. The first time I had no context and was just looking for something to improve myself. The second time I read it to review everything I used and implemented so I could quote the book when writing an article about how to manage your energy to be more effective.
The book provides amazing insights if you like to base your decisions on scientific research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienbio/</guid>
      <description>Book: J.R.R. Tolkien: A Biography, by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a secret to anyone that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R. Tolkien. I have 3 versions of this book. A translated version (pt-BR), the original version in English, and the audiobook. It&amp;rsquo;s no news that it would be a 5 star book to me.
I just listened to the Inklings book by Humphrey Carpenter, so it was the best time to also listen to this one (yes, I went for the Audiobook).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Inklings: C.S. Lewis, J.R.R. Tolkien, Charles Williams, and Their Friends</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/inklings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/inklings/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Inklings: C.S. Lewis, J.R.R. Tolkien, Charles Williams, and Their Friends by Humphrey Carpenter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;m giving it 5 stars because I enjoyed it a lot and it came at the right time for me. For most people, it will probably be a 4-stars book.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien and also the concept of the Inklings. I have my own spin-off of this group with some friends but instead of discussing literature, we just take some time to have some deep conversation about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Programming Rust: Fast, Safe Systems Development</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/programmingrust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/programmingrust/</guid>
      <description>Book: Programming Rust: Fast, Safe Systems Development. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a great book for sure. I started reading it in 2017 but never find the time to read it. Now, thanks to having two babies at home, I have enough time to read while waiting for them to sleep. :)
There are many things I like about this book. The first is the comparisons with C and C++ since both authors are/were C/C++ developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Nonviolent Communication</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/nonviolentcommunication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/nonviolentcommunication/</guid>
      <description>Book: Nonviolent Communication by Marshall B. Rosenberg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book! It&amp;rsquo;s short and straight to the point.
In summary, we should emphasize more with other people and understand what they are really trying to say. Sometimes we don&amp;rsquo;t communicate well and it&amp;rsquo;s up to someone to find out what is the problem and raise the right questions.
This book feels even more important now that we have more people working remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Antidote: Happiness for People Who Can&#39;t Stand Positive Thinking</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/theantidote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/theantidote/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Antidote: Happiness for People Who Can&amp;rsquo;t Stand Positive Thinking by Oliver Burkeman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was a suggestion from a friend when I published the review of Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic: Taking Control of Anxiety Attacks, as he found the content to be complimentary.
I liked the book overall. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how the author shows some scientific facts of the &amp;ldquo;positive thinking&amp;rdquo; which contradicts the current collective thinking. I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything against positive thinking, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure positive thinking alone will not do much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Don&#39;t Panic: Taking Control of Anxiety Attacks</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dontpanicbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dontpanicbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic: Taking Control of Anxiety Attacks by R. Reid Wilson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book and exactly what I needed, thanks for the recommendation, Rafael Rosa!
Some people said it seems like a Rust programming language book because of the word &amp;ldquo;panic&amp;rdquo; but it&amp;rsquo;s actually related to panic/anxiety attacks. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time I suffer from anxiety but it&amp;rsquo;s the first time I felt the panic attack symptoms, so I decided to read more about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Essentialism: The Disciplined Pursuit of Less</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/essentialismbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/essentialismbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Essentialism: The Disciplined Pursuit of Less by Greg McKeown. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nothing outstanding, but a good book overall.
I like listening to books like this one from time to time as it helps me to again think about what is essential. This topic is something we tend to forget and having a reminder is nice.
Sometimes we have so much noise around that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find what is really essential to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Courage to Be Disliked: How to Free Yourself, Change your Life and Achieve Real Happiness</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/couragetobedisliked/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/couragetobedisliked/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Courage to Be Disliked: How to Free Yourself, Change your Life and Achieve Real Happiness by Ichiro Kishimi. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I love these kinds of dialogues where both sides know how to win something. Currently, there are not many good dialogues on our society, especially with the advent of social media (🙄), but I would not go into detail here.
The whole idea of Adlerian psychology is very interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of On the Shortness of Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/shortenessoflife/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/shortenessoflife/</guid>
      <description>Book: On the Shortness of Life by Seneca. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A short and good book. After reading Letters from a Stoic, I got the recommendation of this book as well and it was worth listening to it. This book makes me think about the way I&amp;rsquo;m living my life and how I&amp;rsquo;m using my time (not focusing enough?).
If you want a quick and meaningful book, pick this one. :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/digitalminimalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/digitalminimalism/</guid>
      <description>Book: Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World by Cal Newport. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World book and this is another great book by Cal Newport. This one is not life-changing as Deep work was for me, but it brings great insights into technology in general.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of social networks in general, they are mostly a waste of time in my point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Peak Performance: Elevate Your Game, Avoid Burnout, and Thrive with the New Science of Success</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/peakperformance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/peakperformance/</guid>
      <description>Book: Peak Performance: Elevate Your Game, Avoid Burnout, and Thrive with the New Science of Success by Brad Stulberg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book. I felt like it&amp;rsquo;s a compilation of some good books I read in the past years. It was not a life-changing book for me but it was great to review the important info I collected in the past years. I would totally recommend this book as the first book for someone looking for performance improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Born Standing Up: A Comic&#39;s Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bornstandingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bornstandingup/</guid>
      <description>Book: Born Standing Up: A Comic&amp;rsquo;s Life by Steve Martin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I got a recommendation for this book on Quora. I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember what was the question about, but I usually mark some books to read when I get these &amp;ldquo;books you should read&amp;rdquo; questions.
I had low expectations about this one and it surprised me. :)
It was great to follow Steve&amp;rsquo;s career from a broke comedian to a famous one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of How to Be Free: An Ancient Guide to the Stoic Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/howtobefree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/howtobefree/</guid>
      <description>Book: How to Be Free: An Ancient Guide to the Stoic Life by Epictetus. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book. It seems like a summary of the whole enchiridion. After reading Seneca, I decided to try Epictetus. These books are usually very dense and require some time to think about, so I decided to not go with the long form of the enchiridion. I do not regret it; it was a good reading/listening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Letters from a Stoic</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lettersfromastoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lettersfromastoic/</guid>
      <description>Book: Letters from a Stoic by Seneca. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was expecting a bit more about this book but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it is just a problem with my expectations. The book is a collection of letters from Seneca to Lucilius, and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you should expect from it. Seneca was a wise man and these letters contain great pieces of advice. Many of these advices are still valid today, but some makes much more sense when you consider the whole context in which Seneca was at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of So Good They Can&#39;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sogoodtheycantignoreyou/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sogoodtheycantignoreyou/</guid>
      <description>Book: So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love by Cal Newport. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is the kind of book you read and think: &amp;ldquo;I would love to have read this when I was starting my career&amp;rdquo;, as you have seen a lot of what he describes during the past 10 years.
I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I did most of what he mentions here, and I can say it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Utopia for Realists: How We Can Build the Ideal World</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/utopiaforrealists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/utopiaforrealists/</guid>
      <description>Book: Utopia for Realists: How We Can Build the Ideal World by Rutger Bregman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book that I will recommend to many people. I was between 4 and 5 stars for this one and decided to go with 4. If there was a 4.5, I would totally go for it.
I don&amp;rsquo;t agree with all the ideas presented here but I enjoyed thinking about them and seeing some different perspectives on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Moonwalking with Einstein: The Art and Science of Remembering Everything</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/moonwalkingwitheinstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/moonwalkingwitheinstein/</guid>
      <description>Book: Moonwalking with Einstein: The Art and Science of Remembering Everything by Joshua Foer. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I like this book. Learned many things and enjoyed listening to it as a story. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s life-changing for me, but it brought good insights and some curiosity about how I can improve my memory.
I saw some people mentioning that &amp;ldquo;this is not a book to teach you how to improve your memory&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Buraco Analista</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/buracoanalista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/buracoanalista/</guid>
      <description>Book: Buraco Analista by Aguinaldo Prandini Ricieri. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
É um livro interessante se você tiver interesse em conhecer a vida do professor Ricieri. Eu fui a uma de suas palestras alguns anos atrás e achei muito interessante a forma que ele apresenta a matemática. Ainda não participei de um de seus cursos, mas pretendo.
Esse livro conta a história dele querendo ser um cientista em Cornélio Procópio. Parece ser uma boa descrição do que é ser um cientista no Brasil no geral pelo que ouço falar de outros cientistas também.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/whywesleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/whywesleep/</guid>
      <description>Book: Why We Sleep: Unlocking the Power of Sleep and Dreams by Matthew Walker. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Amazing book! It has the potential to be life-changing for me.
When I started reading it, my review was around 3 stars. This book is not easy to read and sometimes (especially in the beginning) it feels boring. It took me some time to engage in the topic. I think I felt the same when reading Deep Work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Make Time: How to Focus on What Matters Every Day</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/maketimebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/maketimebook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Make Time: How to Focus on What Matters Every Day by Jake Knapp. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.
They mostly talk about their personal experiences and how they helped them to get better. There are some interesting experiences, especially because they were working for Google in the past and the culture of meetings is really strong there.
I already knew many things exposed here, so it was not life-changing for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Norse Mythology</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/norsemythology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/norsemythology/</guid>
      <description>Book: Norse Mythology by Neil Gaiman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book was in my reading list for a while. After an exam that requires pupil dilatation, I decided to go for the audiobook as it would not require any notes. :)
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the influence of Norse Mythology in some things. I particularly noted that Ragnarok mentions the coldest winter, which is also mentioned in ASOIAF as something the is near to the end of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Powerful: Building a Culture of Freedom and Responsibility</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerful/</guid>
      <description>Book: Powerful: Building a Culture of Freedom and Responsibility by Patty McCord. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book but I was expecting more from it. I think it happened because I had the chance to attend a workshop with Patty and it was very good. My feeling is that the book was not bringing that much news for me.
I part I like the most about this book is how Netflix &amp;ldquo;considers their employees as adults&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Remote: Office Not Required</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/remotebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/remotebook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Remote: Office Not Required by David Heinemeier Hansson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The interesting part of reading this book is that I&amp;rsquo;m currently living most part of it in the past 2 years. :)
The book itself is a little bit outdated as it was written in 2013 and we had a very different scenario then. They mention it in the first chapter, BTW.
I found it to be a little repetitive as well, they are not very pragmatic about the content and decided to mention things over and over again so you can open the book in any particular chapter and use it as a reference (at least that&amp;rsquo;s what I felt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Joy of Less, A Minimalist Living Guide: How to Declutter, Organize, and Simplify Your Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/joyofless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/joyofless/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Joy of Less, A Minimalist Living Guide: How to Declutter, Organize, and Simplify Your Life by Francine Jay. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a book I can see myself writing. I would say that around 80% of the things said here regarding a personal organization I already practice since I was a child. The ones about decluttering I learned many years ago when my home was robbed and I decided to get rid of [almost] everything that was left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Coming Storm</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/comingstorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/comingstorm/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Coming Storm by Michael Lewis. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A nice and informative book. It&amp;rsquo;s not outstanding but I found it to have great information about how data can change the way we live, especially in this case where human lives may be in danger. The whole thing about the way the U.S. government deal with their data department is weird, but at least they have one. 🤷‍♂️
Here are my notes for this small book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Homo Deus: A History of Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/homodeus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/homodeus/</guid>
      <description>Book: Homo Deus: A History of Tomorrow by Yuval Noah Harari. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a great book that made me pause many times think. This is the kind of book I love to read. I heard some criticism about Yuval&amp;rsquo;s books and they are mostly related to his way to connect things that he is not an expert about. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s the best part of the books because it also makes me consider the connections and think about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Atomic Habits: An Easy &amp; Proven Way to Build Good Habits &amp; Break Bad Ones</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/atomichabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/atomichabits/</guid>
      <description>This is an amazing book! I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about productivity and habits for a while now and I think this book does a great work of gathering everything together and presenting it in a nice form.
I think I liked it even more because I already apply many of the tips written here and I can assure (at least to myself) that it actually works. I have to say that it was really great to hear confirmation of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of 21 Lessons for the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/21lessons21stcentury/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/21lessons21stcentury/</guid>
      <description>Book: 21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I just read Sapiens and I don&amp;rsquo;t think this book is so good as Sapiens is, that&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to go with 4 stars.
I like the way Yuval brings some topics to the discussion. This book made me think about many things I usually don&amp;rsquo;t think about. Religion is a topic I like to read/listen to from different angles, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Servant: A Simple Story about the True Essence of Leadership</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/theservant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/theservant/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Servant: A Simple Story about the True Essence of Leadership by James C. Hunter. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book was a big hit in Brazil for a while and of course, I heard about it in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit skeptical about books that became a hit, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick this one. My sister asked me to buy this book for her as a gift and I decided to buy one for me too so we could discuss it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Radical Focus: Achieving Your Most Important Goals with Objectives and Key Results</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/radicalfocus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/radicalfocus/</guid>
      <description>Book: Radical Focus: Achieving Your Most Important Goals with Objectives and Key Results by Christina Wodtke. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This one is hard to rate. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I liked it or not, and it&amp;rsquo;s probably related to the structure of the book.
It starts as a non-fiction/business book, as I expected it to be, but out of nowhere, it became &amp;ldquo;a novel&amp;rdquo; (big quotes here). This &amp;ldquo;novel&amp;rdquo; part was not too bad, I liked it in the end, but it was totally unexpected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sapiens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sapiens/</guid>
      <description>Book: Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind by Yuval Noah Harari. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
One of the best books I ever read. The amount of information here is huge. There are many things I did not know about the history and some possible explanations about where we came to the current state.
I really like the way the author says &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t know this yet&amp;rdquo;. Sometimes, we just don&amp;rsquo;t have the answer but we have many proposed theories, so he talks about them and lets you reach your own conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The 21 Irrefutable Laws of Leadership: Follow Them and People Will Follow You</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/21lawsofleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/21lawsofleadership/</guid>
      <description>Book: The 21 Irrefutable Laws of Leadership: Follow Them and People Will Follow You by John C. Maxwell. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between 3 and 4 stars and decided to go with 3 for this one.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book, I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to complain about it. Some &amp;ldquo;laws&amp;rdquo; seem to be fillers to me, but many make total sense.
I would recommend it to someone, but reading a summary first would probably give you 80% of the value the book can bring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Meet the Frugalwoods: Achieving Financial Independence Through Simple Living</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/meetthefrugalwoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/meetthefrugalwoods/</guid>
      <description>Book: Meet the Frugalwoods: Achieving Financial Independence Through Simple Living by Elizabeth Willard Thames. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I follow their blog for a while now and like it a lot, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the same feeling with the book.
It was interesting to read that they felt themselves to be privileged when comparing to the rest of the population. Financial independence is not for everyone but frugality can be and that&amp;rsquo;s what they tried to say, IMO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Power Of Less: The Fine Art of Limiting Yourself to the Essential</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerofless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerofless/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Power Of Less: The Fine Art of Limiting Yourself to the Essential by Leo Babauta. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. It&amp;rsquo;s repetitive and a bit outdated (I heard Google reader somewhere) but all the hints here are still valid.
To summarize: the focus is everything. Chose something you want to do and do it. Remove everything else that&amp;rsquo;s not moving you toward your priorities and do what you have to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of It Doesn&#39;t Have to Be Crazy at Work</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/crazyatwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/crazyatwork/</guid>
      <description>Book: It Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Have to Be Crazy at Work by Jason Fried. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
What a great book! The best part of this book is that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing so out of this world there, they are just talking about what we should be doing.
Hey, it&amp;rsquo;s true, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be crazy at work. We can still do our best and deliver an amazing product without making ourselves miserable working like crazy to meet some made-up numbers used as &amp;ldquo;goals&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Principles</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/principlesbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/principlesbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Principles (Summary) by Ray Dalio. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between 4 and 5 stars for this one. I would say I would rate it with 4.5, but when I was editing my notes I realized the big number of notes I had and decided to go for 5 stars.
There are many good ideas in this book and many of the things I see here are logical. If you&amp;rsquo;re a logical person (instead of an emotional one) you will understand many of the strategies he describes in this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of 1984</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/1984/</guid>
      <description>Book: 1984 by George Orwell. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between a 4 and 5 stars for this book and decided to go with 4.
The ideas behind this book are amazing, especially when you read a little bit about Orwell and the political scenario of the time. It is a criticism of many things but it&amp;rsquo;s still an interesting construct of what may happen in a very extreme scenario.
The whole idea of creating a language to limit how people describe things and how they think is a really interesting concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Lay of Aotrou and Itroun</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aotrouanditroun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aotrouanditroun/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Lay of Aotrou and Itroun by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s an OK book if you&amp;rsquo;re a Tolkien fan.
For those who like Tolkien and everything he researched, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting book to read. I would not recommend this book to someone who&amp;rsquo;s not into Tolkien.
There are three poems in this book and it tries to tell a story about how Tolkien wrote the final poem. None of them are that great alone but together they show one particular part of Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s style of writing/researching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tolkienwest/</guid>
      <description>Book: Tolkien and the West: Recovering the Lost Tradition of Europe (The Modern Scholar) by Michael D.C. Drout. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book if you are a fan of J.R.R. Tolkien (like me).
I read 10+ J.R.R. Tolkien books already. I really like the descriptive way of writing and the whole fantasy world he created. I also read some other books that are not related to middle earth.
With that said, it was amazing to me to find so much that was not explicit in the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Brief History of Time</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/briefhistoryoftime/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/briefhistoryoftime/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Brief History of Time by Stephen Hawking. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book but not that simple for those who are not engaged with physics. That&amp;rsquo;s not a problem with the book, IMO, physics is complicated.
The pacing of the book is really good. He starts with the basics of physics and how paper after paper it is changing. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how Stephen Hawking puts himself as part of that story, not the center of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Introvert&#39;s Edge: How the Quiet and Shy Can Outsell Anyone</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/introvertsedge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/introvertsedge/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Introvert&amp;rsquo;s Edge: How the Quiet and Shy Can Outsell Anyone by Matthew Owen Pollard. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I bought this book because I wanted to understand a little bit more about introverts, so I can improve myself and understand others better. In the end, this book is totally related to sales, and part of it was not so interesting to me.
I have to say that his method seems to be really good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Fast Focus: A Quick-Start Guide To Mastering Your Attention, Ignoring Distractions, And Getting More Done In Less Time!</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/fastfocusbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/fastfocusbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Fast Focus: A Quick-Start Guide To Mastering Your Attention, Ignoring Distractions, And Getting More Done In Less Time! by Damon Zahariades. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book overall. I was between 4 and 5 for this one. It shares some great insights with [b:When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|35412097|When The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|Daniel H. Pink|https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1502223427s/35412097.jpg|56779991][b:When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|35412097|When The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing|Daniel H.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Managing Oneself</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/managingoneself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/managingoneself/</guid>
      <description>Book: Managing Oneself by Peter F. Drucker. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book is not life-changing but it&amp;rsquo;s small, straight to the point, and has many terrific bits of advice for your career and life.
I would totally recommend you to read it since it&amp;rsquo;s not expensive and quick to read/listen to (around 1 hour on Audible).
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Feedback analysis: whenever you take a crucial decision or action take note of the results you&amp;rsquo;re expecting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Filosofia Explica as Grandes Questões da Humanidade</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/filosofiaquestoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/filosofiaquestoes/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Filosofia Explica as Grandes Questões da Humanidade by Clóvis de Barros Filho. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro bem interessante para aqueles que querem pensar sobre algumas coisas mais &amp;ldquo;profundas&amp;rdquo; mas sem precisar adentar em um idioma mais complicado. Os autores comentam de forma simples sobre algumas questões interessantes (e as vezes complicadas) da filosofia. Se você já conhece muitas delas mais a fundo, provavelmente esse não seja um livro para você.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hardthingabouthardthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hardthingabouthardthings/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers by Ben Horowitz. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book overall, especially if you are (or want to be) a CEO. Some (many?) ideas are not aligned with the way I would manage my own company, but there are many useful insights into hairy situations one may be faced during his CEO time.
Sometimes the author contradicts himself, IMO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Blood, Sweat, and Pixels: The Triumphant, Turbulent Stories Behind How Video Games Are Made</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bloodsweatandpixels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bloodsweatandpixels/</guid>
      <description>Book: Blood, Sweat, and Pixels: The Triumphant, Turbulent Stories Behind How Video Games Are Made by Jason Schreier. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Good book overall, I did not take notes because it seems like a fictional book. :P
If you like this book I would also recommend you to read Masters of Doom and some chapters of Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution where they tell some game companies stories.
I would also add Indie game: the movie (also available on Netflix) to the list of complimentary content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/zerotoone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/zerotoone/</guid>
      <description>Book: Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future by Peter Thiel. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. There are some good insights, some things that only work for a particular context, and some others that I disagree.
I have to highlight one item of my notes:
&amp;ldquo;Even working remotely should be avoided because misalignment can creep in whenever colleagues aren&amp;rsquo;t together full-time, in the same place, every day&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Wait, What?: And Life&#39;s Other Essential Questions</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/waitwhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/waitwhat/</guid>
      <description>Book: Wait, What?: And Life&amp;rsquo;s Other Essential Questions by James E. Ryan. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I bought this book as an Audible daily deal. For the price and size of the book, it was ok.
The book is exactly what the author says in the beginning: It&amp;rsquo;s a lecture that became a book. It can be summarized in less than 10 lines. Please read the other reviews and you will know the whole book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Shop Class as Soulcraft: An Inquiry Into the Value of Work</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/shopclasssoulcraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/shopclasssoulcraft/</guid>
      <description>Book: Shop Class as Soulcraft: An Inquiry Into the Value of Work by Matthew B. Crawford. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was between 3 and 4 stars for this review but decided to stick with 3. The book has some interesting insights and the whole motorcycle thing resonates a lot with me, but in general, I found myself bored by the pacing and abstraction.
Here are my raw notes about the book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/guidetogoodlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/guidetogoodlife/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy by William B. Irvine. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about stoicism and its practices. After reading this I found that I&amp;rsquo;m practicing many techniques of stoicism for many years without knowing it.
The book starts with the history of stoicism, the first stoics, and the context of their time. The beginning is not pragmatic as I was expecting but when I finished the book, I decided it was a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of Learning: A Journey in the Pursuit of Excellence</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artoflearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artoflearning/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of Learning: A Journey in the Pursuit of Excellence by Josh Waitzkin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book. I first heard of Josh when listening to Tim Ferriss show and then I got a recommendation (tks, Amir!).
The author is the guy from &amp;ldquo;Searching for Bobby Fischer&amp;rdquo; movie (http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108065/). He was a chess prodigy as a kid and a Tai Chi Chuan champion as an adult. The links between the learning of martial arts and chess are really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Richest Man in Babylon</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/richestmaninbabylon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/richestmaninbabylon/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Richest Man in Babylon by George S. Clason. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I just read &amp;ldquo;rich dad poor dad&amp;rdquo; before reading this one and I think it ruined my experience. After reading that book first, this one looks like a puzzle you already know the answer.
This book is a series of parables of the &amp;ldquo;richest man in Babylon&amp;rdquo; (as you expect) and you need to read the parables understand the context and translate it to your life if you want to get something useful from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Rich Dad, Poor Dad</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/richdadpoordad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/richdadpoordad/</guid>
      <description>Book: Rich Dad, Poor Dad by Robert T. Kiyosaki. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The first part of this book was truly amazing. I really enjoyed the way he was showing the difference that both dads tell him how to live life and invest in his future. It was really great to take children for that because some things just don&amp;rsquo;t make sense for a child and are really easy to explain to the reader without having to rely on his current knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Anything You Want</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/anythingyouwant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/anythingyouwant/</guid>
      <description>Book: Anything You Want by Derek Sivers. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Amazing book! It&amp;rsquo;s worth 5 stars.
I listened to it on Audible, and it&amp;rsquo;s around 1h30 of audio, straight to the point. He is not theorizing about what should be right or what you should do to be successful. Instead, he is talking about his experience and what he thinks were the goods and bad choices he made.
This book was concise enough and with tons of valuable information to earn this 5 stars review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of Invisibility: The World&#39;s Most Famous Hacker Teaches You How to Be Safe in the Age of Big Brother and Big Data</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artofinvisibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artofinvisibility/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of Invisibility: The World&amp;rsquo;s Most Famous Hacker Teaches You How to Be Safe in the Age of Big Brother and Big Data by Kevin D. Mitnick. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is not new to me that we have a lot of security flaws everywhere. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s scary, but that&amp;rsquo;s what you sign for when you decide to use the internet.
He shows some things you can do to be anonymous but it&amp;rsquo;s tough and you usually don&amp;rsquo;t need it to live a normal life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Hiding in Unnatural Happiness</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/unnaturalhappiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/unnaturalhappiness/</guid>
      <description>Book: Hiding in Unnatural Happiness by Devamrita Swami. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I received this book from a monk while walking on the streets of York (UK) last year. I gave a small donation, and he told me to keep the book, so I decided to read it. He said it was about meditation, but it&amp;rsquo;s about yoga in general (not the physical practice).
I was not aware of anything related to Bhagavad Gita, Krishna, or anything like that, so it was an enjoyable reading for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of At the Mountains of Madness</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mountainsofmadness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mountainsofmadness/</guid>
      <description>Book: At the Mountains of Madness by H.P. Lovecraft. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The first H.P. Lovecraft book I read/listen and now I understand what people say from his descriptions.
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how he keeps the suspense until the last 5% of the book. The bad part is that it becomes boring sometimes. You want to understand was is there and why he doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about it but he keeps describing icy mountains and large rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Minimalism: Live a Meaningful Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/minimalismbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/minimalismbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Minimalism: Live a Meaningful Life by Joshua Fields Millburn. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was expecting more from this book.
I listen to their Podcast and read some articles on their website. This book looks like a list of pointers to their website. I would just recommend it in case you want something to start your journey in minimalism thinking, so you can buy the audiobook and listen to it in your spare time before diving deep into their articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of On Power</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/onpowerbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/onpowerbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: On Power by Robert A. Caro. Rating: ⭐️⭐️.
Not that much to learn from this &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s really small (almost two hours of audio) and looks like an abridged version of a collection of other books. I&amp;rsquo;m not American, so I&amp;rsquo;m not part of the context or his target audience and maybe it also plays some role here.
The whole thing about the electricity was a reality for my mom (and for me when I visited my grandparents as a child) in Brazil, it may be shocking to people living in New York nowadays but I already knew all of that in my own context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of What Doesn&#39;t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude, and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/wimhoffbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/wimhoffbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: What Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude, and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength by Scott Carney. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was 3 stars most part of the book but I actually learned some stuff and added some pointers for further research, so it deserves a 4.
The good part of this book is to convince you, or at least inspire you to research a little bit on the topic, that we can be more than what we are now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Rendezvous with Rama (Rama, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rendezvouswithrama/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rendezvouswithrama/</guid>
      <description>Book: Rendezvous with Rama (Rama, #1) by Arthur C. Clarke. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I tend to not read much science fiction but this is a great book.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R. Tolkien because I love the way he used to build his world. I found Rama an amazing place where things work in a different way but following most of the same laws we have.
Arthur C. Clarke writes in a nice way, adding the exact number of details you need to feel immersed in the story without adding too much information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of My Favorite Universe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/myfavoriteuniverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/myfavoriteuniverse/</guid>
      <description>Book: My Favorite Universe by Neil deGrasse Tyson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book to introduce physics to common people.
Neil deGrasse Tyson is great at explaining complicated topics in a simple way. The explanation of dense objects using hot chocolate and cream was really nice for me (no spoilers, read it! :D).
Did you watch Cosmos? Do you like to (or at least used to) follow Discovery Channel space documentaries? In case your answer is yes to any of these questions, you probably already know most part of this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Cesar Millan&#39;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bringinghomeashelterdog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bringinghomeashelterdog/</guid>
      <description>Book: Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog by Cesar Millan. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book for those thinking about adopting a shelter dog and did not research it yet.
I adopted my dog from a local shelter, he was abandoned at the shelter door with his brothers as a puppy. He was 2 months old when we adopted him. I had to do some research in different sources and buy some e-&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Radical Candor: Be a Kickass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/radicalcandorbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/radicalcandorbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Radical Candor: Be a Kickass Boss Without Losing Your Humanity by Kim Malone Scott. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A book every boss should read. It helps to create a culture of giving and receiving honest feedback and create great teams. It has many truths, you will notice many of them if you&amp;rsquo;re working for a big company. You may not agree with some parts of it depending on how you see work and people but if you really care about people careers and the performance of your team it makes a lot of sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/leadershipselfdeception/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/leadershipselfdeception/</guid>
      <description>Book: Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box by The Arbinger Institute. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book. Good information in a good narrative form.
This is a short book with an easy to follow narrative about leadership. There are not so many notes about this one, but here they are:
 See People as people, not objects Self-betrayal is an act in contrary of what I feel I should do for another person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Game of Thrones (A Song of Ice and Fire, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gameofthrones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gameofthrones/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Game of Thrones (A Song of Ice and Fire, #1) by George R.R. Martin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great book.
I know ASOIAF from the TV show &amp;ldquo;Game of Thrones&amp;rdquo;. This book was the first one I bought at Audible but decided to not start with it (33hs of content). As the 7th season of the TV show started, I decided to gather more information about the whole plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Practice Perfect: 42 Rules for Getting Better at Getting Better</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/practiceperfectbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/practiceperfectbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Practice Perfect: 42 Rules for Getting Better at Getting Better by Doug Lemov. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book with lots of advice. The structure is not so good, but it&amp;rsquo;s OK.
As the title says, it shows 42 rules to improve yourself and practice in the right way. It an introduction, 42 tips on how to get better at getting better, a conclusion, and the appendices. The structure looks like a to-do list of &amp;ldquo;rules&amp;rdquo;, so it&amp;rsquo;s not so comfortable to read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/letmypeoplegosurfing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/letmypeoplegosurfing/</guid>
      <description>Book: Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman by Yvon Chouinard. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was 3 stars until 70% of the book but the ending deserves 4.
This book is the story of Patagonia and how its founders deal with business, people, and the environment.
Their way of life resonates a lot with what I think is a good way to live. Maintain a sustainable business, hire people you trust and give them enough freedom to live a good life while giving their best to make the company grow, thinking about the environment, grow only when you have to grow (to supply your demand), live a minimalistic life, and so many other stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Score Takes Care of Itself: My Philosophy of Leadership</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/scoretakescareofitself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/scoretakescareofitself/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Score Takes Care of Itself: My Philosophy of Leadership by Bill Walsh. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great book on leadership. I confess that I was really bored in the first 15% of the book. The beginning is boring for those who don&amp;rsquo;t give a f*ck about football but keep reading, it worth the journey. Bill Walsh took the San Francisco 49ers from a really bad performance (2 wins/14 losses) to an amazing one (13 win/3 losses) 2 years later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/startwithwhy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/startwithwhy/</guid>
      <description>Book: Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action by Simon Sinek. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I always thought we must first have a reason to create something and this book shows some companies that are famous for doing that and how they did it.
Here are some notes about it:
 Most of what we have now is marketing by manipulation Fear is the most powerful manipulation of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Secrets of Story: Innovative Tools for Perfecting Your Fiction and Captivating Readers</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/secretsofstory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/secretsofstory/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Secrets of Story: Innovative Tools for Perfecting Your Fiction and Captivating Readers by Matt Bird. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A great book on how to write books. 4.5 stars.
The book goes through many problems and misconceptions behind writing a fiction book. In the book blog, you can find a big checklist with many questions your book has to answer: http://www.secretsofstory.com/2014/09/the-ultimate-story-checklist-raising.html
There are many examples around each of these topics throughout the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Louder Than Words: The New Science of How the Mind Makes Meaning</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/louderthanwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/louderthanwords/</guid>
      <description>Book: Louder Than Words: The New Science of How the Mind Makes Meaning by Benjamin K. Bergen. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book, but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.
I really like books that have a lot of research behind it, this is one of them. For almost every assumption made, the author reveals research done to support his point.
This book made me realize that our words do not give meaning to something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/deepworkbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/deepworkbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World by Cal Newport. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
re-reading 2017
I will work on a new project and this book will be a perfect fit for the new work environment, so I decided to revisit it.
I wrote my book (Desconstruindo a Web: As tecnologias por trás de uma requisição using Deep work and it was an amazing experience.
Embrace boredom is the most difficult practice from this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/elonmuskbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/elonmuskbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Elon Musk: Tesla, SpaceX, and the Quest for a Fantastic Future by Ashlee Vance. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a life-changing book but it&amp;rsquo;s cool to understand Elon Musk path.
Here are some few sentences I like and some comments on them:
 The best minds of our time are working to make users click on ads
 That&amp;rsquo;s really sad. Elon has a great vision of the future and you can feel like him when reading the book (at least I can).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Power of Broke: How Empty Pockets, a Tight Budget, and a Hunger for Success Can Become Your Greatest Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerofbroke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerofbroke/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Power of Broke: How Empty Pockets, a Tight Budget, and a Hunger for Success Can Become Your Greatest Competitive Advantage by Daymond John. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
An ordinary book. 3 stars are good enough.
The whole book discusses how to do business when you have no money. Daymond is the man behind Fubu and a TV show called Shark Tank. His story is really interesting to follow because he raised his entire business out of nothing, following the power of broke principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Einstein no Brasil</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/einsteinnobrasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/einsteinnobrasil/</guid>
      <description>Book: Einstein no Brasil by Aguinaldo Prandini Ricieri. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro comum, com apenas um quote que valeu muito a pena. No geral consegui extrair algumas poucas boas informações sobre o Einstein daqui.
Muita coisa do que tem nesse livro é parte do contexto do Brasil em 1925. Apesar da visita do Einstein ter sido noticiada em vários jornais e ele ter recebido homenagens de vários grupos, não teve nada muito revelador.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Spaceman: An Astronaut&#39;s Unlikely Journey to Unlock the Secrets of the Universe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/spacemanbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/spacemanbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Spaceman: An Astronaut&amp;rsquo;s Unlikely Journey to Unlock the Secrets of the Universe by Mike Massimino. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book, 4.5 stars.
Mike does a great job describing how is the life of an astronaut. Listen (yes, I used an Audible audiobook) to his story was like living it with him. I could feel how was to be waiting for the NASA phone call after so many years trying to be an astronaut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Smarter Faster Better: The Secrets of Being Productive in Life and Business</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/smarterfasterbetter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/smarterfasterbetter/</guid>
      <description>Book: Smarter Faster Better: The Secrets of Being Productive in Life and Business by Charles Duhigg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is a good book. I almost gave 3 stars, but it is still a Mastery effect. It deserves four.
Each chapter in the book is devoted to a specific area: Motivation, Teams, Focus, Goal setting, Managing others, Decision making, Innovation, and Absorbing data.
My notes on each topic:
Motivation  Motivation is feeling in control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Art of The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artoflotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artoflotr/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Art of The Lord of the Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien by Wayne G. Hammond. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is one of those books for Tolkien fans. I do not recommend it if you did not read other books by Tolkien.
It is nice to read if you already read The Hobbit and The Lord of the Rings. This book shows a lot of details that Tolkien used as a guideline to write the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Mindfulness in Plain English</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mindfulnessplainenglish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mindfulnessplainenglish/</guid>
      <description>Book: Mindfulness in Plain English by Henepola Gunaratana. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I was expecting some more but after reading the description again it seems to deliver exactly what it says.
The whole book is about meditation and I would say 50% of it is about focusing on your breathe.
The chapter about loving kindness is also interesting. There are some quotes of Buddha that are really great.
Here are my raw notes about the book:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Urban Monk: Eastern Wisdom and Modern Hacks to Stop Time and Find Success, Happiness, and Peace</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/urbanmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/urbanmonk/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Urban Monk: Eastern Wisdom and Modern Hacks to Stop Time and Find Success, Happiness, and Peace by Pedram Shojai. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The author was a Monk for 4 years, is a Doctor of Oriental Medicine and studied Kung Fu and Tai Chi for decades, this is what you will get from the book.
There are some chapters with a lot of meditation techniques and some tips about sustainability. The idea is to help you to live like a monk in the urban landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Mastery</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/masterybook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/masterybook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Mastery by Robert Greene. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
One of the best books I ever read.
This book goes through the life of various masters of our history. Some of them I did not know and decided to look after their life, which was a great experience as well.
If you want to be a master of something, be prepared to use a huge amount of time dealing with it and practicing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de A história de Kullervo</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/kullervo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/kullervo/</guid>
      <description>Book: A história de Kullervo by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um livro para quem é fã de Tolkien.
Esse é um livro relativamente pequeno, com uma história de cerca de 50 páginas e muitas referências para um dos primeiros trabalhos do Tolkien. Eu só recomendaria esse livro para quem já leu outras obras do Tolkien como Silmarilion ou Os Filhos de Húrin.
A história de Kullervo inspirou muito do que aconteceu na história de Turin Turambar, além de outras coisas que são contadas no Silmarilion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Diary of a Young Girl</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/annefrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/annefrank/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Diary of a Young Girl by Anne Frank. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I decided to read this book one month before visiting the Anne Frank Museum in Amsterdam. My plan is to use the whole context of the book to have the full experience when visiting the museum.
The book is OK. Most part of it is just what you expect from a diary of a 14 years old girl, even with the whole context implied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Outliers: The Story of Success</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/outliersbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/outliersbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Outliers: The Story of Success by Malcolm Gladwell. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was a good reading. I would review this book as 3 stars but at the end, I was convinced that it made me think about many interesting things on successful people in general.
The key point of this book is: what makes successful people is a match of many factors. Some of those factors were not clear to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Memory Illusion: Remembering, Forgetting, and the Science of False Memory</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/memoryillusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/memoryillusion/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Memory Illusion: Remembering, Forgetting, and the Science of False Memory by Julia Shaw. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The whole point of this book is to show that our memories are not reliable. We can&amp;rsquo;t be sure that something happened because a lot of things may influence our past memories.
The good argument in favor of this book is its references. There are many references for academic studies. The bad part is that it is not so comfortable to read, the language is not that good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Algorithms to Live By: The Computer Science of Human Decisions</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/algorithmstoliveby/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/algorithmstoliveby/</guid>
      <description>Book: Algorithms to Live By: The Computer Science of Human Decisions by Brian Christian. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is that kind of book that does not answer questions, it just creates a lot more. :)
I tend to not implement algorithms just for the sake of learning a new one and this is not a good thing. When you read these kinds of books you understand why it&amp;rsquo;s so important to know which kinds of algorithms already exists and which problems they solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Introdução à Web Semântica: A inteligência da informação</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/websemantica/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/websemantica/</guid>
      <description>Book: Introdução à Web Semântica: A inteligência da informação by Diego Eis. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Tive o prazer de ajudar no processo de revisão desse livro. O assunto sempre me chamou a atenção mas nunca parei para estudar e entender as necessidades.
Esse livro vai desde o começo da internet, mostrando as outras tentativas de implementação e como chegamos na forma de mostrar dados que temos hoje. Essa forma possui alguns problemas para dar contexto para as coisas e fazer os links entre os conteúdos, e é aí que entra a web semantica.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Programming Elixir: Functional |&gt; Concurrent |&gt; Pragmatic |&gt; Fun</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/programmingelixir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/programmingelixir/</guid>
      <description>Book: Programming Elixir: Functional |&amp;gt; Concurrent |&amp;gt; Pragmatic |&amp;gt; Fun by Dave Thomas. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the best Elixir book I read but it&amp;rsquo;s a good book.
I started with Programming Phoenix for a more practical learning. This book feels like the other &amp;ldquo;Programming language book&amp;rdquo;. You will find how to split a string, or how you can deal with regex. In case you&amp;rsquo;re looking for the methods for many types, it will be for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck: A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/artofnotgivingafuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/artofnotgivingafuck/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck: A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life by Mark Manson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It was good at the beginning but the end was too self-help for me.
I learned good things in this book and that&amp;rsquo;s what matters for me.
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Give a fuck about things you already have, not only what you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of TED Talks: The Official TED Guide to Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/tedtalksbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/tedtalksbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: TED Talks: The Official TED Guide to Public Speaking by Chris J. Anderson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
There are some cool tips in this book but it&amp;rsquo;s not so straight to the point if you&amp;rsquo;re just looking for speaking tips. If you like to speak at IT events (like I do) I really recommend http://speaking.io.
This book shows the way to deliver a presentation that earns a standing ovation at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Will It Fly?: How to Test Your Next Business Idea So You Don&#39;t Waste Your Time and Money</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/willitfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/willitfly/</guid>
      <description>Book: Will It Fly?: How to Test Your Next Business Idea So You Don&amp;rsquo;t Waste Your Time and Money . Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I like this book and have a bunch of notes to share.
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Grab a piece of paper and divide it into four sections. Then, identify the four most important parts of your life. Your categories might be, for example, Family, Career, Well-being and Money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The 10x Rule: The Only Difference Between Success and Failure</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/10xrule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/10xrule/</guid>
      <description>Book: The 10x Rule: The Only Difference Between Success and Failure by Grant Cardone. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I really like this book. I would recommend it if you are the kind of person that wants to make a difference in the world and want to be remembered in the future generations. The book will not give you that but if you follow a methodology like it recommends you will get closer to your big goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Guia Front-End: O caminho das pedras para ser um dev Front-End</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/guiafrontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/guiafrontend/</guid>
      <description>Book: Guia Front-End: O caminho das pedras para ser um dev Front-End by Diego Eis. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
O Diego Eis está aí desde a época que usávamos tabelas para construir sites, é sempre interessante absorver conteúdo de pessoas com tanto histórico.
O livro não foi escrito para o meu perfil, mas mesmo assim me fez pensar em umas coisas interessantes. Ele me fez realizar o mundo sem CSS para criação de páginas, onde você precisava colocar o estilo em todas as tags, sendo que as tags que estão dentro dela não herdariam o estilo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Einstein: His Life and Universe</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/einsteinbio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/einsteinbio/</guid>
      <description>Book: Einstein: His Life and Universe by Walter Isaacson. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is the first biography that I read and I found it amazing.
I knew that Albert Einstein was a genius but it was not just that. He was extremely devoted to what he did. I had many quotes from this book and one of them shows what I just said:
&amp;ldquo;As long as I am able to work, I must not and will not complain, because work is the only thing that gives substance to life&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Programming Phoenix: Productive |&gt; Reliable |&gt; Fast</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/programmingphoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/programmingphoenix/</guid>
      <description>Book: Programming Phoenix: Productive |&amp;gt; Reliable |&amp;gt; Fast by Chris McCord. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is a great book for web developers learning Elixir (yeah, not just Phoenix).
I&amp;rsquo;m on the path of playing with Elixir and was looking for a book to amplify my knowledge. I first started with Programming Elixir, from Dave Thomas but I was looking for something more practical.
I decided to try Programming Phoenix and found that it shows everything I need to know about Elixir to build a web application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/phoenixproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/phoenixproject/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Phoenix Project: A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win by Gene Kim. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a great book for IT folks.
In case you worked (or still work) in a big company with lots of ITIL things that holds the development, this book will be like home for you.
It is a typical hero&amp;rsquo;s journey and the characters are not so well developed (IMO) but the story is still good to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Level Up Your Life: How to Unlock Adventure and Happiness by Becoming the Hero of Your Own Story</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/levelupyourlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/levelupyourlife/</guid>
      <description>Book: Level Up Your Life: How to Unlock Adventure and Happiness by Becoming the Hero of Your Own Story by Steve Kamb. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a good book but it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.
I already use many of the tips mentioned in this book and they really work. It makes a good pair with habitica.com, in case you like to play these kinds of games in real life.
There are many great references for the nerds out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/coachinghabits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/coachinghabits/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Coaching Habit: Say Less, Ask More &amp;amp; Change the Way You Lead Forever. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Read this book in 2016 but never published any review until now (2021, even if the post date is the day I finished the book). I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say now, but at least I can publish my notes from 2016.
Here are my raw notes about the book:
 Kickstart, AWE (and what else), and Focus - Are the guides for a coach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of How to Spot a Liar with People Don&#39;t Tell the Truth</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/howtospotaliar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/howtospotaliar/</guid>
      <description>Book: How to Spot a Liar with People Don&amp;rsquo;t Tell the Truth by Gregory Hartley. Rating: ⭐️⭐️.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used the Audible Abridged version for this one. The narration is not good as the other audiobooks I&amp;rsquo;m used to listen.
The book content is not good to follow as well. It is focused on interrogation and this is not my goal for reading it.
But it is not all that bad. I got some interesting tips on body language and these kind of stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Thinking, Fast and Slow</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/thinkingfastslow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/thinkingfastslow/</guid>
      <description>Book: Thinking, Fast and Slow by Daniel Kahneman. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
The concept of system 1 (fast) and system 2 (slow) is really great.
For tech folks, the system 1 looks like a cache inside your head. It is the best way to explain it for tech related people, in my opinion.
There are dozens of serious research done to make this book happen. They were not made exclusively for the book, but it is really nice to read a book that has strong foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Armadilhas da Mente</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/armadilhasdamente/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/armadilhasdamente/</guid>
      <description>Book: Armadilhas da Mente by Augusto Cury. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Eu já tinha lido o &amp;ldquo;Ansiedade - Como Enfrentar o Mal do Século&amp;rdquo;, portanto esse livro não adicionou tanto para mim.
Esse livro mostra todos os conceitos gatilhos, janelas, autofluxo e etc. dentro de um romance. A história é ok e chega a ser interessante até perto do final. Na minha visão ficou nítido que a história não é o centro do livro e sim os conceitos que estão envolvidos com ela.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/powerofhabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/powerofhabit/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business by Charles Duhigg. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Read this book for the first time in 2016 and re-read it now (2019). The first time I read it, I did not take notes, so I decided to &amp;ldquo;properly read/listen&amp;rdquo; now.
I like the number of studies this book shows and how much we understand about our habits by looking at its results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Life, the Universe and Everything (Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy, #3)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker3/</guid>
      <description>Book: Life, the Universe and Everything (Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, #3) by Douglas Adams. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nothing special about this one&amp;hellip; The first one is brilliant, the second one is great, the third is just OK.
This book made me think about reading the fourth and fifth and I think I will stop here. All that moments that make you think about &amp;ldquo;Life, Universe and Everything&amp;rdquo; are not present here like was in the first books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ouvir livros (audiobooks), o futuro da leitura</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/audiobooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/audiobooks/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Ouvir livros é o futuro.
Atualização de 18/06/2016: Adicionando o audiobooks.com.
Quem me conhece sabe que há muito tempo eu ouço podcasts sempre que eu posso, principalmente no caminho entre a minha casa e o trabalho. No fim do ano de 2015 eu vi a quantidade de livros que o Rafael Rosa leu e fiquei abismado. Ele leu mais de 90 livros em um ano! Tudo bem que ele estava em um período sabático, mas mesmo assim ainda é uma quantidade bem absurda de livros para se ler em um ano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Restaurant at the End of the Universe (Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy, #2)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker2/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Restaurant at the End of the Universe (Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, #2) by Douglas Adams. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Another great book from Douglas Adams. The idea behind the restaurant is really really interenting and the author does a great job to insert funny concepts behind the whole event.
There are some nice gotchas that make you laugh while reading, I really recommend it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy (Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hitchhiker1/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy (Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, #1) by Douglas Adams. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This book is amazing! There are some non-sense parts but in general, it makes you think about &amp;ldquo;life, universe, and everything&amp;rdquo;.
There are some ideas that look so absurd in real life but make sense in the book context. If you&amp;rsquo;re that kind of geek/nerd that likes physics (you don&amp;rsquo;t need to be an expert, just an enthusiast) this book will be great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Future of the Professions: How Technology Will Transform the Work of Human Experts</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/futureofprofessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/futureofprofessions/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Future of the Professions: How Technology Will Transform the Work of Human Experts by Richard Susskind. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It is a nice idea and the arguments looks valid and make you think about the future. The book is not easy to follow through and I the first 5 chapters are not so interesting. Most part of the book is an introduction to the main subject that is presented on the last chapters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Docker Security: Using Containers Safely in Production</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dockersecuritybook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dockersecuritybook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Docker Security: Using Containers Safely in Production by Adrian Mouat. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good book for who is using or planning to use Docker in production. There are some very good tips that are not so obvious about Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Caixa de Ferramentas DevOps: Um guia para construção, administração e arquitetura de sistemas modernos</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/caixaferramentasdevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/caixaferramentasdevops/</guid>
      <description>Book: Caixa de Ferramentas DevOps: Um guia para construção, administração e arquitetura de sistemas modernos by Gleicon Moraes. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Um bom livro para quem não conhece as ferramentas de devops do momento e está procurando alguma coisa que seja bem mão na massa. O autor mostra como usar Ansible, Docker, Vagrant e como fazer deploy usando Digital Ocean e AWS de uma forma automatizada e que pode ser aplicada a multiplas linguagens e/ou ambientes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Wolf of Wall Street (The Wolf of Wall Street, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/wolfofwallstreet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/wolfofwallstreet/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Wolf of Wall Street (The Wolf of Wall Street, #1) by Jordan Belfort. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Did you watch the movie?
Yes: you&amp;rsquo;re done. The book does not add anything relevant IMO.
No: Watch the movie.
In case you prefer books than movies, you may try this one. It is not a bad book and you will see how a smart guy can be a perfect asshole.
The only thing that I absorved from this book is: This kind of life is not for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People: Powerful Lessons in Personal Change</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/7habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/7habits/</guid>
      <description>Book: The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People: Powerful Lessons in Personal Change by Stephen R. Covey. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is a good book. There are some good examples there and it is worth reading, but if you want to understand the habits in a quick and easy manner just read on the author&amp;rsquo;s website.
There are some great insights, at least for me, in this book. The author says that the world works on the &amp;ldquo;outside-in&amp;rdquo; but we need to work on the &amp;ldquo;inside out&amp;rdquo;, taking care of ourselves and doing the best to make things better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Ferreiro de Bosque Grande</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/ferreirobosquegrande/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/ferreirobosquegrande/</guid>
      <description>Book: Ferreiro de Bosque Grande by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
É um livro muito legal para quem é fã de Tolkien. A história é bem pequena, menos da metade de livro. O restante do livro é um pouco de contexto sobre a história e porque ela foi escrita, juntamente com algumas ligações sobre a vida do Tolkien na época.
Esse foi o último livro escrito pelo Tolkien antes de sua morte e diz muito sobre o seus pensamentos sobre escrita, sobre o mundo das &amp;ldquo;fadas&amp;rdquo; (que não tem nada a ver com o que pensamos dele atualmente) e sobre a vida no geral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Getting Real: The Smarter, Faster, Easier Way to Build a Web Application</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/gettingrealbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/gettingrealbook/</guid>
      <description>Book: Getting Real: The Smarter, Faster, Easier Way to Build a Web Application by 37 Signals. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
There are almost 10 years from this book release and the ideas are still valid for the software development industry that we have now.
Some of them can&amp;rsquo;t be applied to big and established companies, but it shows why small companies can beat them if they know how to organize. &amp;ldquo;Divide and conquer&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Do only what is needed&amp;rdquo; are the core of this book IMO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/hackerscomputerrevolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/hackerscomputerrevolution/</guid>
      <description>Book: Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution by Steven Levy. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Great book. John Carmack said it was the most inspiring book for him and I can understand why.
The word Hackers is not the same these days, but the Hacker Ethics still lives in some of the programmers out there. Those guys that keep hacking (and/or programming) for hours and hours just for the joy of create and modify things still exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of MONEY Master the Game: 7 Simple Steps to Financial Freedom</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/moneymasterthegame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/moneymasterthegame/</guid>
      <description>Book: MONEY Master the Game: 7 Simple Steps to Financial Freedom by Anthony Robbins. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I have mixed feelings about this one. I got some cool insights about financing and how I can improve my plant of financial freedom, but the book was repetitive most of the time.
When I started this book my feeling was: &amp;ldquo;Man, this may be one of the best books I read&amp;rdquo;. Some time ago I was reading a lot of &amp;ldquo;soon you&amp;rsquo;ll see&amp;rdquo; or even repeating what was said before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de O Pistoleiro (A Torre Negra, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/darktower1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/darktower1/</guid>
      <description>Book: O Pistoleiro (A Torre Negra, #1) by Stephen King. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nunca tinha lido Stephen King, esse foi meu primeiro livro dele.
O começo do livro é bem confuso e muitas vezes eu tinha que reler para entender em qual contexto as coisas estavam acontecendo. Gostei do clima de suspense que o autor coloca em várias partes e das partes bizarras que foram descritas bem o suficiente para me deixar imerso e pensando.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de O Cavaleiro dos Sete Reinos (The Tales of Dunk and Egg)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dunkandegg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dunkandegg/</guid>
      <description>Book: O Cavaleiro dos Sete Reinos (The Tales of Dunk and Egg #1-3) by George R.R. Martin. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
It&amp;rsquo;s a good story for those who follow the whole series of &amp;ldquo;A song of ice and fire&amp;rdquo; as it occurs around 100 years before the first book.
The only part that is a bit annoying is that the story feels unfinished for me in the end, but the whole experience is good enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de A Jornada do Escritor: Estrutura mítica para escritores</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jornadaescritor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jornadaescritor/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Jornada do Escritor: Estrutura mítica para escritores by Christopher Vogler. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Essential reading for those who wants to write a book. I really like the way that Christopher explores movies like Titanic, Pulp Fiction, and The Lion King. The examples of the Hero&amp;rsquo;s journey based on this movie really helped me to understand the various archetypes and how they interact in each stage of the journey.
Just read it for the first time but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that I&amp;rsquo;ll read it again soon and keep it on my desk for reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of A Study in Scarlet (Sherlock Holmes, #1)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sherlockholmes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sherlockholmes1/</guid>
      <description>Book: A Study in Scarlet (Sherlock Holmes, #1) by Arthur Conan Doyle. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
A good book! I always wanted to read Sherlock Holmes books but never tried it. Thanks to BBC&amp;rsquo;s Sherlock Series I decided to give it a try. The good part is that I could understand a lot of jokes that the TV show made and the differences from the 189x to 201x. :)
I really recommend you to read it if you like stories on investigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Masters of Doom: How Two Guys Created an Empire and Transformed Pop Culture</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mastersofdoom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mastersofdoom/</guid>
      <description>Book: Masters of Doom: How Two Guys Created an Empire and Transformed Pop Culture by David Kushner. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I love this book. The two Johns created an empire by using the engineering capabilities of Carmack with the enthusiasm and ideas of Romero.
There are some other thoughts to put in this book. The two Johns are doing great and creating amazing games following the startup way of life, relying on junk food and diet coke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Cartas do Papai Noel por J.R.R Tolkien</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/cartaspapainoel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/cartaspapainoel/</guid>
      <description>Book: Cartas do Papai Noel by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Eu realmente admiro o J.R.R Tolkien. Esse tipo de livro mostra como ele usava toda a sua imaginação e suas habilidades para fazer coisas para os filhos dele.
Para quem é fã das obras do Tolkien vai curtir bastante esse livro. Se você é pai (não é o meu caso) talvez veja uma forma legal de lidar com o seu filho pequeno e fazer brincadeiras durante os anos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Big Drop: How To Grow Your Wealth During the Coming Collapse</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/bigdrop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/bigdrop/</guid>
      <description>Book: The Big Drop: How To Grow Your Wealth During the Coming Collapse by James Rickards. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️.
TL; DR - A lot of theories about the next economic crash, if you want to know some connections between gold, dollar and other different investments to protect you in case it happens, it may be a good book for you.
I&amp;rsquo;m Brazilian and some part of the economic context is not the same here, but there are some parts make totally sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/freakonomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/freakonomics/</guid>
      <description>Book: Freakonomics: A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side of Everything by Steven D. Levitt. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Nice book with really interesting statistics done in some sets of data. It remembers me about the whole &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; trend that we have today.
In some parts it looks like the comparison of the global warming and the number of pirates (as my &amp;ldquo;Statistics One&amp;rdquo; professor and the book author used to say: &amp;ldquo;correlation does not imply causation&amp;rdquo;), but the whole idea behind the studies are really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Management 3.0: Leading Agile Developers, Developing Agile Leaders</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/management30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/management30/</guid>
      <description>Book: Management 3.0: Leading Agile Developers, Developing Agile Leaders by Jurgen Appelo. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
I read this book in 2015 when the product director of the company I worked for suggested to buy a bunch of copies and do a book club on that book. The director (and many of us, leaders) liked the ideas here, but there were not not attractive to the rest of the directors. Needless to say that reading this didn&amp;rsquo;t change anything in how the company does things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review de Ruby on Rails: coloque sua aplicação web nos trilhos</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/railsvinibaggio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/railsvinibaggio/</guid>
      <description>Book: Ruby on Rails: coloque sua aplicação web nos trilhos by Vinícius Baggio Fuentes. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
Esse livro é muito legal para quem não conhece Rails e quer colocar a mão na massa criando uma aplicação do zero. Com ele você consegue explorar uma boa parte do que é necessário para criar uma aplicação comum usando o framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluxo de leitura e o Android</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/leitura-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/leitura-android/</guid>
      <description>Quem me conhece sabe como eu sou meio doido quanto a ler coisas aleatórias (Google reader e artigos interessantes que eu acho perdidos por aí), e como eu tenho um tempo um pouco limitado, devido ao trabalho e a faculdade eu sempre tenho alguns esquemas diferentes para ler. :P
Fluxo de leitura Depois que eu comprei um Android o meu fluxo de leitura se modificou um pouco. E está da seguinte maneira:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rework</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/rework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/rework/</guid>
      <description>Hoje terminei de ler o livro da 37signals chamado Rework! E vou falar um pouco sobre a idéia dele aqui.
Atualmente eu fiz uma compra na Amazon em conjunto com uns amigos (@vinibaggio, @hugobarauna, @cantoniodasilva), e cogitei a compra do Rework, mas depois de uma pergunta no Twitter e algumas respostas sobre a idéia do livro eu resolvi não comprar, pois parecia muito gerencial, e acabei optando por outros (Design Patterns In Ruby, Ruby Programming Language, The Pragmatic Programmer), que falarei em outros posts :P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silmarilion</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/silmarilion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/silmarilion/</guid>
      <description>Book: Silmarilion by J.R.R. Tolkien. Rating: ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️.
This is J.R.R. Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s life work. The other known books a product of this. He was not able to finish this masterpiece, but Christopher Tolkien finished his father&amp;rsquo;s work in a great way.
I&amp;rsquo;m not going to lie, the Silmarilion is not an easy to read book. I would not recommend it to anyone who was not totally aware of the other books and still looking for more middle earth content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cabeça de Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/stevejobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/stevejobs/</guid>
      <description>Aqui estou eu novamente para falar de um livro que eu li nas férias! Dessa vez vou comentar sobre: &amp;ldquo;A cabeça de Steve Jobs&amp;rdquo;
Sobre o livro O livro é bem interessante e conta como Steve Jobs fez para ter o sucesso que tem atualmente, contando não somente os acertos, mas também os erros de Steve com o mercado, o que faz com que você caia na real que ele (assim como você) é apenas uma pessoa comum e que as vezes suas decisões fantásticas levavam a uma má situação.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anjos e Demônios</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/anjosedemonios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/anjosedemonios/</guid>
      <description>Felizmente eu estou de férias da faculdade novamente, e isso me dá um tempo livre para ler alguns livros, portanto resolvi começar com “Anjos e Demônios“, que é um livro que eu estou postergando a leitura faz mais de 2 anos (desde que li o código da vinci).
Eu particularmente gosto dos livros do Dan Brown, pois em sua grande maioria são histórias “polemicas” por misturar alguns fatos reais (que ninguem consegue provar a favor nem contra) com outros que são pura ficção.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance Websites</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/highperfwebsites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/highperfwebsites/</guid>
      <description>Mais um dos livros que eu consegui terminar de ler nas férias! O livro fala sobre performance de front end, como fazer as suas páginas carregarem mais rapidamente e fornecer uma melhor experiência para o usuário.
O livro começa explicando um pouco sobre o HTTP, seus métodos e utilizações, e depois inicia as sobre as 14 regras para ter um website mais performático. Eu vou tentar mostrar um pouco de cada uma das regras que o livro aborda, mas é claro que sem os grandes detalhes, comparações e exemplos que o livro dá, que são muito amplos e interessantes para se entender, mas vou dar uma visão geral de qual é o conteúdo da regra, para te chamar para comprar o livro e ler (ou não&amp;hellip;hehhe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/lotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/lotr/</guid>
      <description>Chegou o momento que eu estava esperando há vários meses&amp;hellip;. Após terminar de ler, vou escrever sobre O Senhor dos Anéis! :D
Todos que me conhecem sabem como eu sou apaixonado pelo mundo de O senhor dos anéis na verdade sobre histórias medievais e o Senhor dos anéis é foda), e eu só tinha assistido o filme (mais de 10 vezes o primeiro, e milhões de vezes os outros 2) e não tinha lido o livro ainda, o que me deixava inquieto, pois eu sabia muito bem que o nível de riquezas e detalhes do livro ia muito alem do que eu podia imaginar, sem contar que muita coisa foi cortada no filme (obviamente) para que se fosse feita uma boa adaptação.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic version control using Git</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/pragmaticgit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/pragmaticgit/</guid>
      <description>Há tempos que eu estava querendo conhecer um pouco mais do Git e nos últimos dias estava procurando um livro legal, quando me deparei com esse livro. Fiz algumas perguntas para um pessoal no Twitter como pessoalmente sobre esse livro, alguns me recomendavam, outros me passavam outros também interessantes, e estava em dúvida entre comprar ou não, até que consegui emprestado e li em 3 dias.
O livro é bem interessante, aborda desde o mais básico até o nível intermediário, não abordando conteúdos tão avançados.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
