<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stats on PotHix</title>
    <link>https://pothix.com/tags/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stats on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pothix.com/tags/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020 Year in Review</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/2020/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, like any other stats post, this one will be HUGE
If you&amp;rsquo;re following my blog, you know that I sometimes mentioned things were too hard and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sit down and write. Looking back now, I have a good laugh for my past self. ☺️
I can say for sure that 2020 was a complicated year and a lot of things change in my life. The biggest change is that I&amp;rsquo;m now a father of twins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Year in Review (full of metrics!)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/2019/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, like any other stats post, this one will be HUGE
My year in review for 2018 was never posted because I could never finish it. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to let the same thing happen this year, so here I am.
The end of 2018 and the beginning of 2019 was quite hard for me and me just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the energy to sit down in front of the computer during the weekends to write my monthly reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jun, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jun2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jun2018/</guid>
      <description>Guess what!? Yes, metrics for June! 📊
Books I usually don&amp;rsquo;t count how many books I read, I just track and check at the end of the month. When I saw that I read five books read this month, my face was like 😱. All of them received a 4-star review, so the result is quite good.

 Managing Oneself: This is a great book. It&amp;rsquo;s not life-changing, but there are many great tips to improve your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for May, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/may2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/may2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s May, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for metrics! 📊
Books Two books read this month, but both received a 3 stars review: 
 Wait, What?: And Life&amp;rsquo;s Other Essential Questions: Exactly what the author says in the beginning: It&amp;rsquo;s a lecture that became a book. Not bad, but OK-ish. Shop Class as Soulcraft: An Inquiry into the Value of Work: More political views than I was expecting and the pacing is not so good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Apr, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/apr2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/apr2018/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time for April metrics! 📊
Books Note: I write a review for each book I read. You can find them on my Goodreads account.
Again, just one book this month, and again, a 5 stars one!

A Guide to the Good Life: The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy. This book was on my reading list for many months now. After reading it, I realized I&amp;rsquo;m practicing a fraction of Stoicism for many years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Mar, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mar2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mar2018/</guid>
      <description>March is gone, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for metrics! 📊
Books Note: I write a review for each book I read. You can find them on my Goodreads account.
Just one book this month, but a 5 stars one:

When: The Scientific Secrets of Perfect Timing. This book is about optimization based on time and energy. What is the best time to do some action based on statistics? I found it to be amazing and could confirm many of the assumptions with my data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Feb, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/feb2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/feb2018/</guid>
      <description>February time! Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can get from my metrics. 😀
Books Note: I write a review for each book I read. You can find them on my Goodreads account.
I&amp;rsquo;m quite satisfied with my reading list for this month:

Five books read in a month and a 4.6 average rating. That&amp;rsquo;s what I call a good reading month.
The Art of Learning: A Journey in the Pursuit of Excellence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jan, 2018</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jan2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jan2018/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to write this post about my performance for the first month of the year. I think I will have some great news at the end of this post, related to my expenses.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started! 😀
Books I decided to listen to my podcasts this month, so I did not hear that many audiobooks. The only book I read this month was a physical book:

Hiding in unnatural happiness is a book I received from a monk in York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Year in Review (with metrics!)</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/2017/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, this post will be HUGE
TL;DR: It was a great year and I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to see the metrics and notice everything I accomplished.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I posted my yearly review publicly but as I&amp;rsquo;m doing monthly posts of my stats, it makes sense to do an annual review as well.
I do yearly reviews since around 2005 but I never post them publicly. I also write down my goals for the next year, so I can review them in the last week of the year (like I did some weeks ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Dec, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/dec2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/dec2017/</guid>
      <description>Came back from a travel last month and just packed my stuff to travel again this month. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it affected my performance.
Books I was traveling this month, so as usual, I&amp;rsquo;m not reading/listening to audiobooks because I prefer to focus on the place I&amp;rsquo;m visiting. For this reason, I did not finish any book this month.
With that said, it is the first time I have 4 books on my reading list at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Nov, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/nov2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/nov2017/</guid>
      <description>Came back from a travel last month and just packed my stuff to travel again this month. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it affected my performance.
Books 
Read three books this month. My first book of H.P. Lovecraft, called At the mountains of madness was one of them. It was an interesting experience to read it. I also read about minimalism just to realize that I&amp;rsquo;m a minimalism since forever. If you like minimalism I also recommend to listen to their podcast and read their website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Oct, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/oct2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/oct2017/</guid>
      <description>This month was very unusual because I was traveling through Portugal and Spain for work and tourism, so it will probably affect my stats a lot. With that said, let&amp;rsquo;s see how it is. 😄
Books I read some pages from Elixir in Action, but unfortunately did not finish any book this month. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t read that much when traveling, so it&amp;rsquo;s sad but expected. 😞
Articles As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m using that same export file from Pocket and the same script to calculate the amount of articles I read:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for sep, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/sep2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/sep2017/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s already the end of October and I could not manage to post my stats from September but I have a good reason for that (which you will read about in the next month 😉).
Books 
What Doesn’t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength is a book that describes what the human body can do if trained for it. The writing process is not so good for my taste, sometimes it looks like a memoir, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s non-fiction&amp;hellip; but the message it passes is really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Aug, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/aug2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/aug2017/</guid>
      <description>September is here, time to review my stats for August, 2017.
Books 
This is my personal record of books read in one single month. 7 freaking books. 😱
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with two small books I read. Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Audiobooks for Dogs and Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog. These two books were free on Audible for Dogs, so I decided to give them a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jul, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jul2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jul2017/</guid>
      <description>Okay, here we go for the first full month working in my new job. :)
Books 
This month I read Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman, which was recommended by the other Doisters. It&amp;rsquo;s a great book by the guy who built the company Patagonia, a bootstrapped company, from scratch. Their way of thinking looks a lot like the way we think at Doist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jun, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jun2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jun2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m ready to review my stats for June and share them with you! Are you? Hope so! :D
Books 
Last month I read Deep Work again because I was preparing to work for a new company. The new company is Doist, but this is a topic for a another post. It proved to be a great asset, as they also recommend reading it. From their reading list I also took The score takes care of itself and Start with Why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for May, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/may2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/may2017/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again for my stats for the last month. :)
Books 
I will start a in a new company this month, so I decided to re-read Deep Work (I really recommend this one). This book is just great for everyone who wants to focus and do the hard work. It has everything to do with my new work schedule. The book about Elon Musk was a good reading as well, this guy has some great ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for April, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/apr2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/apr2017/</guid>
      <description>This was not a good month. I spent most of the time sick, recovering from what may be a Labyrinthitis. I still have to confirm that, but I&amp;rsquo;m in slow motion for a while.
But anyways, let&amp;rsquo;s go to the collected data.
Books Books for this month:

&amp;ldquo;Einstein no Brasil&amp;rdquo; (Einstein in Brazil) is a physical book I borrowed from a friend and The Art of The Lord of the Rings I have in my shelf (as a good LotR fan).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for March, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/mar2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/mar2017/</guid>
      <description>Back to work this month. :)
After one month vacation, I got back to my routine and got some good results this month.
Books Added three more books to the list:

I have to note here that Mastery is one of the best books I ever read. Both Mindfulness in plain English and The Urban Monk are about meditation and how to live a minimalist life.
Articles I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to find a way to track the articles I read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for February, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/feb2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/feb2017/</guid>
      <description>February was an atypical month because I was on vacation. :)
Much of my stats will reflect my travel around Europe. But no coding was done during this trip.
Books Continuing my goal to read 30 books this year, I read two books this month:

I had plans to visit Amsterdam and Oxford during my travel. Because of that I decided to read the story of Kullervo, which mention a lot about J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for January, 2017</title>
      <link>https://pothix.com/jan2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pothix.com/jan2017/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of a series that will show all the data I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting during the month. One of my goals this year is to track everything possible. These posts will help me to analyze all the data and may extract something for me.
This is not a new idea, I&amp;rsquo;m inspired by posts like this from Matthew of truevalhalla.com.
Books My goal is to read 30 books this year, so I must have an average of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
