<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats on PotHix</title>
    <link>http://pothix.com/tags/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stats on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 | Follow on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mgjohansen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mgjohansen/hucore.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hucore theme&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; ♥</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pothix.com/tags/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jul, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jul-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jul-2017/</guid>
      <description>Okay, here we go for the first full month working in my new job. :)
Books 
This month I read Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman, which was recommended by the other Doisters. It&amp;rsquo;s a great book by the guy who built the company Patagonia, a bootstrapped company, from scratch. Their way of thinking looks a lot like the way we think at Doist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jun, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jun-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jun-2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m ready to review my stats for June and share them with you! Are you? Hope so! :D
Books 
Last month I read Deep Work again because I was preparing to work for a new company. The new company is Doist, but this is a topic for a another post. It proved to be a great asset, as they also recommend reading it. From their reading list I also took The score takes care of itself and Start with Why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for May, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again for my stats for the last month. :)
Books 
I will start a in a new company this month, so I decided to re-read Deep Work (I really recommend this one). This book is just great for everyone who wants to focus and do the hard work. It has everything to do with my new work schedule. The book about Elon Musk was a good reading as well, this guy has some great ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for April, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-apr-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-apr-2017/</guid>
      <description>This was not a good month. I spent most of the time sick, recovering from what may be a Labyrinthitis. I still have to confirm that, but I&amp;rsquo;m in slow motion for a while.
But anyways, let&amp;rsquo;s go to the collected data.
Books Books for this month:

&amp;ldquo;Einstein no Brasil&amp;rdquo; (Einstein in Brazil) is a physical book I borrowed from a friend and The Art of The Lord of the Rings I have in my shelf (as a good LotR fan).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for March, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-mar-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-mar-2017/</guid>
      <description>Back to work this month. :)
After one month vacation, I got back to my routine and got some good results this month.
Books Added three more books to the list:

I have to note here that Mastery is one of the best books I ever read. Both Mindfulness in plain English and The Urban Monk are about meditation and how to live a minimalist life.
Articles I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to find a way to track the articles I read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for February, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-feb-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-feb-2017/</guid>
      <description>February was an atypical month because I was on vacation. :)
Much of my stats will reflect my travel around Europe. But no coding was done during this trip.
Books Continuing my goal to read 30 books this year, I read two books this month:

I had plans to visit Amsterdam and Oxford during my travel. Because of that I decided to read the story of Kullervo, which mention a lot about J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for January, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jan-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jan-2017/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of a series that will show all the data I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting during the month. One of my goals this year is to track everything possible. These posts will help me to analyze all the data and may extract something for me.
This is not a new idea, I&amp;rsquo;m inspired by posts like this from Matthew of truevalhalla.com.
Books My goal is to read 30 books this year, so I must have an average of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>