<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>PotHix blog</title>
  <subtitle>@PotHix</subtitle>
  <id>http://pothix.com/</id>
  <link href="http://pothix.com/"/>
  <link href="http://pothix.com/feeds/feed_en.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-03-03T21:00:00-03:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>My presentation at FOSDEM 2017</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2017/03/04/my-presentation-at-fosdem-2017.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2017/03/04/my-presentation-at-fosdem-2017.html</id>
    <published>2017-03-03T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:28:49-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year my proposal to speak at &lt;a href="http://fosdem.org"&gt;FOSDEM&lt;/a&gt; was accepted and I
spoke at the Desktop devroom! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first talk in English, so I decided to do as many rehearsals as I
could. I was 8 in total, but as expected, it was still a little bit faster than
expected. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had 30 minutes to present and I did it in 26. I usually speak fast and this
presentation &lt;strong&gt;was made to be fast&lt;/strong&gt; because I had a lot of content to show in
30 minutes. So, &lt;strong&gt;it was FAST&lt;/strong&gt; (even more than what I was expecting). LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m OK with the final result. It&amp;rsquo;s far from being my best presentation but it&amp;rsquo;s
the first one in a different language, so it&amp;rsquo;s acceptable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They already published the video for my presentation, and it
is &lt;a href="https://video.fosdem.org/2017/K.4.401/"&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt; as
&lt;strong&gt;desktops_open_source_behind_web_request&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you want more information about the presentation, including the slides,
you may want to check its page
on
&lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2017/schedule/event/desktops_open_source_behind_web_request/"&gt;FOSDEM Schedule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOSDEM was great, can&amp;rsquo;t wait for the next! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Experiences of almost two years using colemak</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2015/10/08/experiences-of-almost-two-years-using-colemak.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2015/10/08/experiences-of-almost-two-years-using-colemak.html</id>
    <published>2015-10-07T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: I like colemak, and it is a &lt;em&gt;very good&lt;/em&gt; layout. I found some equivalent
pros and cons, so I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it to anyone without a little bit of
philosophy. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know &lt;a href="http://colemak.com/"&gt;Colemak&lt;/a&gt;, it is a keyboard layout
created to make the most used keys stay in the home row as well as make you
swipe between your right and left hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a
&lt;a href="http://www.patrick-wied.at/projects/heatmap-keyboard/"&gt;keyboard layouts heatmap&lt;/a&gt;
for you to understand the benefits of using a keyboard layout that was designed
to help you to be confortable and fast when typing instead of one that
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QWERTY"&gt;helping the operator to not jam the typewriter&lt;/a&gt;.
I tried some code (python), English and Portuguese texts and it looks almost the
same on the heatmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using Colemak since Dec, 25 of 2013 and here are come pros and cons that I
found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first con is that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to type fast on qwerty anymore, now I&amp;rsquo;m
typing as I never saw a qwerty layout before. The problem is that everyone uses
this crappy layout and sometimes you need to use it to write and it makes you
look like a granpa. The good part is that I almots don&amp;rsquo;t need to use qwerty, all
devices that belog to me I&amp;rsquo;ve changed to colemak (computers, cellphones and so
on), so I just need to use qwerty when I&amp;rsquo;m typing on other peoples devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pro is that my typing speed grew from an average of 75 WPM to almost 100
WPM. I need to consider that I also bought a Kinesis Advantage Pro;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/posts/almost-two-years-using-colemak-kinesis-df04aec3.jpg" title="Kinesis Advantage" alt="Kinesis advantage photo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without this keyboard I&amp;rsquo;m not that fast. Just tried
&lt;a href="http://10fastfingers.com/user/504663/"&gt;10fastfingers now and got 92 WPM&lt;/a&gt; using
my laptop&amp;rsquo;s keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another pro is that I really feel confortable using Colemak, you the same way as
being an experienced Vim user, looks like you don&amp;rsquo;t need to type so much. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, talking about Vim&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m an experienced Vim user, but Vim is totally
coupled with qwerty layout. I tried to remap some keys (like hjkl for example)
in order to keep using the home row to navigate but it was not very good. Totay
I&amp;rsquo;m just using plain colemak layout on Vim and it is not so good as it was on
qwerty. For this reason I decided to try a new editor and I&amp;rsquo;m using Emacs
now. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me at least a month to get back to my old typing speed, I was training
everyday on 10fastfinges to get used to the layout. In the beginning you may
feed some headaches because of the mind remapping. It&amp;rsquo;s not so easy to change
something that you thought was the only way of getting things done. It was a
great challenge for me and it just seems right, I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna use a keyboard
layout that was made to avoid jams on a typewriter, Jesus, we&amp;rsquo;re in 2015 and
there is not typewriters anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this post helps a lot of colemak newcommers and the only thing I could say
about my journey is that &lt;strong&gt;I would do it again if I could&lt;/strong&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OSCON 2015</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2015/07/27/oscon.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2015/07/27/oscon.html</id>
    <published>2015-07-26T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been at OSCON this year (thanks to
&lt;a href="http://locaweb.com.br"&gt;Locaweb&lt;/a&gt;) and this post will summarize my
impressions about the conference. I spoke at Locaweb Tech-Talks about it and
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1yR7aEIVJdznAASNvaNW0AjUDmgA5qvOstOHhSP1JLDM/pub?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=3000"&gt;you can find my slides
here&lt;/a&gt;
(in portuguese).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://oscon.com"&gt;OSCON (Open Source Conference)&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most
important open source conferences of our time and happened in Portland
this year as usual.  Portland is a great city, the one I liked the
most until now, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have high car traffic, MAX (the train) took
us for most of the places we wanted to know, nice people all over the
place, great convention center and a lot of other benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;July, 20&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference started at 9:00 am of July 20, 2015 with the first day of
tutorials. In the first day I followed the &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes tutorial&lt;/strong&gt; and it was cool.
I had the chance to talk with Google guys about it and try Google
Computing Engine, which was very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;July, 21&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day was filled with more tutorials and I chose RUST and Cassandra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;RUST&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was a good tutorial with a lot of exercises and good tips of the
language. I really liked it and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably give
&lt;a href="http://rust-lang.org/"&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; a try on the next months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Cassandra&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was expecting a different thing from this one. It was based on how
to use &lt;a href="http://cassandra.apache.org/"&gt;cassandra&lt;/a&gt;, create tables and so
on and I was expecting tips on how to create and scale it and maybe a
little bit about the caveats we may found on the way. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t
bad at all, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a little bit on how to use it and as a gift I
tried a little bit of spark as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of this day the Expo hall opened for everyone, cool things there
(including some T-shirts&amp;hellip; T-shirts everywhere).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;July, 22&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the conference begin! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with the keynotes at 9:00 and I would like to highlight one of them.
All keynotes &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL055Epbe6d5YhDchEvY3O4nIuSLYyrx7K"&gt;are avaiable on
youtube&lt;/a&gt;
btw. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Facebook open source at scale (Keynote)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to understand the open source culture behind these big
companies. It is really interesting to know that there are only &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt;
people to handle all the facebook open source process shocked me a
litte bit. They have a great open source review and publishing process
and all the softwares they release are running in their production
environment. So, why do they do open source software? Because it&amp;rsquo;s
good for the company, helps them to make better software and bring
smart people to work with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the multiple sessions started, a lot of great subjects in the agenda
and you have to choose one (!!!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Roller Coaster Tycoon with genetic algorithms and Go&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker
&lt;a href="https://kev.inburke.com/kevin/roller-coaster-tycoon-genetic-algorithms/"&gt;Kevin Burke&lt;/a&gt;
spoke about his hobbie of playing with
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RollerCoaster_Tycoon"&gt;roller coaster tycoon&lt;/a&gt;
game maps with Go and Genetic Algorithms in order to create de best
roller coaster ever! It is not there already but the presention was
really cool to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You type &amp;ldquo;google.com&amp;rdquo; into your browser bar and press enter: What happens next?&amp;ldquo;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker for this talk is
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/mathie"&gt;Graeme Mathieson&lt;/a&gt;. I was planning to
spoke about it before de last edition of
&lt;a href="http://devinsampa.com.br/"&gt;DevInSampa&lt;/a&gt; (2012? Btw, it could happen
again&amp;hellip;) but didn&amp;rsquo;t had the guts to make it yet and there it is,
someone made it before me. The pace of the presentation was not good
but the content was cool (it was his first presentation). At least it
made me think more about this topic and &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll try to speak
about it soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the lunch I tried to attend to &lt;strong&gt;Evolution of information
security threats&lt;/strong&gt; presentation but the room was full, so decided to
go to &lt;a href="http://matrix.org/"&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; guys presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Fixing the fragmentation problem for real-time communications&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matrix&amp;rsquo;s is really interesting, the main idea is to make a
protocol for messages, just like the email protocols do for our
email, we may use our client and store our own email but it is not
possible with today&amp;rsquo;s messaging like hangouts, whatsapp, telegram,
skype and so on. They had a live demo piloting a quadricopter via
chat, it was really cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;High adventures in sniffing my own metadata&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker is &lt;a href="http://matrix.org/"&gt;Josh Deprez&lt;/a&gt; from Google
Australia. He described his work using a Go program (home made) to
analize his own internet traffic and which information he got on
it. The presentation itself was cool to follow but the discoveries
wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much interesting. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Building the $9 computer, or how I learned to stop worrying and love embedded Linux&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the
&lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1598272670/chip-the-worlds-first-9-computer"&gt;C.H.I.P project&lt;/a&gt;
owner &lt;strong&gt;Dave Rauchwerk&lt;/strong&gt; speaking about the story behind the
project. This guy is hilarious and a real hacker, he made a gif camera
just for the lulz and tried a product with it!  Unfortunately it was
too expensive, to be viable for selling, so he decided to create
C.H.I.P to make the camera cheaper and C.H.I.P became the product by
itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Continuous delivery and large microservice architectures: Reflections on Ioncannon&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last one was really interesting &lt;strong&gt;Kevin Scaldeferri&lt;/strong&gt; from
&lt;a href="http://newrelic.com"&gt;New Relic&lt;/a&gt; spoke about how they grown from a big
and monolythic Rails application to 250 microservices. In short, it
was a mess in the beginning, a lot of techlologies and deploy tools
until they organized and found a standard for the language and deploy
tools, it is really better now, but the old Rails app is still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;July, 23&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new day with an typical American breakfast at Denny&amp;rsquo;s and starting
with keynotes at 9:00 AM again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Making architecture matter (Keynote)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.martinfowler.com/"&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; spoke about architecture
in general, there was some good quotes. One of the arguments that
really make sense is that the today&amp;rsquo;s &amp;quot;Architect&amp;rdquo; is that guy that
don&amp;rsquo;t write code (!?). How can a professional that doesn&amp;rsquo;t write code
talk about how to write code? Another good point was about the user
perspective about architecture it can&amp;rsquo;t see it anywhere but still need
to pay for it! We need to argue using economic principles in order to
be able to create a good architecture for our softwares because
economics always win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of examples of products that were the market leader for their
segment and it could not evolve anymore to the point that it was swallowed by
another competitor. This is a sign of bad architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;You code like a sysadm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hm&amp;hellip; This talk was not so good but it left a message for everyone:
&amp;ldquo;Bad code is still better than no code at all&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And obviously: Good code is better than bad code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, instead of not doing something because you think your code is not good
enough, do it and improve as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;When Performance Counts: C++ in the 21st Century&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker threw some good arguments that haven&amp;rsquo;t came to my mind until this
day: &amp;ldquo;Why is C++ getting more attention these days?&amp;rdquo;, we have C++11 being
created and more people talking about it. In his words, the world was not in
need for performance anymore, we had big computers and most of time the other
languages (java, in his examples) are doing a good job to create what is needed
without the need to manage memory by hand. But today we have some other
hardwares that need this performance back, like tablets, mobile devices, cloud
applications that pays based on cpu time and so on. Good catch man! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Creating an open source office: Lessons from Twitter&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a bad choice based on the presentation title and changed rooms as fast as
I could to follow this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some notes on the presentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure projects have owners or give it to the community: this is the
twitter example of
&lt;a href="http://getbootstrap.com/2.3.2/"&gt;Twitter bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always say Thank you for your project collaborators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lessons from &lt;a href="http://mesos.apache.org/"&gt;mesos&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple uses mesos for Siri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source foundations force good pactices on you (incubated aurora)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lessons for &lt;a href="https://github.com/twitter/twemcache"&gt;twencache&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep track with the upstream if you fork something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share your code with some peers to gauge interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open source project with collaborators is better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good lesson that I got from this presentation is that community
doesn&amp;rsquo;t come for free. Companies like Twitter have their own community
managers, conference speakers, conference organizers, documentation
writers and their developers to make everyone engaged with the
project. Throw something on github and expect collaboration is not the
best idea for OSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your employess may become open source celebrities sometimes, and if they became
popular they may leave the company. It is not so good for the company but the
same popular projects may attact new talents as well. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Troll&amp;rsquo;s are everywhere and youy will always hear that your project is stupid and
useless. The best way to deal with it is to take it as a compliment because
people care enough to say it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Mesos the OS for your datacenter&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Greenberg from &lt;a href="http://www.twosigma.com/"&gt;Two sigma&lt;/a&gt; spoke about how they
built their own &lt;a href="http://mesos.apache.org/"&gt;mesos&lt;/a&gt; framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mesos has a high level API to do things and you don&amp;rsquo;t need to care about the
resources. It provide an algorith called
&lt;a href="https://www.cs.berkeley.edu/~alig/papers/drf.pdf"&gt;DRF&lt;/a&gt; for a fair allocation of
resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several built frameworks for mesos like Marathon, Aurora, Jenkins and
some more. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to build your own framework (netflix, twitter, apple and
two sigma have it). A good reason to build your own is to deal with some exotic
workload, this default frameworks are built for small tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, mesos is the future and I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be looking for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;July, 24&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the last day of the conference and it started with 3 keynotes. After the
keynotes there was two sessions more and the conference ending at the main ballroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Hacking Conway&amp;rsquo;s Lay (Keynote)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;organizations which design systems &amp;hellip; are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structures of these organizations
—M. Conway[2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When rebuilding a system it&amp;rsquo;s really important to think about your team because
it will be part of its architecture like conway&amp;rsquo;s law says. So when a decision
is made to build a new system without changing the way people work you will face
the same problems the other system had but with a different code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you&amp;rsquo;re using microservices but your team is still monolithic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve technical problems, you often have to go outside the technical domain.
Raffi Krikorian&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good points that ended the presentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not all about the code!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small teams can do big things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full stack teams keeps your architecture flexible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t fight Conway&amp;rsquo;s Law, work with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of good lessons learnt from this one. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Build a botnet?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker (&lt;a href="http://fossetcon.org"&gt;Bryan Smith&lt;/a&gt;) did a great (and funny :P)
presentation around the topic. And some things are really scary when speaking
about botnets. The most scary thing for me was its price, you can use a botnet
for an hour spending only $5&amp;hellip; it is really low and probably will get a service
out of business for that time. There are some softwares avalable if you want to
build your own botnet these days (accorting to Bryan, if you want to build a
botnet you&amp;rsquo;re probably a scumbag&amp;hellip; LOL), here are some of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;citadel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kreios C2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andromeda V2.6 - leaked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaiten IRC bot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SDBot - GPL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DSNX Bots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q8 Bots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll not post links here but you can google them if you really want it. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most funny part of the presentation was its end when the speaker laptop got
rebooted when trying to bring the botnet up. LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Freedom and responsibility @Netflix: Centralized team in a decentralized world&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best presentations of the
conference. &lt;a href="http://www.mikemcgarr.com/about.html"&gt;Mike McGarr&lt;/a&gt; spoke
about his team (tools team) role at
&lt;a href="http://techblog.netflix.com/"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; and the hacker culture there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the team roles is to increase the rate of innovation and reduce
the impact of change by providing good tools for the other teams. Their clients
are the other teams engineers, it&amp;rsquo;s not a simple internal system it&amp;rsquo;s a product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix has a
&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/reed2001/culture-1798664"&gt;great culture&lt;/a&gt; and each
team as a subset of this culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix has a lot of good tools but the engineers may choose to not use it and
build their own in case it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix their problems. For this reason there are
4 deploy tools running on Netflix actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have no Ops team, you build it, you support it! And in order to remove part
of the constant interruptions, the team uses a &amp;ldquo;responder rotation&amp;rdquo; when each
time (day, week, month?) a new engineer will be in charge of solving problems
and helping the other teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They (like many of us) don&amp;rsquo;t like ticket systems, but they use it anyway (like
many of us?). For this case the tip is: Make creating a ticket easy, minimize
fraction by making it as easy and fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackatons are made between the team in order to keep the innovation process
flowing and making space for innovation. Another good thing to think about is to
always hire beyond your needs, it makes more space for innovation (not all
people working on day to day tasks) and it will be really helpful when the
project is on fire and the team needs more intensity on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication is really important for the teams and they do not set a limitation
for important communications like framework versions and DC migrations. For this
task they use hipchat, email, banners and everything that may call the
engineers&amp;rsquo; attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Situation normal, everything must change&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the last keynote and maybe the best one, and I highly recommend you to
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty6pOVEc3bA"&gt;watch it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Wardley used the fact that OSCON is moving to speak about situation
awareness and what could happen when you&amp;rsquo;re not prepared for a new thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His arguments are that we&amp;rsquo;re using the wrong maps to try to understand our
problems. In business we use &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SWOT_analysis"&gt;SWOT&lt;/a&gt;
for example, which is really bad to understand to understand the whole picture,
it was really funny to see his comparisons with
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Thermopylae"&gt;the battle of the 300&lt;/a&gt;
using a SWAT map instead of land map. LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker shows some maps he uses for his business, and it looks really better
than just a SWOT. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I really recommend you
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty6pOVEc3bA"&gt;watch this talk&lt;/a&gt;. I liked it. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best conference I ever attended. Everything was great: hotel, Portland
Conference Center, the city in general, the food, the conference content and so
on. It definitely worth the 14 hours plane travel to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would live in a city like Portland, it is one of the best cities I ever
visited. I&amp;rsquo;m sad to know that the next OSCON will happen in Austin instead of
Portland. :(&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New layout of PotHix blog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2015/05/25/new-layout-of-pothix-blog.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2015/05/25/new-layout-of-pothix-blog.html</id>
    <published>2015-05-24T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new blog layout of PotHix.com! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that the time has came to change not just the layout but the blog
engine as well. I&amp;rsquo;m now using middleman instead of wordpress. Just to be clear,
I don&amp;rsquo;t think wordpress is not good at all, but I want to publish static files
instead of keeping the wordpress &amp;ldquo;infrastructure&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve divided into 3 feeds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only english posts: &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/EnglishPotHix"&gt;http://feeds.feedburner.com/EnglishPotHix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All posts: &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/PotHix"&gt;http://feeds.feedburner.com/PotHix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts related to programming or technology in genenal: &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/PotHixTech"&gt;http://feeds.feedburner.com/PotHixTech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that&amp;rsquo;s it! Hope you enjoy the new layout (now responsive!) and get in touch! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Golang and 1.2 version performance improvement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2013/12/03/golang-and-1-2-version-performance-improvement.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2013/12/03/golang-and-1-2-version-performance-improvement.html</id>
    <published>2013-12-02T22:00:00-02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Go last month and I really liked to work with the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project I&amp;rsquo;m working on is dead simple and just retrieves metrics and save on
a redis server (the data will be analyzed by a different project that I&amp;rsquo;m
working on). So I have 15 goroutines retrieving data constantly and I&amp;rsquo;m using
just two native threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some CPU profiling on the code using my current machine for Golang 1.1.2
and 1.2 and the results can be seen below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golang 1.1.2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    (pprof) top10
    Total: 188701 samples
    137454  72.8%   72.8%   137454  72.8% crypto/des.permuteBlock
    44032   23.3%   96.2%   169187  89.7% crypto/des.feistel
    3750    2.0%    98.2%   184544  97.8% crypto/des.cryptBlock
    823     0.4%    98.6%   185650  98.4% crypto/cipher.(*cbcDecrypter).CryptBlocks
    290     0.2%    98.8%      290   0.2% encoding/binary.bigEndian.PutUint64
    232     0.1%    98.9%      232   0.1% encoding/binary.bigEndian.Uint64
    227     0.1%    99.0%      227   0.1% crypto/sha1.block
    215     0.1%    99.1%      267   0.1% encoding/json.state1
    207     0.1%    99.2%      430   0.2% encoding/json.checkValid
    178     0.1%    99.3%      398   0.2% encoding/json.nextValue

    # top command result
    PID USER      PR  NI  VIRT    RES      SHR S  %CPU %MEM    TIME+  COMMAND
    18115 pothix    20   0  871800  67888   3932 S 188.8  1.7  12:40.08 crebain

    # A snapshot of the processors
    %Cpu0  :100.0 us,  0.0 sy,  0.0 ni,  0.0 id,  0.0 wa,  0.0 hi,  0.0 si,  0.0 st
    %Cpu1  : 95.0 us,  3.0 sy,  0.0 ni,  2.0 id,  0.0 wa,  0.0 hi,  0.0 si,  0.0 st
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golang 1.2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    (pprof) top10
    Total: 6894 samples
    1686    24.5%   24.5%   1686    24.5%   crypto/aes.decryptBlockGo
    1299    18.8%   43.3%   3093    44.9%   crypto/cipher.(*cbcDecrypter).CryptBlocks
    471     6.8%    50.1%   1062    15.4%   encoding/json.checkValid
    420     6.1%    56.2%   541     7.8%    encoding/json.state1
    359     5.2%    61.4%   359     5.2%    crypto/sha1.block
    305     4.4%    65.9%   838     12.2%   encoding/json.nextValue
    245     3.6%    69.4%   274     4.0%    syscall.Syscall
    230     3.3%    72.7%   230     3.3%    encoding/json.stateBeginValue
    186     2.7%    75.4%   225     3.3%    encoding/json.stateEndValue
    156     2.3%    77.7%   156     2.3%    runtime.memmove

    top command result
    PID USER      PR  NI    VIRT    RES    SHR S  %CPU %MEM     TIME+ COMMAND
    20534 pothix    20   0  598428  51584   3532 S  12.9  1.3   0:03.76 crebain

    %Cpu0  : 12.1 us,  5.1 sy,  5.1 ni, 72.7 id,  5.1 wa,  0.0 hi,  0.0 si,  0.0 st
    %Cpu1  : 20.0 us,  4.0 sy,  0.0 ni, 75.0 id,  1.0 wa,  0.0 hi,  0.0 si,  0.0 st
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What an improvement! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that this application may not be the best example to compare Go with a
different language because it depends of a third application (that is my
bottleneck BTW) and Ruby perform as good as the new version but I really liked
to give Go a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go language has a lot of interesting ideas and it is growing fast.
Looks like it is a good idea of language for some of my projects, welcome Golang!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Game Network Programming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2013/07/15/game-network-programming.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2013/07/15/game-network-programming.html</id>
    <published>2013-07-14T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: This post was about my presentation with Diego Souza
(vulgo Marciano) about Game network programming. I was studying and reading
Quake source just for fun and decided to learn more about game networking in
general, so I decided to prepare this presentation to show other people what
I’ve learned. You can see the full video (portuguese only, sorry) and the slides
below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portuguese&lt;/strong&gt;: Eu e o Diego Souza (vulgo Marciano) fizemos uma palestra sobre
  Game network programming tanto na Locaweb como no Guru-SP. A palestra que
  fizemos no Guru-SP foi gravada pelo Agaelebe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://a.blip.tv/api.swf#hOdBg5PuBQI" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E aqui estão os slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="http://blip.tv/play/hOdBg5PuBQI.html?p=1" width="550" height="443" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Como eu estava na vibe de jogos desde o começo do ano passado, eu estava lendo
os posts sobre o código do Quake. Quem me conhece sabe que eu trabalho na equipe
de IaaS da Locaweb e lá nós lidamos com bastante coisa de redes e eu curto o
assunto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversando com o Diego sobre os algoritmos de redes utilizados no Quake nós
decidimos juntar as pesquisas dele sobre os protocolos TCP e UDP com o que eu li
sobre a implementação dos algoritmos nos jogos para poder fazer uma palestra
legal de game network programming, e assim saiu essa palestra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lá nós apresentamos os algoritmos de alguns jogos como o Quake, Age of Empires e
outros não tão conhecidos, mostrando as soluções legais que eles chegaram e
quais foram os maiores desafios que eles encontraram para resolver os problemas
de latencia e necessidade de velocidade. O Diego focou mais na parte de
otimização dos algoritmos e flags que podem ser alteradas para melhorar o
comportamento da rede.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essa foi uma palestra muito legal de fazer e aprendi bastante no processo
também! Se tiverem dúvidas postem aí nos comentários. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A lifestyle</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2012/09/10/a-lifestyle.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2012/09/10/a-lifestyle.html</id>
    <published>2012-09-09T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just a transcript from &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vlZ4ONTb9i0&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, 
but it reflects my way of life at this stage of my life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
24
25
26
27
28
29
30
31
32
33
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;We believe in going our own way,no matter which way the rest of the world is going.

We believe in bucking the system that’s built to smash individuals as bugs on a windshield.

Some of us believe in the man upstairs.All of us believe in sticking in to the man down here.

We believe in the sky and we don’t believe in the sunroof.

We believe in freedom.

We believe in dust,tumbleweeds,buffalo,mountain ranges and riding off into the sunset.

We believe in saddle bags and we believe that cowboys had it right.

We believe in refusing to knuckle under to anyone.

We believe in wearing black,because it doesn’t show any dirt or weakness.

We believe the world is going soft and we’re not going along with it.

We believe in motorcycle rallies that last a week.

We believe in road side attractions,gas station,hot dogs and finding what’s over the next.

We believe in rumbling engines,pistons the size of garbage cans,fuel tanks designed in 1936, freight-train size headlights,chrome and custom paint.

We believe in flames and skulls.

We believe life is what you make it,and we make it one hell of a ride.

We believe the machine you sit on can tell the world exactly where you stand.

We don’t care what everyone else believes.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Javascript and Gamedev discussion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2012/09/02/javascript-and-gamedev-discussion.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2012/09/02/javascript-and-gamedev-discussion.html</id>
    <published>2012-09-01T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read the &lt;a href="http://www.phoboslab.org/log/2012/08/letter-to-john-carmack"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;
from &lt;a href="http://impactjs.com"&gt;Impact engine&lt;/a&gt; creator 
&lt;a href="http://www.phoboslab.org/"&gt;Dominic&lt;/a&gt; where he shows an email he sent to 
&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack"&gt;John Carmack&lt;/a&gt;
about his opinions on Javascript expressed on 
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wt-iVFxgFWk"&gt;his keynote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dominic is trying to show that Javascript is not a good language
to develop the next AAA game but it is awesome to make simple
games and have it easily available to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of negative comments on the post (I really don&amp;rsquo;t
know why) but some good ones too. One of the good comments was
written by John Carmack himself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was just explaining his point of view about Javascript and game
development, and said what we already know and is obvious (right?)
that javascript is not so fast to perform some kind of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people are dreaming that Javascript is so fast as C in some
cases but we know that it is not true for a whole game and the
native version will always run faster. But you should say that the 
web (and the computers at all) are evolving each day, so the javascript
performance, but the native version is evolving as well and javascript
will always be some steps back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John&amp;rsquo;s comment is really interesting because he knows that javascript
has its benefits but he also knows that some of the real problems they 
are solving at &lt;a href="http://idsoftware.com"&gt;Id Software&lt;/a&gt;
will not be solved efficiently using Javascript (and a browser)
as the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion for the discussion is what I was expecting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Choose the right tool for the right job&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you doing a little 2D game? Try javascript, 
and define the platforms for it to run. But if your game really needs 
performance because you need to have the most impressive graphics,
you need to go native.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously you should choose a lot of different languages / platforms as
well, you just need to decide which one is better for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the right tool. That&amp;rsquo;s it, no silver bullet. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kernel compiling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2012/07/23/kernel-compiling.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2012/07/23/kernel-compiling.html</id>
    <published>2012-07-22T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I bought an Acer notebook to use Linux again (I sold my mac, I
have a post about it but in portuguese) I started to compile my own
kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons for the decision:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a hardware that works better with the newer kernels.
I really want to understand the linux kernel better.
As Judas Priest sings on Painkiller song: “I’m living on the eeeeeedge”. LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How to proceed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some steps to follow when compiling a new kernel for your
Linux box:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clone the kernel repository with git, I made it using the Github url:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;git clone git://github.com/torvalds/linux.git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy your .config file to the linux folder. If your distro have the
&amp;ldquo;Enable config.gz&amp;rdquo; flag enabled (most distros have it) you can use the
generated config as a base for your new compiled version:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;zcat /proc/config.gz &amp;gt; linux/.config
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a functional config file (it was running on the
stock kernel right? ￼ ), just cd do the kernel folder and run make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cd linux
make
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process take about 40 minutes to finish on my i7, with 4GB of RAM
and SSD, running with -j4, to use all the 4 cores. Obviously the time
to finish will depend on what it will need to compile (defined on the
.config file) and the processing power of your machine. You can
improve this compiling time but I’ll talk more about it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the compiling time to prepare the mkinitcpio file for the
installation. On my archlinux box I have created a file named
git.preset on /etc/mkinitcpio.d/ directory with the following content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;ALL_config="/etc/mkinitcpio.conf"
ALL_kver="/boot/vmlinuz-git"

PRESETS=('default')

default_image="/boot/initramfs-git.img"
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that you’ll need to change your bootloader conf a bit. I’m using
grub (not grub2 yet) which makes the setup really easy! Just change
your /boot/grub/menu.lst and add something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;title  Git Kernel
root   (hd0,0)
kernel /vmlinuz-git root=/dev/sda2 ro quiet acpi_backlight=vendor init=/bin/systemd
initrd /initramfs-git.img
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m using systemd to init and I need to define the
acpi_backlight to make my hardware to work properly, but probably
you’ll not need these parameters. If you’re using grub, you may find
useful to copy the other configuration of the same file and change
what needs to me changed (title and initrd).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the compilation ends and your mkinitcpio file is ready you can
continue the process by generating the modules for your kernel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo make modules_install
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will create a folder with the compiled modules on
/lib/modules. After that, just copy the generated image file to the
boot directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo cp arch/x86_64/boot/bzImage /boot/vmlinuz-git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And create the initial randisk environment for your preset using
mkinitcpio:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo mkinitcpio -p git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONE! Your kernel is compiled and ready to boot! Just restart you
computer and choose the new item on the boot menu! ￼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;.config tunning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, your new kernel is running perfectly (I hope so…It’s a release
candidate, we never know what may happen :P), but you’ll want to go
deeply into the kernel options and improve the compiling time and the
disk space for the kernel, so lets tune the .config file to be
specific to our hardware!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING&lt;/strong&gt;: It will take a lot of time to get a good configuration
and you’ll not receive so much benefit from it, but it will be
fun. I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s get started! Go to the linux kernel directory and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;make menuconfig
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fun part starts here because you’ll be seeing an awesome curses
screen with a lot of menus and submenus about a lot of things that you
never heard about, but no despair! Some things you already know, like
your processor for example! If you have an Intel processor is safe to
remove all the AMD related configurations from the .config file and
probably add some intel ones as built in (and vice versa).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things you need to have in mind when starting to buil your own
kernel configuration is that you really need to know what hardware
you’re running on your machine. This is really interesting because we
don’t care so much about some pieces of hardware nowadays, and you’ll
need to care about it if you want to build your own configuration
because you can’t remove these modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good way to start is boot with the stock configuration, run lsmod
and backup this into a file. These modules should not be removed
because they are making your machine to work as it is working now, but
some of them should be marked as builtin into the kernel. I saw some
recommendations to not include the WIFI driver as builtin to avoid
some pre-load problems, so I’m keeping my WIFI driver as a module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some cool (but not so useful) parts can be found on “General Setup”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default hostname – This configuration will be specific, so name your
machine!  Local version – Append an string to the kernel release I
can’t help you so much on this journey because each hardware has its
own dependencies and corner cases, so you will need to compile and see
how it’s going to fit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Some tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning to customize your configuration file I really
recommend to use a versioning control (like git) to keep tracking of
your file because you’ll need to revert some changes sometimes
(believe me) and git will help you to make this process less painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are weird people (me for writting this and you to be interesting in
doing the same thing) but this process will help you to understand
some interesting things about your operating system and feel that
there is no magic happening there, this is just code that you can
change if you want. I was planning to end this article with “there is
no advantage on making this at all” but after remembering all the
process I think that I learned a lot, so it is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old comments by: Darkside | Not available anymore. :(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Simlinks for ruby on Debian Squeeze</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2012/07/17/simlinks-for-ruby-on-debian-squeeze.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2012/07/17/simlinks-for-ruby-on-debian-squeeze.html</id>
    <published>2012-07-16T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every time we need to deploy a new Ruby application on top of Debian Squeeze
we need to fix some Ruby depedencies to make the application work as it should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happens because we&amp;rsquo;re building using rvm instead of the packaged version
of ruby, but it needed to be that way in order to use our old build server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it documented here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;ln -s /usr/lib/libruby-1.9.1.so.1.9.1 /usr/lib/libruby.so.1.9
ln -s /usr/bin/rake1.9.1 /usr/bin/rake
ln -s /usr/bin/ruby1.9.1 /usr/bin/ruby
ln -s /usr/bin/gem1.9.1 /usr/bin/gem
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that run &lt;code&gt;ldconfig&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should make the common ruby commands work again. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Translated Rubylearning presentation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2009/04/10/translated-rubylearning-presentation.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2009/04/10/translated-rubylearning-presentation.html</id>
    <published>2009-04-09T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I promised, here goes my presentation! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally i finished to translate all the presentation! Watched the
video a lot of times, pausing and playing to write all I said
translating to english. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I had a big help from my friend
&lt;a href="http://vgoff.blogspot.com/" title="The Red Gem of programming"&gt;Victor Goff&lt;/a&gt;,
that corrected all my grammar errors and typos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m posting below all i have about the presentation, slides from
&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/PotHix/what-is-and-how-does-work-rubylearningorg-1257258" title="Presentation at Slideshare"&gt;Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;
and a translation pasted here, but you can find the
&lt;a href="http://docs.google.com/Doc?id=dgd96k6n_45fkh4q5g9" title="Translated Speach at Google Docs"&gt;translation at Google Docs&lt;/a&gt; too. &lt;strong&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/strong&gt; :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/ftgGS74G9EZF6F" width="425" height="355" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Words&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Willian Molinari as Marcelo said, I participated of 3rd
Batch of Rubylearning at the beginning of the last year. Since the
finish of the course I was an Assistant Teacher, and i&amp;rsquo;m a Mentor
since the beginning of this year.  I attempt to show to you a bit of
what Rubylearning is and how does it work, what is the course idea.
It is a short presentation, you will see that I&amp;rsquo;ll &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; with the
content, but the presentation idea is to show you a bit of what
RubyLearning courses are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slide1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fist, lets start with &amp;ldquo;What is Rubylearning?&amp;rdquo; The course itself is
Rubylearning.org, and Rubylearning is divided into Blog, Website and
courses.
Blog is where Satish post some of his interviews with Ruby community
guys like Matt of Merb project or Dr. Nic. And on blog have other cool
posts too.
On Website Satish maintain a Ruby tutorial, a Ruby Book and post other ruby
contents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on Rubylearning.org the course happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slide2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer the question &amp;ldquo;What is Rubyleraning.org&amp;rdquo; I was helped by the other
teachers of Rubylearning. One of the good answers was made by George
Thompson, this guy that you see in the large photo. After telling a
funny joke, saying that Rubylearning is for everything since it will &amp;ldquo;allow you to grow wings to fly&amp;rdquo; and will &amp;ldquo;help you in the bedroom&amp;rdquo;
He gives these topics to speak about.&lt;br&gt;
The first thing is that Rubylearning is for everyone that has an interest in
Ruby, if you are a experienced professional, or just learning now, Rubylearning is here to help you.&lt;br&gt;
It is a framework to your first steps with Ruby, so you will not depend just
from Google or online tutorials, on Rubylearning you will have more people
to help you to participate and discuss your answers and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Rubylearning is not just for who are starting with Ruby. If you work with
Ruby for a long time, you can participate to help the students that are
starting, returning to the community what you received. And you can participate
with other Rubylearning intermediate courses (Rubylearning doesn&amp;rsquo;t have just
the Core course, we have other courses for those who already have
knowledge of Ruby)&lt;br&gt;
And of course&amp;hellip;Rubylearning is a place to have fun! To code for fun, to
know different people of other countries, or maybe of your country, and you
didn&amp;rsquo;t know that this person was programming on this language.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rubyleraning is based on Moodle, as you can see, the image is strange
here, but the first screenshot is the screen after you sign up, and you
can see all the courses that you can subscribe to, and below you can see the
screen inside the course, all the material is divided by blocks, the forums and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More interesting informations about Rubylearning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the declared winner of shorty awards in education category.&lt;br&gt;
Unfortunately we couldn&amp;rsquo;t participate of ceremony in USA because only Satish
can participate in the ceremony, and the price to travel from India (Satish is Indian) to USA could not cover the
costs&amp;hellip;But anyway, we are the winners!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of participants get over 7200 mark, and maybe now we already pass
the 7500 mark, because this information is from 1 month ago, more or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another cool thing, more than 40% of Rubylearning participants are from
Brazil, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have arguments to say: &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t participate, because
the course have people that from other countries and i don&amp;rsquo;t speak english
very well&amp;rdquo;, because always you will find a Brazillian to help you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And who is the main teacher? Who is behind Rubylearning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satish Talim, as I said, lives in India. He is a programmer, teacher,
consultant, working on some companies at India and USA, is speaker and has
more than 30 years of experience with I.T. He has these two domains:
Rubylearning.org and rubylearning.com. On .org domain we have the course
and on Rubylearning.com is his site. And he have a personal website domain, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, if Satish is behind Rubylearning, who are these guys that help on
forums? So&amp;hellip; I asked to Satish by e-mail, because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about how he divide us.
The assistant teachers are people that come from the core course and
enjoyed the course, so they are invited to help, and whomever accept comes as
assistant teachers of the next core course to help on foruns, answering the
students that are having doubts and helping on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentors are experieced professionals that are working with I.T for a long
time and more time on Rubylearning, too. They help not only on Core course,
but on the other courses ( intermediate courses ) too.
The Patrons, this guys are on Rubylearning since rubylearning is coming to
be international, on the 2nd batch more or less, on the last months of
2007, and they have more time on rubylearning, so the way that Satish has
to classify teacher is time on rubylearning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For who is this course appropriate? Well&amp;hellip; Our focus is the people
that already know something about programming, some other language and
wants to know Ruby, and not those people that do not know how to
program and want to learn on Rubylearning, This is not our focus. Our
focus is to teach Ruby for who those have a notion about programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide9&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does Rubylearning work? Well&amp;hellip;The course is slotted into weekly study
material blocks. Every Saturday, Satish posts different sudy material with
important notes, so you can review quickly all you already read; Some
exercises, 10 or 5 exercises depending on how extensive is the material,
for you to solve and post on forums, to view the answers of teachers too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you have a method and you are using return to return the
variable on the PHP style for example, but can be other language, so
somebody replies to you saying that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to specify this
return because the Ruby language returns the last statement by
default, and so on&amp;hellip;  The Quiz, is for your own benefit, so you can
see if you learn all the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the Extras! The extras take to you some good material as links to good
content, a screencast related to the weekly study material, and others!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do quizzes work? As i said, Quiz is for your own benefit. A lot of
people are questioning me about the importance of quizzes on the course
participation, &amp;ldquo;if we don&amp;rsquo;t answer the quiz, are we kicked out of the
course&amp;rdquo; or we don&amp;rsquo;t receive the certificate. The quiz idea is auto-validation,
so after you read all the content, you will know with the quiz if you really
learn all you need to learn about that content, if you got a good result
with the quiz, you probably really learned this weeks content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide11&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is necessary be active on Foruns? Humm&amp;hellip;Yes! The main focus of
Rubylearning is the participation of everybody, so, if you really want to
get the best of the course you must to post your exercise answers, to
receive from more experienced people feedback about your solution. If you
don&amp;rsquo;t participate so much.. it&amp;rsquo;s okay too&amp;hellip;You just lost the chance to learn more and
more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide12&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the things that everybody speaks about&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;Ohhh&amp;hellip;The course
is in english, from India, i will talk nonsense words, i don&amp;rsquo;t speak
english, my english is bad&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;Humm&amp;hellip;My personal English, i&amp;rsquo;m a assistant
teacher, is not so good, but i can communicate with others! If you can
communicate with other people is good enough! You will read and understand
the content and post your code on forums, if you are not comfortable to
write english, you can just post your code, somebody will reply to you, you
will understand the reply and it is good enough to your learning. If you
can talk is really better, because you can help on discussions, but the
english is not a big barrier to participate of Rubylearning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide13&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is the course pace? As i said, Satish does weekly content posts on
forums&amp;hellip;Not forums&amp;hellip;the study materials. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to follow this
weekly pace, if you decide to view all the course in the last week you can,
but we recommend you to follow weekly because you can talk with other
people that are studying the same lesson and you have more focus on your
studies making it easy to learn different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What topics the course cover? Well&amp;hellip;We cover all the Beginning with Ruby,
from Ruby installation through&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide16&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;basic classes like numbers, blocks, variable scopes, constants, methods,
manipulation of text files, Regular Expressions, but only the basis of
Regular Expressions, how to work with RE with Ruby, working with classes,
inheritance, exceptions&amp;hellip; We can&amp;rsquo;t cover tests (the Ruby test/Unit class)
on the core course just a bit of it, we want to create a course just to
cover test/unit itself, so it is not a core part of Ruby in this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide17&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other questions that are often made to me when I recommend Rubylearning
couse is: &amp;ldquo;I will receive a certificate?&amp;rdquo;. The important thing on the
Rubylearning course is how much you can learn with the course, the
certificate is not the course focus, but&amp;hellip;The answer is YES!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide18&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my certificate from 3rd Batch that i participated, really
beautiful, signed by Satish, you receive in PDF, is not received in paper,
but you can print and store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide19&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As i said, Rubylearning is not made of only the Core course, we have a
lot of other courses that we call the &amp;ldquo;Intermediate courses&amp;rdquo;, and is
appropriate to who that already have a notion of what is Ruby core, if you
know core, you can move on to these other courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide20&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The merb course, now merb team are joining Rails team, maybe this course
will be extinct, but this is one of our courses for now.
Git / GitHub is a course of one week. Git is not directly connected with
ruby, but all the Ruby community are using it, so we decided to prepare
a course about it.
Ruby with database, using MySql and sqlite, you learn on how to use
activerecord to manipulate a database from a script Ruby.
FXRuby as Marcelo said in another speech.
Sinatra for web development, maybe will get the Merb course place, because
Merb and Rails will be one.
Shoes, as Marcelo said too, for Desktop development, very interesting.
Ruby and Twitter, is a course that will be released now, i don&amp;rsquo;t know when
it will start, maybe april 14th or 16th, for who those already have a ruby
knowledge, will be very interesting. They will show how to play with
&amp;ldquo;Twitter API&amp;rdquo; and make some interesting things with it.
And Rails 3, Satish promised that when Rails 3 is comming out he will
create a course about it to everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide21&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is some screenshots of shoes course. The application of the screenshot
on the Right was made by Satoshi, that was the main teacher of Rubylearning
shoes course, and is is a clock that show all the assistant teachers and
mentors timezone on the world, all teacher have a photo placed on with their
timezone.
I asked Satoshi to send a message to all of you, and he sent to me a
message with a &amp;ldquo;Google translation&amp;rdquo; Phrase in portuguese saying &amp;ldquo;Oi todo
mundo&amp;rdquo; that probably is &amp;ldquo;hello everybody&amp;rdquo;, and he says that you don&amp;rsquo;t need
to care about your english because we can communicate with Ruby, and he
wants to see you on Rubylearning Forums. Here you can see other screenshot
of a little game that they do with shoes, each student have your own game,
you can see a &amp;ldquo;questions and answers&amp;rdquo; game on the next screenshot. Very
interesting and a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide22&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you have a message from Satish Talim, i asked to him to send one, and
he is saying thanks to all Brazilian friends, Locaweb and Fabio Akita,
that are sponsors of the course, the locaweb is a Sponsor of the core
course, and saying thanks to you that are helping to spreading ruby around
the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Slide23 - Questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My presentation idea is to be very quick, just to show to you a bit of
what is Rubylearning and how you can participate, what you will learn and
so on&amp;hellip;
Somebody have some question?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo:&lt;/strong&gt; This courses that you show, all of them are free? Or have some paid
courses too?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Willian:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, the core course is free. The other courses you need to pay to
get in, but the cost is very low, something like 5 dollars, 3 or 5 dollars,
just to maintain the website, Satish put a lot of his time on Rubylearning,
so he need a way to maintain all of this, and he is making it with this
paid courses and some sponsors, but is not high price, just 3 or 5 dollars
with paypal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other question? I trampled some content because I have little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marcelo:&lt;/strong&gt; Lets thank Willian, no more questions now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;slide23&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks! =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old comments by: Bruno Croci, Andres Pereira, CrociDB, Carlan Calazans, Elden Lickfelt | Not available anymore. :(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Deploying a simple Merb application on Locaweb</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2009/01/07/deploying-a-simple-merb-application-on-locaweb.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2009/01/07/deploying-a-simple-merb-application-on-locaweb.html</id>
    <published>2009-01-06T22:00:00-02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I writing this post to help my friends of
&lt;a href="http://rubylearning.org/class/" title="Rubylearning.org"&gt;Rubylearning&lt;/a&gt; with
a little &lt;a href="http://merbivore.com/" title="Merb Official Home Page"&gt;Merb&lt;/a&gt;
application deployment on &lt;a href="http://www.locaweb.com.br" title="Locaweb"&gt;Locaweb&lt;/a&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;m just translating some informations that you can find
&lt;a href="http://prodblog.locaweb.com.br/2008/11/11/suporte-a-merb-10-na-hospedagem-compartilhada-linux/" title="Merb on Linux Share Host (in portuguese )"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in portuguese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets get started! :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First open the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://painel.locaweb.com.br/painel_controle/gerenciador_dominios.asp" title="Gerenciador de domínios"&gt;Domain Manager&lt;/a&gt;
(gerenciador de domínios) on Locaweb Panel (painel da Locaweb) and
configure the pointer of your main site to other directory on
public_html of your account (this directory don&amp;rsquo;t need to exist).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow this steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &amp;ldquo;alterar&amp;rdquo; (change)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the &amp;ldquo;Diretório Web&amp;rdquo; (web directory) to the new diretory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And click on button &amp;ldquo;Salvar&amp;rdquo; (save)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transfer your application to this directory on your host. For this
example, lets say that your application is called &amp;ldquo;sample&lt;em&gt;merb&amp;rdquo;, so,
connect via SSH on your account and create the directory &amp;ldquo;rack&lt;/em&gt;app&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;mkdir -p rack_app/sample_merb
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And move your application to there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your application must to have a file called &amp;ldquo;config.ru&amp;rdquo; to be executed
by Phusion Passenger, so, you need to create this file on your
application folder (rack&lt;em&gt;app/sample&lt;/em&gt;merb on this case) with this
content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;require 'rubygems'
require 'merb-core'

Merb::Config.setup(:merb_root   =&amp;gt; “.”, :environment =&amp;gt;; ENV['RACK_ENV'])

Merb.environment = Merb::Config[:environment]
Merb.root = Merb::Config[:merb_root]
Merb::BootLoader.run
run Merb::Rack::Application.new
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you need to create a symbolic link on your public_html diretory,
as you have configured on your Domain Manager (gerenciador de domínios)
of Locaweb Panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;ln -s ~/rack_app/sample_merb/public ~/public_html/sample_merb
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using this simple configuration you will have your application
pointed by apache with Phusion Passenger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to you know, you can see the merb gems that are installed with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class="rouge-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-gutter gl"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="rouge-code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;gem list | grep merb
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this help you on how to make your simple application works on Locaweb. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Old comments by: website erstellen lassen, Vikki Guitreau | Not available anymore. :(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New year is coming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2008/12/31/new-year-is-coming.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2008/12/31/new-year-is-coming.html</id>
    <published>2008-12-30T22:00:00-02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Estou apenas postando para dizer que nesse novo ano eu pretendo postar
mais sobre programação! Essa é a primeira virada de ano desse blog,
então resolvi postar meus &amp;ldquo;planos&amp;rdquo; para o próximo ano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Como o blog é novo eu comecei a escrever faz pouco tempo e estou
pegando experiência aos poucos, e talvez agora nesse novo ano a
qualidade dos posts aumente! (ou não&amp;hellip;heheh).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Não sei bem qual rumo minha vida vai seguir nesse novo ano, o que eu
vou ter que aprender e estudar, talvez eu tenha que aprender coisas
que eu não tinha planejado e isso pode tomar uma boa parte do meu
tempo, mas eu pretendo postar todos os meus estudos aqui, portanto
terei algum material interessante aqui.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esse ano estarei em alguns eventos por aqui (como todo ano), e eu
pretendo postar sobre eles aqui no blog! Um evento que já está com
minha presença confirmada é o
&lt;a href="http://campusparty.com.br/index.php/oevento.html" title="Campus Party"&gt;Campus Party Brasil&lt;/a&gt;,
que parece que vai ser bem lega, além da conexão monstruosa que terei
lá vou encontrar umas pessoas bem legais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eu estarei fazendo o curso de
&lt;a href="http://www.ime.usp.br/~verao/index.php?secao=difusao&amp;amp;amp;anoID=1&amp;amp;amp;" title="Curso de verão do IME/USP"&gt;verão da USP&lt;/a&gt;
(tópicos de programação) no mês de janeiro no período noturno,
portanto se alguem for fazer tambem me avise que nos encontraremos por
lá! ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bem&amp;hellip;É isso! Um feliz ano novo a todos os leitores do Blog e amigos e
nos veremos em 2009!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First post in English here</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://pothix.com/2008/12/16/first-post-in-english-here.html"/>
    <id>http://pothix.com/2008/12/16/first-post-in-english-here.html</id>
    <published>2008-12-15T22:00:00-02:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-04T19:25:48-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Willian Molinari (a.k.a PotHix)</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi international friends! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just posting to inform that I want to post some content in English
too! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make a RSS Feed only for my English posts, so you
don&amp;rsquo;t need to view my portuguese posts on your feed reader. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everyone knows, my English is not so good, but I think you can
understand me well! Any English errors (I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will have a lot of
them) please tell me and I&amp;rsquo;ll correct it asap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to have you following this blog! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
