<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on PotHix</title>
    <link>http://pothix.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on PotHix</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 | Follow on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mgjohansen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mgjohansen/hucore.git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hucore theme&lt;/a&gt; &amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; ♥</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pothix.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Year in Review (with metrics!)</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/2017-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/2017-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Brace yourselves, this post will be HUGE
TL;DR: It was a great year and I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to see the metrics and notice everything I accomplished.
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I posted my yearly review publicly but as I&amp;rsquo;m doing monthly posts of my stats, it makes sense to do an annual review as well.
I do yearly reviews since around 2005 but I never post them publicly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Dec, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-dec-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-dec-2017/</guid>
      <description>Came back from a travel last month and just packed my stuff to travel again this month. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it affected my performance.
Books I was traveling this month, so as usual, I&amp;rsquo;m not reading/listening to audiobooks because I prefer to focus on the place I&amp;rsquo;m visiting. For this reason, I did not finish any book this month.
With that said, it is the first time I have 4 books on my reading list at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Nov, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-nov-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-nov-2017/</guid>
      <description>Came back from a travel last month and just packed my stuff to travel again this month. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if it affected my performance.
Books 
Read three books this month. My first book of H.P. Lovecraft, called At the mountains of madness was one of them. It was an interesting experience to read it. I also read about minimalism just to realize that I&amp;rsquo;m a minimalism since forever. If you like minimalism I also recommend to listen to their podcast and read their website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Oct, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-oct-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-oct-2017/</guid>
      <description>This month was very unusual because I was traveling through Portugal and Spain for work and tourism, so it will probably affect my stats a lot. With that said, let&amp;rsquo;s see how it is. 😄
Books I read some pages from Elixir in Action, but unfortunately did not finish any book this month. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t read that much when traveling, so it&amp;rsquo;s sad but expected. 😞
Articles As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m using that same export file from Pocket and the same script to calculate the amount of articles I read:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for sep, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-sep-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-sep-2017/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s already the end of October and I could not manage to post my stats from September but I have a good reason for that (which you will read about in the next month 😉).
Books 
What Doesn’t Kill Us: How Freezing Water, Extreme Altitude and Environmental Conditioning Will Renew Our Lost Evolutionary Strength is a book that describes what the human body can do if trained for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Aug, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-aug-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-aug-2017/</guid>
      <description>September is here, time to review my stats for August, 2017.
Books 
This is my personal record of books read in one single month. 7 freaking books. 😱
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with two small books I read. Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Audiobooks for Dogs and Cesar Millan&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Bringing Home a Shelter Dog. These two books were free on Audible for Dogs, so I decided to give them a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jul, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jul-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jul-2017/</guid>
      <description>Okay, here we go for the first full month working in my new job. :)
Books 
This month I read Let My People Go Surfing: The Education of a Reluctant Businessman, which was recommended by the other Doisters. It&amp;rsquo;s a great book by the guy who built the company Patagonia, a bootstrapped company, from scratch. Their way of thinking looks a lot like the way we think at Doist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for Jun, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jun-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jun-2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m ready to review my stats for June and share them with you! Are you? Hope so! :D
Books 
Last month I read Deep Work again because I was preparing to work for a new company. The new company is Doist, but this is a topic for a another post. It proved to be a great asset, as they also recommend reading it. From their reading list I also took The score takes care of itself and Start with Why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for May, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again for my stats for the last month. :)
Books 
I will start a in a new company this month, so I decided to re-read Deep Work (I really recommend this one). This book is just great for everyone who wants to focus and do the hard work. It has everything to do with my new work schedule. The book about Elon Musk was a good reading as well, this guy has some great ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for April, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-apr-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-apr-2017/</guid>
      <description>This was not a good month. I spent most of the time sick, recovering from what may be a Labyrinthitis. I still have to confirm that, but I&amp;rsquo;m in slow motion for a while.
But anyways, let&amp;rsquo;s go to the collected data.
Books Books for this month:

&amp;ldquo;Einstein no Brasil&amp;rdquo; (Einstein in Brazil) is a physical book I borrowed from a friend and The Art of The Lord of the Rings I have in my shelf (as a good LotR fan).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for March, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-mar-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-mar-2017/</guid>
      <description>Back to work this month. :)
After one month vacation, I got back to my routine and got some good results this month.
Books Added three more books to the list:

I have to note here that Mastery is one of the best books I ever read. Both Mindfulness in plain English and The Urban Monk are about meditation and how to live a minimalist life.
Articles I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to find a way to track the articles I read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for February, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-feb-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-feb-2017/</guid>
      <description>February was an atypical month because I was on vacation. :)
Much of my stats will reflect my travel around Europe. But no coding was done during this trip.
Books Continuing my goal to read 30 books this year, I read two books this month:

I had plans to visit Amsterdam and Oxford during my travel. Because of that I decided to read the story of Kullervo, which mention a lot about J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats for January, 2017</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jan-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/stats-jan-2017/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of a series that will show all the data I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting during the month. One of my goals this year is to track everything possible. These posts will help me to analyze all the data and may extract something for me.
This is not a new idea, I&amp;rsquo;m inspired by posts like this from Matthew of truevalhalla.com.
Books My goal is to read 30 books this year, so I must have an average of 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford for Tolkien fans</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/oxford-for-tolkien-fans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/oxford-for-tolkien-fans/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: When traveling to Europe, I decided to take 2 or 3 days to visit Oxford. I will describe how was the experience of a J.R.R. Tolkien fan there.
I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of J.R.R Tolkien. Have read most of his books, the ones released when he was still alive and other edited by Christopher Tolkien.
After attending FOSDEM I decided to travel around some countries in Europe and UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendendo minhas coisas</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/vendendo-minhas-coisas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/vendendo-minhas-coisas/</guid>
      <description>Esse ano aconteceram algumas coisas zuadas para mim e resolvi capitalizar o dinheiro das coisas que eu tenho e começar denovo no ano que vem.
Procurei preços justos para tudo que estou vendendo (os links das minhas pesquisas estão nas descrições dos produtos), mas caso alguém ache que alguma das coisas está com um preço não-justo e estiver interessado é só entrar em contato que negociamos.
Estou aproveitando para testar a plataforma do loja integrada, mas os pagamentos eu prefiro que sejam por depósito mesmo, e se possível marcamos a entrega pessoalmente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizando os Feeds do Blog</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/organizando-os-feeds-do-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/organizando-os-feeds-do-blog/</guid>
      <description>Como muitos sabem, eu sou meio doido por organização (heheh) e eu mesmo não gosto de ficar lendo coisas que não me interessam de outros blogs, ou seja, no blog de alguém que gosta bastante de Vim eu ter que ficar lendo sobre paraquedismo :P
Agora eu gostaria de além de escrever sobre coisas técnicas, escrever também sobre os meus outros hobbies, como Motos, Shows e etc. Alguns deles eu até já escrevia um pouco antes, mas nem tanto, e isso já me incomodava um pouco, por que eu sei bem que várias pessoas que seguem o feed não gostam das mesmas coisas que eu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluxo de leitura e o Android</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/fluxo-de-leitura-e-o-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/fluxo-de-leitura-e-o-android/</guid>
      <description>Quem me conhece sabe como eu sou meio doido quanto a ler coisas aleatórias (Google reader e artigos interessantes que eu acho perdidos por aí), e como eu tenho um tempo um pouco limitado, devido ao trabalho e a faculdade eu sempre tenho alguns esquemas diferentes para ler. :P
Fluxo de leitura Depois que eu comprei um Android o meu fluxo de leitura se modificou um pouco. E está da seguinte maneira:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saldo final das férias de julho</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/saldo-final-das-ferias-de-julho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/saldo-final-das-ferias-de-julho/</guid>
      <description>Eu sempre digo que a faculdade me atrasa bastante, por que eu não consigo estudar/fazer um monte de coisas que eu tenho vontade para me dedicar as coisas que a faculdade me obriga a fazer. Se a faculdade é bom ou ruim não é discussão para esse post, mas resolvi postar a quantidade de coisas que eu consegui fazer nessas férias aproveitando que eu não precisava me preocupar com a faculdade, assim deixando o tempo da noite e a cabeça menos preocupada:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projeto de fevereiro</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/projeto-de-fevereiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/projeto-de-fevereiro/</guid>
      <description>No mês de fevereiro eu estive envolvido com um projeto bem interessante na empresa que estou trabalhando, que foi feito em Python / Django e deveria gerar páginas estáticas ( exigência do projeto ).
Tivemos um prazo muito curto para tudo que deveria ser feito, o que gerou uma grande quantidade de trabalho fora do horário e dos dias comuns. Entre o começo e o fim do projeto, tínhamos o carnaval, portanto tivemos que deixar nossos espíritos carnavalescos guardados e partir para o trabalho árduo no feriado até horas indeterminadas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dia difícil</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/dia-dificil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/dia-dificil/</guid>
      <description>Hoje o dia foi $#&amp;amp;&amp;amp;!

Atualmente moro em Diadema (que não é uma cidade ruim como muitos ouvem falar), e tenho o azer de morar próximo a um córrego, que a prefeitura promete canalizar há mais de 10 anos, e agora parece que finalmente o projeto começou a andar, mas enquanto o projeto não é concluído de vez a coisa ficou pior que o normal&amp;hellip;
No momento ruim eu tirei algumas fotos (o que sempre faço nesses casos) para mostrar a situação da coisa&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year is coming</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/new-year-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/new-year-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>Estou apenas postando para dizer que nesse novo ano eu pretendo postar mais sobre programação! Essa é a primeira virada de ano desse blog, então resolvi postar meus &amp;ldquo;planos&amp;rdquo; para o próximo ano.
Como o blog é novo eu comecei a escrever faz pouco tempo e estou pegando experiência aos poucos, e talvez agora nesse novo ano a qualidade dos posts aumente! (ou não&amp;hellip;heheh).
Não sei bem qual rumo minha vida vai seguir nesse novo ano, o que eu vou ter que aprender e estudar, talvez eu tenha que aprender coisas que eu não tinha planejado e isso pode tomar uma boa parte do meu tempo, mas eu pretendo postar todos os meus estudos aqui, portanto terei algum material interessante aqui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurso Quarto mais Nerd</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/concurso-quarto-mais-nerd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/concurso-quarto-mais-nerd/</guid>
      <description>Bem&amp;hellip;Estava eu aproveitando as férias (tanto da faculdade como as férias coletivas do trabalho) para colocar as coisas em ordem, começando pelo meu quarto que é o lugar da casa que eu passo mais tempo e eu gosto de manter bem organizado, portanto já tratei de aproveitar meu tempo livre para deixar ele do jeito que eu queria.
Comprei uma pequena estante para colocar mais livros e outras coisas legais, encaixotei várias coisas que eu quase nunca vou usar, e joguei 2 sacolas de papéis e outras coisas inúteis fora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post in English here</title>
      <link>http://pothix.com/post/first-post-in-english-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pothix.com/post/first-post-in-english-here/</guid>
      <description>Hi international friends! :)
I&amp;rsquo;m just posting to inform that I want to post some content in English too! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make a RSS Feed only for my English posts, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to view my portuguese posts on your feed reader. :)
As everyone knows, my English is not so good, but I think you can understand me well! Any English errors (I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will have a lot of them) please tell me and I&amp;rsquo;ll correct it asap.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>